<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lifestyle &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/category/lifestyle/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 22:01:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Lifestyle &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Top 5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Inemesit Etim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 08:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tech guys are all about the value their car gives them, not the money; that is not their problem. They want to park at the gym on a hot Saturday morning and be the center of attraction, not the guy whose car blows thick clouds every time. If you are that tech guy looking for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/">Top 5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span>Tech guys are all about the value their car gives them, not the money; that is not their problem. They want to park at the gym on a hot Saturday morning and be the center of attraction, not the guy whose car blows thick clouds every time.</span></p>
<p><span>If you are that tech guy looking for a car in Nigeria, there are car brands you should avoid, including the Toyota Sienna. Trust me, I have nothing against this car brand, but even you will agree that it doesn&#8217;t go with your style, and the list goes on and on.</span></p>
<p><span>Some cars will cause you more trouble than they&#8217;re worth, and you don&#8217;t want to worry about car repairs when there&#8217;s a code to crack. If you&#8217;re that tech guy who just hit the <em>milli</em> and wants a nice car, you&#8217;re in the right place.</span></p>
<p><span> At the end of this article, I will give you a heads-up on what to look out for in a car as a tech bro. I&#8217;m considering everything from aesthetics to speed, <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lifestyle/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">reliability and safety</a>.</span></p>
<h2>5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Guy</h2>
<div id="attachment_17778" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17778" class="wp-image-17778 size-large" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1024x736.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro" width="940" height="676" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1024x736.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-300x216.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-768x552.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-480x345.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro.jpg 1057w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17778" class="wp-caption-text">Toyota Sienna</p></div>
<h3>1. Avoid The Toyota Sienna</h3>
<p><span>The Toyota Sienna is one of the best minivans on the market. It is roomy, comfortable, and stylish, with a powertrain that provides 245 horsepower. It has an EPA fuel rating of 36 mpg in the city and 36 mpg on the highway. </span></p>
<p><span>On the interior, you&#8217;ll see a center console that runs from the dashboard to the center armrest. The Toyota Sienna&#8217;s newest infotainment system is a 9.0-inch touchscreen display that sits upright over the climate controls on the dashboard. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CarPlay" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple CarPlay</a>, Android Auto, and Amazon Alexa connection are standard, and the van&#8217;s interior has seven USB outlets. </span></p>
<p><span>As for safety, the Toyota Sienna comes with blind-spot monitoring and its Safety Sense 2.0 bundle of driver-assistance features. It earned five stars from the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, <a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/vehicle/2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NHTSA</a>, for safety and a predicted reliability score of 74 out of 100. </span></p>
<p><span>Why, then, should you avoid it? We can all agree that Siennas are meant for large families because which tech guy needs an 8-seater car? And the aesthetics are basic, not cool. Remember, you&#8217;ll see and drive your car every day. It better looks good.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17779" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17779" class="size-large wp-image-17779" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-1024x752.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 1" width="940" height="690" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-1024x752.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-300x220.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-768x564.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-480x353.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1.jpg 1055w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17779" class="wp-caption-text">Kia Soul</p></div>
<h3>2. Stay Away From The Kia Soul</h3>
<p><span>The Kia Soul is a small, boxy, subcompact car offered in various trims and powertrain configurations. Beautiful car but too problematic; the Kia Soul is prone to oil leaks. Such repairs are expensive, but the most annoying part is that it is frequent. </span></p>
<p><span>Kia Soul owners also say the car has suspension issues. The front wheel bearings and suspension springs are prone to failure. Furthermore, steering pins and tie rod system components might break, resulting in ongoing suspension troubles and costly repairs.</span></p>
<p><span>That&#8217;s not the only problem Kia Souls have; there are reports that the Kia Soul could lose power unexpectedly while driving. Most of them are caused by catalytic converter damage induced by high exhaust temperatures. Imagine you&#8217;re cruising on Third Mainland bridge, and your car ceases, not cool. </span></p>
<p><span>The power problem causes engine components to fail and, in extreme cases, can result in a fire beneath the hood. Yes, the Soul is prone to catching fire. It is a serious issue, and Kia recalled nearly 380,000 vehicles due to fire risks in 2021. But you&#8217;re in Nigeria, so even if there were a recall, you wouldn&#8217;t benefit from it.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17780" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17780" class="size-large wp-image-17780" title="2012 Acura TL" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-1024x755.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 2" width="940" height="693" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-1024x755.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-300x221.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-768x567.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-480x354.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2.jpg 1052w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17780" class="wp-caption-text">2012 Acura TL</p></div>
<h3>3. Leave The 2012 Acura TL Alone</h3>
<p><span>The 2012 Acura TL is one of the best-equipped sedans in its class, offering a strong V6 engine, excellent handling and braking ability, and a comfortable ride. Standard equipment on the 2012 Acura TL includes leather upholstery, heated front seats, a power sunroof, automatic climate control, and Bluetooth. </span></p>
<p><span>2012 Acura is not bad on fuel efficiency either. It has an EPA rating of 20/29 mpg city/highway. So when fuel prices go up at year-end, you can trust your car not to empty your bank account. </span></p>
<p><span>Some reviewers say the brake is powerful, while others say it feels numb. You need a sound brake system for the Nigerian road where most drivers aren&#8217;t very sane but let&#8217;s not forget safety. </span></p>
<p><span>No one plans to ram their car onto another one, but if it happened, you&#8217;d trust your car to save you, right? The 2012 Acura TL is not that car. It has an NHTSA rating of two over five for the frontal crash test and an overall NHTSA safety rating of three over five stars. Dear tech guy, you work so hard to make millions; there&#8217;s no way you want your career to end because your car couldn&#8217;t protect you.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17781" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17781" class="size-large wp-image-17781" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 3" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-1024x665.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 3" width="940" height="610" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-1024x665.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-300x195.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-768x498.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-480x312.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3.jpg 1228w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17781" class="wp-caption-text">Tesla</p></div>
<h3>4. Don&#8217;t Buy A Tesla</h3>
<p><span>I know you didn&#8217;t see this coming, but that Tesla car you admire is not suitable for you. Sure, you love Elon Musk&#8217;s technology, and I agree, the guy is a tech genius, but you&#8217;re a tech guy in Nigeria, not Canada. The <a href="https://www.tesla.com/models" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Model S</a> has a 396-mile range, 1,020 horsepower, and an overall top speed of 200 miles per hour, a true classic. Plus, the Model S has cutting-edge technology and a lovely interior. </span></p>
<p><span>Nigerians love luxury cars; no matter how expensive a car is, at least two people in Nigeria will buy it. I&#8217;ve seen a Tesla before in Nigeria, and more may be on their way, but someone else should buy them, not you.</span></p>
<p><span>Charging will always be a problem. An electric vehicle needs to be charged in a proper electric charging station. Furthermore, the S model has suspension, body components, and electronics issues.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17782" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17782" class="size-large wp-image-17782" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 4" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-1024x672.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 4" width="940" height="617" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-1024x672.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-300x197.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-768x504.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-480x315.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4.jpg 1182w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17782" class="wp-caption-text">Subaru Outback</p></div>
<h3>5. Don&#8217;t Buy A Subaru Outback</h3>
<p><span>Yes, the Subaru Outback is a great wagon. It combines car-like handling and small-SUV performance with a slew of standard and optional technology, comfort, and driver-assistance systems. In the 2022 Outback, Subaru offers two versions of their Starlink infotainment system. </span></p>
<p><span>The entry-level models have a pair of 7-inch touch screens and a few buttons and knobs for quick navigation. However, the top speed of any Outback model is roughly 130 mph, which is too sluggish for you. You can get it for your significant other.</span></p>
<h2>What Should Tech Guys Look For In A Car?</h2>
<p><span>Many people buy cars only because it&#8217;s cheap that&#8217;s why we outlined <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lifestyle/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the best 10 luxury cars under 7 million naira for naija techies</a>, but if you want the best of what is available, you must stop thinking about the cost. But tech guys supposedly have money because there’s money in the IT industry. With all that being said, here are some things that tech guys look out for when buying a car.</span></p>
<h3>Class</h3>
<p><span>Men love to drive in style, and tech guys raise the bar; they go for class. In case you haven’t noticed, perception is everything. When you’ve achieved a certain status in life, you no longer want the basic things. Your car choice will go beyond what helps you move faster to what gives you that stylish excellence. Tech guys and excellence go so well together.</span></p>
<h3>A Sound Navigation System</h3>
<p><span>GPS navigation systems help drivers navigate through unfamiliar locations. They can also show traffic conditions and even allow you to search for nearby restaurants, hotels, and other businesses. Some navigation systems also have voice control, so you can ask for directions without taking your hands off the wheel.</span></p>
<h3>Connectivity</h3>
<p><span>Connected cars allow you to check your vehicle&#8217;s status remotely to adjust climate control settings while you&#8217;re away from home or work using your smartphone. Many newer cars have built-in Wi-Fi hotspots so passengers can connect their smartphones and other devices while on the road.</span></p>
<p><span>Bluetooth allows you to connect your smartphone or another device to your car&#8217;s stereo system to listen to music or make calls while driving. For tech guys, music is therapeutic; what use is a car without music?</span></p>
<h3>Reliability</h3>
<p><span>If you&#8217;re buying a new car, don&#8217;t just focus on what looks good and drives well — take the time to find out how well it will hold up over time. Cars go through a lot during their lifetimes. They should handle everyday wear and tear without breaking down or needing expensive repairs too often. </span></p>
<p><span>A vehicle that gets excellent reliability ratings from <a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Consumer Reports</a> or JD Power will probably be more dependable than one that doesn&#8217;t perform as well in these tests.</span></p>
<h3>Safety</h3>
<p><span>Safety is important in cars. When you&#8217;re driving, you need to be able to trust your car will keep you and your passengers safe. If you&#8217;re not comfortable with the safety of your vehicle, it&#8217;s time to get it checked out by a mechanic before driving it again. </span></p>
<p><span>The NHTSA has made progress in getting car companies to manufacture vehicles with better safety features. They test car safety on side crashes, front crash, and over-lapping. If your car gets five out of five stars on safety, it&#8217;s a good buy.</span></p>
<h3>Fuel Economy</h3>
<p><span>If you&#8217;re buying an SUV because you want more space for your family but don&#8217;t want gas bills that rival those of a yacht owner, check out fuel economy before committing yourself to anything too big or powerful. Smaller cars tend to get better gas mileage than larger ones. </span></p>
<h2>Wrap Up</h2>
<p><span>Cars aren’t just machines for transportation; in a way, your car reflects your personality. Just like clothes can make or break your style, cars can make or break your image, which is why aesthetics are important. But beyond that, consider how safe, reliable, and fuel-efficient the car is before you buy.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/">Top 5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Techies in Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Inemesit Etim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 07:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17738</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When buying a luxury car, you usually have two options: buy pre-owned or buy new. If you&#8217;re drooling for a new ride but don&#8217;t want to pay too much, you have to decide how much you’re willing to spend on a car and stick to the budget. One of the best luxury cars in Nigeria [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/">Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Techies in Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="normal" style="margin-bottom: 10.0pt">When buying a luxury car, you usually have two options: buy pre-owned or buy new. If you&#8217;re drooling for a new ride but don&#8217;t want to pay too much, you have to decide how much you’re willing to spend on a car and stick to the budget.</p>
<p class="normal" style="margin-bottom: 10.0pt">One of the best luxury cars in Nigeria is the Kia Rio 1.4L which you can get for less than 7 million Naira. This car offers the standard and comfortable driving experience you crave at a lower price. The Toyota Venza is cool too, but for this budget, you can only get a used one.</p>
<p class="normal" style="margin-bottom: 10.0pt">Luxury cars have always been expensive, but there are some great bargains out there. You just need to look in the right place. This article will save you stress by highlighting the best luxury cars under 7 million naira for young tech guys in Nigeria.</p>
<h2>10 Best Affordable Luxury Cars Under 7 Million</h2>
<div id="attachment_17786" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17786" class="size-large wp-image-17786" title="luxury cars" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1024x764.jpg" alt="luxury cars" width="940" height="701" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1024x764.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-300x224.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-768x573.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-480x358.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars.jpg 1155w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17786" class="wp-caption-text">Lexus ES 330</p></div>
<h3>1. Lexus ES 330</h3>
<p>Here’s another luxury innovation by the Toyota Motor Corporation. Lexus ES 330 doesn’t just tick the list of luxurious cars but prides itself in allowing its users to enjoy a thrilling ride with safety and confidence without spending so much.</p>
<p>Lexus ES 330 isn’t your regular car; the aesthetics are superb. It features an incredible 3.3L 6-cylinder engine that produces 225 Horsepower and 240lb-ft of torque that transforms into a five-speed automatic transmission.</p>
<p>If you’re not tall and you wish to get the Lexus ES 330, don’t worry. This model has an adjustable driver’s seat that can increase or reduce the height. This seat also has lumbar support that enhances comfort. This model also prides itself on the large cabin, which can contain up to eight people.</p>
<p>Whether locally or foreign fairly used, you can get Lexus ES 330 in Nigeria for as low as 2.5 million Naira. However, the price sometimes depends on the condition of the car. Depending on this, the price can increase to 3.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.5 to 3.5 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 2.7 to 5.1 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17787" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17787" class="size-large wp-image-17787" title="luxury cars 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-1024x762.jpg" alt="luxury cars 1" width="940" height="699" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-1024x762.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-300x223.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-768x571.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-480x357.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1.jpg 1167w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17787" class="wp-caption-text">2005 Nissan Xterra</p></div>
<h3>2. 2005 Nissan Xterra</h3>
<p>From a sleek design to superfast acceleration, the 2005 Nissan Xterra is a luxurious ride that allows you to enjoy a more practical and thrilling ride without spending so much. It prides itself in being an excellent ride that satisfies your cravings with standard features and quality infotainment at an affordable rate.</p>
<p>With a 6.0L engine, 265 Horsepower, 284lb-ft of torque, and a five-speed automatic transmission, you’ll surely enjoy a thrilling ride experience. Talk of the lightweight, beautiful exterior and interior features, and the standard infotainment systems, the 2005 Nissan Xterra has it all polished to impress you.</p>
<p>It offers fine features like traction control, electronic brakeforce distribution, tire pressure monitoring, and an adjustable driver’s seat. Its tire pressure monitoring device ensures safety and value for your money.</p>
<p>The price for this vehicle ranges from 2.5 million Naira to 5.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.5 million Naira to 4.5 million Naira.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Foreign used: Between 3.5 million Naira to 5.5 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17789" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17789" class="size-large wp-image-17789" title="luxury cars 2" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-1024x533.jpg" alt="luxury cars 2" width="940" height="489" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-1024x533.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-300x156.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-768x400.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-480x250.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-1320x687.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2.jpg 1469w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17789" class="wp-caption-text">Honda Cr-V</p></div>
<h3>3. Honda Cr-V</h3>
<p>Here’s another mid-range model of Honda that gives you that classy and sleek SUV feeling without taking so much from your pocket. Honda CR-V is one of the luxurious car brands with standard features that offer a high-quality and comfortable riding experience.</p>
<p>According to Honda, CR-V represents a Comfortable Roundabout Vehicle. Asides from being fuel efficient, the Honda CR-V has quality inbuilt technology and high-quality infotainment systems to keep you entertained on the road.</p>
<p>It also offers a sleek and stylish performance with its 39.2 cubic feet that expands up to 75.8, 148 Horsepower, and 350lb-ft of torque with manual transmission gear.</p>
<p>Honda CR-V ranks the second best on SUVs compact list. Currently, it is 15.5 million Naira in the Nigerian automobile market. However, you can get a fairly used one for 5.5 million Naira. And not to worry! The fairly used ones are just as good as the brand-new ones.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 3.5 million Naira to 5.5 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 4.1 million Naira to 5.7 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17790" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17790" class="size-large wp-image-17790" title="luxury cars 3" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-1024x649.jpg" alt="luxury cars 3" width="940" height="596" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-1024x649.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-300x190.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-768x487.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-480x304.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3.jpg 1269w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17790" class="wp-caption-text">Honda Accord</p></div>
<h3>4. Honda Accord</h3>
<p>A million thanks to Honda for crafting this supermodel. This luxury car offers peerless driving dynamics, quality infotainment systems, and fuel efficiency. It’s standard at its peak; isn’t that what we all want?</p>
<p>The Honda Accord is equipped with five comfortable seats, a 2.0L engine, and a ten-speed automatic transmission, so your car glides through Nigerian roads smoothly.</p>
<p>The Honda Accord also has dual-zone automatic climate control, soft leather seats, Apple CarPlay, and Android Auto smartphone integration, which combine to wow your ride experience. For safety, you get low-speed anti-collision braking.</p>
<p>If you’re looking forward to buying a honda accord in Nigeria, you need to budget 13 million Naira. However, you can get fairly used between 2.5 to 6.5 million Naira. The fairly-used ones are as good as the brand-new ones.</p>
<p>You may notice glitches with the ignition switch coupled with excess oil usage, but, the Honda Accord tops ranks 85 out of 100 in reliability.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.2 to 5.2 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 5.7 to 6.2 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17791" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17791" class="size-large wp-image-17791" title="luxury cars" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-1024x652.jpg" alt="luxury cars 4" width="940" height="599" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-1024x652.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-300x191.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-768x489.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-480x306.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4.jpg 1256w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17791" class="wp-caption-text">Kia Rio</p></div>
<h3>5. Kia Rio 1.4L Top</h3>
<p>Kia Rio is a luxurious mid-sedan that comes in four colors; Aurora black, Bright Silver, Clear White, and Signal Rendall. It rates high in performance, style, and speed.</p>
<p>With a cabin that offers a five-seat interior comfort, standard infotainment, an inbuilt air conditioner, brake assistance, adjustable seats, and central locking to keep you protected inside, this car sets the standard for comfort and safety.</p>
<p>The Kia Rio 1.4L offers a sleek and stylish performance with its 107 Horsepower, 136 lb-ft, and a four-speed automatic transmission. Users also praise it for its top speed in delivering at 183 km/hour.</p>
<p>What’s more? Kia Rio 1.4L Top rates are high in the list of reliable cars, which offers good value for your money. The starting price is 5.4 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.5 to 4.8 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 3.8 to 6.3 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17792" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17792" class="size-large wp-image-17792" title="luxury cars 5" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-1024x735.jpg" alt="luxury cars 5" width="940" height="675" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-1024x735.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-300x215.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-768x551.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-480x344.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5.jpg 1169w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17792" class="wp-caption-text">Toyota Venza</p></div>
<h3>6. Toyota Venza</h3>
<p>You can say that Toyota Venza is a ride that’s excellent in all forms, and you wouldn’t be wrong. Riding in this luxurious and sleek ride will give you value for your money while allowing you to enjoy comfort at its peak with quality infotainment systems and a  ride experience.</p>
<p>The seats of this beautiful model are soft. Covered with smooth feathers, they offer comfort at any trim level and are easy to clean. It also has a digital rearview mirror that doesn’t just display a reflection when in use but also displays the camera from the rearview mirror.</p>
<p>With its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hybrid_vehicle" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hybrid engine</a>, it has a continuous-variable automatic speed. It doubles up on-road performance providing 219 HorsePower and 1,029 torque power.</p>
<p>The driver’s seat in Toyota Venza is adjustable and offers lumbar support. What’s more? The tires can survive on any terrain, rough or smooth. For reliability rating, it rates 78 out of 100.</p>
<p>The price of Toyota Venza in Nigeria ranges from 2.3 million Naira to 6.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.3 to 5.5 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 5.5 to 6.5 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17793" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17793" class="size-large wp-image-17793" title="luxury cars 6" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-1024x649.jpg" alt="luxury cars 6" width="940" height="596" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-1024x649.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-300x190.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-768x487.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-480x304.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6.jpg 1315w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17793" class="wp-caption-text">Nissan X-trail</p></div>
<h3>7. Nissan X-trail</h3>
<p>The Nissan X-trail is a spectacular mid-sized SUV. With its top-quality infotainment systems and smooth ride, you cannot help but rate this model high.</p>
<p>Talking about the interior, this model can easily pass for a family car as it has a large interior; you’d appreciate this extra space if you have a bunch of tech kids growing under your roof. The seating system is flexible, and you can adjust it to suit your style.</p>
<p>The price range for Nissan x-trail in Nigeria ranges from 10 million to 12 million Naira. However, you can get a fairly used Nissan X-trail between 2.5 million Naira to 6.8 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.5 to 5.8 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 2.6 to 6.8 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17794" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17794" class="size-large wp-image-17794" title="luxury cars" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-1024x547.jpg" alt="luxury cars" width="940" height="502" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-1024x547.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-300x160.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-768x410.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-480x256.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-1320x705.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX.jpg 1477w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17794" class="wp-caption-text">Acura MDX</p></div>
<h3>8. Acura MDX</h3>
<p>For luxurious cars, it’s the faster, the better, and Acura MDX ticks all the boxes. It is super fast, reliable, and safe.  With its lightweight, standard interior and sleek exterior, this car is everything a tech guy would love. Everything about Acura MDX speaks style and class.</p>
<p>It is a good choice if you want to go low on fuel consumption and the premium safety features allow you to feel a sense of comfort while in motion. The most interesting part is that you can get this model for as low as 2.8 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.3 million Naira to 4.5 million Naira<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 2.8 million Naira to 6.8 million Naira</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17795" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17795" class="size-large wp-image-17795" title="luxury cars 7" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-1024x577.jpg" alt="luxury cars 7" width="940" height="530" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-1024x577.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-768x433.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-480x270.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-1320x744.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7.jpg 1480w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17795" class="wp-caption-text">Hyundai Grand</p></div>
<h3>9. Hyundai Grand</h3>
<p>Despite its ups and downs, Hyundai Grand still strives to be among the best luxurious and affordable vehicles for tech guys.</p>
<p>This model has 256 liters of cargo space. With five seating capacities, a 7.0-inch touchscreen infotainment system with android and apple CarPlay,  automatic ORVMs that lock and unlock, 81.86 horsepower, 13.75 torque power, and manual transmission speed, this model prides itself in standard features that add up to its premium qualities.</p>
<p>As for reliability rating, Hyundai ranks 75 out of 100, which is a pretty impressive score. The price depends on the model and condition, but the starting price in Nigeria is 8.5 million Naira. However, you can get a fairly used one for 3.8 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.8 to 4.5 million Naira.<br />
Foreign used: Between 5.5 to 6.8 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17796" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17796" class="size-large wp-image-17796" title="luxury cars 8" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-1024x511.jpg" alt="luxury cars 8" width="940" height="469" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-1024x511.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-300x150.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-768x383.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-480x239.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-1320x659.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8.jpg 1327w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17796" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-Benz C-300</p></div>
<h3>10. Mercedes-Benz C-300 (2010)</h3>
<p>Talk about strength, durability, and class; the Mercedes-Benz C-300 has got it all. It doesn’t matter if you buy a fairly used one; with good servicing, this vehicle can last you as long as seven years before needing an <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lifestyle/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">expensive repair</a>.</p>
<p>The Mercedes-Benz C-300 is fitted with a 3.0L hybrid engine that generates 228 Horsepower and a seven-speed shiftable transmission for a comfy and pleasurable performance. It can go as fast as 130 miles per hour.</p>
<p>It also prides itself on premium features like a four-wheel independent suspension, an adjustable driver seat with lumber support, five seating capacity, and descent control. If you’re not tall, don’t worry, this model has height-adjustable seats for your comfort. Asides from the roomy interior, it has traction control which is perfect for Nigerian terrains.</p>
<p>In Nigeria, the start price for Mercedes-Benz C-300 is quite expensive, but you can get a fairly used one for as low as 6.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><b>Nigeria used: Between 6.5 million to 6.9 million Naira.</b></p>
<p><b>Foreign used: Between 6.9 million to 7 million Naira.</b></p>
<h2>Wrap Up</h2>
<p>There you have it! The 10 Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Tech Guys in Nigeria. These car models are super fast, sleek, and classy. So, if you want to buy a luxury but affordable car, you have those ten car models to choose from.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/">Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Techies in Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Low-Maintenance Mercedes Benz Cars for Tech Guys</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emmanuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 05:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s face it; Mercedes-Benz is never cheap to own. Still, there are options for young tech guys who want the 3-point star ride without spending a fortune on periodical maintenance. What determines the maintenance cost of a Benz car goes beyond mechanical or electrical fixes from time to time. You also want to put a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">Best Low-Maintenance Mercedes Benz Cars for Tech Guys</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s face it; Mercedes-Benz is never cheap to own. Still, there are options for young tech guys who want the 3-point star ride without spending a fortune on periodical maintenance.</p>
<p>What determines the maintenance cost of a Benz car goes beyond mechanical or electrical fixes from time to time. You also want to put a great deal of thought into the Model age, service history, and location where you will use the Benz.</p>
<p>As a young techie looking for the best low-maintenance Benz cars to buy, you want to steer clear from models like the Metris and Sprinter since their average yearly maintenance is around $2,500. That&#8217;s pretty high.</p>
<p>With my exposure to Mercedes Benz models over the years and a little more digging into a pool of data from giant auto review sites, I&#8217;ve put together a list of the seven classy Benz cars that are great for tech guys and economy-friendly to maintain in the long run.</p>
<p>This will help you in your buying decision to save your budget and your vehicle from major repair costs.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get right into it.</p>
<h2>List of Best Benz Cars with Low-Maintenance Costs for Techies</h2>
<p>As you probably know, the sticker price is one of many things you will pay to own a Benz car.</p>
<p>During my extensive discussion with various technicians who see cars getting fixed day in and day out, I discovered that many Benz owners spend more money maintaining Brakes, Oil changes, Spark plugs, Transmission service, Coolant service, Tires, and Smog checks.</p>
<p>Given the status of the German vehicle, these services could set you back thousands of dollars annually compared to regular Chinese cars.</p>
<p>Fortunately, you stand a chance to spend less on maintenance while enjoying Merc if you drive any of these models:</p>
<h3>1. 2010 Mercedes-Benz C350</h3>
<div id="attachment_17682" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17682" class="wp-image-17682 size-full" title="2010 Mercedes Benz C350" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350.jpg" alt="2010 Mercedes Benz C350" width="1200" height="675" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350.jpg 1200w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-768x432.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-480x270.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17682" class="wp-caption-text">2010 Mercedes Benz C350. 📸: <em>CNET Roadshow</em></p></div>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/reliability/mercedes-benz/c350" rel="noopener">Repairpal&#8217;s reliability rating</a> of the 2010 Mercedes-Benz C350 estimates average annual maintenance costs to be $720, influenced by the age, mileage, and location the vehicle is often used.</p>
<p>This Mercedes-Benz C-Class is one of the best options you can think of if you need a Benz car with the luxurious look of a classy techie but low maintenance cost. However, the model seems to be a better fit for handling than for comfort (many C-class do, too)</p>
<p>I won&#8217;t recommend the C350 if you ply curvy roads most of the time, but the vehicle has a fair chance of hitting 200,000 miles or more if you play your cards well in the area of maintenance routines.</p>
<p>The average buying price of the 3.5-liter V6 equipped vehicle starts from around $39,500 and is known for its high-quality parts like other Benz models.</p>
<p>The 2010 Mercedes-Benz C350 releases 268 Horsepower and 258 lb-ft of torque. It will stay in good condition for a very long time if you follow the affordable-to-achieve German manufacturer&#8217;s maintenance guidelines.</p>
<h3>2. 2012 Mercedes-Benz E350</h3>
<div id="attachment_17689" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17689" class="wp-image-17689 size-full" title="2012 Mercedes Benz E350 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1.jpg" alt="2012 Mercedes Benz E350 " width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17689" class="wp-caption-text">2012 Mercedes Benz E350. 📸: <em>The Car Connection</em></p></div>
<p>Generally, you can expect a Mercedes-Benz E-Class to gulp about $11,224 for maintenance and repairs during its first ten years of service. While this beats the industry average for luxury cars, the 2012 Mercedes-Benz E350 offers more.</p>
<p>According to the leading provider of auto repair and maintenance information, Repairpal, <a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/cars/mercedes-benz/e350/2012#:~:text=The%20annual%20maintenance%20cost%20of,%2C%20mileage%2C%20location%20and%20shop." rel="noopener">the average upkeep cost of the Mercedes-Benz E350</a> annually is around $788. It is a reasonable maintenance cost for a full-size luxury sedan.</p>
<p>With an impressive 3.5-liter V6 engine that produces 302 horsepower, E350 is an excellent catch for the average &#8216;tech bro&#8217; willing to buy a German car on a budget. However, you have to keep in mind that the vehicle requires factory-recommended maintenance if it&#8217;s going to be on the road for as long as possible.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, on average, you can expect the Mercedes-Benz E350 to last, hitting 15,000 miles in 15 years.</p>
<h3>3. 2014 Mercedes-Benz CLA250</h3>
<div id="attachment_17688" style="width: 2570px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17688" class="wp-image-17688 size-full" title="2014 Mercedes Benz CLA250 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1.jpg" alt="2014 Mercedes Benz CLA250 1" width="2560" height="1492" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1.jpg 2560w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-300x175.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-1024x597.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-768x448.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-1536x895.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-480x280.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-1320x769.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17688" class="wp-caption-text">2014 Mercedes Benz CLA250 📸: <a href="https://branditechture.agency/the-forgotten-website-where-you-can-get-over-70-million-free-images/"><em>Wikimedia Commons</em></a></p></div>
<p>Next on our list of low-maintenance Benz to buy is the CLA250.</p>
<p>This model is doing a better job challenging its contender, Audi A3 and Lexus CT 200h, in the compact luxury car market landscape. It is also cracking the top among a few others as it is the best affordable luxury car for upkeep.</p>
<p>It would cost you, at most, $736 to keep the 2014 CLA250 healthy throughout the year, as various reviews on RepairPal point out that the CLA250 is a top reliable car. <a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/mercedes-benz/cla250#:~:text=The%20annual%20maintenance%20cost%20of,%2C%20mileage%2C%20location%20and%20shop." rel="noopener">The four-star RepairPal reliability rating</a> the model has garnered from users is enough conviction.</p>
<h3>4. 2014 Mercedes-Benz GLK350</h3>
<div id="attachment_17687" style="width: 1290px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17687" class="size-full wp-image-17687" title="2014 Mercedes Benz GLK350" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1.jpg" alt="2014 Mercedes Benz GLK350 " width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1.jpg 1280w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-480x270.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17687" class="wp-caption-text">2014 Mercedes Benz GLK350. 📸: <em>Sherwood Park Toyota</em> via YouTube</p></div>
<p>It is only possible to list low-maintenance luxury cars by mentioning this 2014 Mercedes-Benz GLK350.</p>
<p>Well, you can say that is subjective. Still, it is more convincing when you consider the fantastic reliability of the GLK as it secures the 7th position on the list of the top <a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/reliability/compact-suv" rel="noopener">luxury compact SUVs on RepairPal.</a></p>
<p>The crossover combines the comfort of a sedan and the spacious cabin of an SUV to offer a decent driving experience. Fixing the 2014 GLK350 annually will cost you between $776 and $948, depending on vehicle usage.</p>
<p>Another exciting part of having this Benz model is that you are likely to experience fewer problems with the vehicle compared to when driving other luxury compact SUVs.</p>
<h3>5. 2020 Mercedes-Benz SL450</h3>
<div id="attachment_17686" style="width: 1610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17686" class="size-full wp-image-17686" title="5. 2020 Mercedes Benz SL450 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1.jpg" alt="2020 Mercedes Benz SL450" width="1600" height="1067" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1.jpg 1600w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-480x320.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-1320x880.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17686" class="wp-caption-text">2020 Mercedes Benz SL450 📸: <em>Edmunds</em></p></div>
<p>The 2020 Mercedes-Benz SL450 is a luxurious two-seat retractable-hardtop vehicle that offers more comfort and reliability than most Benz lineups.</p>
<p>The vehicle is not a hundred percent pass on many grounds, but it is the closest thing to perfection regarding low upkeep cost. With as low as $908, you will keep the SL450 running perfectly throughout the year in excellent condition.</p>
<p>This is a reasonable maintenance cost compared to the thousands of dollars that most other Benz cars gulp annually.</p>
<p>The 2020 Mercedes-Benz SL450 has a potent 3.0-liter twin-turbo V6 that dismisses 362 horsepower. It is one of the Benz makes that has a surprisingly low maintenance cost.</p>
<h3>6. 2020 Mercedes C200</h3>
<div id="attachment_17685" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17685" class="size-full wp-image-17685" title="2020 Mercedes C200" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1.jpg" alt="2020 Mercedes C200 " width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17685" class="wp-caption-text">2020 Mercedes C200 📸: The Car Connection</p></div>
<p>The 2020 Mercedes C200 is my all-time favorite as long as the discussion of Mercedes Benz is in play. The vehicle is not only considered a decently reliable Mercedes model but also costs low when it comes to maintenance.</p>
<p>The C200 price isn&#8217;t encouraging for techies on a budget, especially when you place it alongside your typical Japanese car brand. But incredible things come at a price, Yeah?</p>
<p>And, what&#8217;s the point when the Benz model is cheaper to maintain than most of its German Luxury alternatives?</p>
<p>Upkeep routines like a simple oil change for the 2020 Mercedes C200 will cost around $150, including parts and labor, while full service for a C-class costs around $500.</p>
<h3>7. 2017 Mercedes-Benz GLS550</h3>
<div id="attachment_17684" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17684" class="size-full wp-image-17684" title="2017 Mercedes Benz GLS550 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1.jpg" alt="2017 Mercedes Benz GLS550 1" width="1920" height="1367" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1.jpg 1920w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-300x214.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-1024x729.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-768x547.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-1536x1094.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-480x342.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-1320x940.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17684" class="wp-caption-text">2017 Mercedes Benz GLS550 📸: <em>Select Luxury Cars</em></p></div>
<p>The 2017 Mercedes-Benz GLS550 has a young family demographic appeal as a full-size SUV. So, you will find many young guys buying this Benz model, which makes it a good fit for an average tech guy with a wife and children.</p>
<p>But still, another significant reason to consider the GLS550 is the low maintenance fee which puts it ahead of its alternatives like the Cadillac Escalade and even Audi&#8217;s Q7.</p>
<p>It will only cost you around $908 annually to maintain the 2017 Mercedes-Benz GLS550, allowing you to enjoy this luxury car&#8217;s benefits for a long time. It is equipped with a blistering turbo V8 and requires fewer visits to the repair shop for fixes if appropriately used.</p>
<h2>Reasons Why These Benz Cars are Cheaper to Maintain than Others</h2>
<p>These Benz models have been reviewed to be the best in low maintenance areas based on data from consumer surveys, up-close repair shop interviews, car history reports from RepairPal, and my exposure to a series of Mercedes lineups.</p>
<p>If you pay close attention, you will notice that all these Benz cars have something in common that makes them cost less for upkeep in the long run.</p>
<p>Similar features include simple technology, accessible replacement parts, and ample room under the hood of these cars that reduce the labor cost during repairs.</p>
<p>These Benz models appear to have a less complicated technology that makes it easier and quicker to observe repairs or maintenance routines.</p>
<p>Little wonder why many of the low-maintenance Benz cars are of older models since newer lineups are more complicated. In addition, these cars have common, standardized replacement parts, making their repairs cheaper.</p>
<p>Maintenance routines like regular oil changes, proper damage repair, and other essential tasks are required to guarantee the reliability of any Benz car. But observing this routine can be expensive for the typical Benz, but the few models reviewed earlier are going against the odds.</p>
<h2>Bottom Line</h2>
<p>Mercedes-Benz has a glorified reputation for making desirable premium cars. While most of their vehicles are expensive, we have walked through some of the best low-maintenance Mercedes-Benz models every Tech guy can buy.</p>
<p>If it were up to me, I recommend you choose the 2020 Mercedes C200. Not only is the C200 a decently reliable Mercedes model, but it is also a reasonably affordable car to maintain compared to many other Mercedes models on a broader comparative analysis.</p>
<p>The C200, indeed, is not a cheap buy like the regular American vehicle but is still cheaper to maintain than most of its German Luxury alternatives &#8211; a simple oil change will cost around $150 on average, with full service starting from as low as $500.</p>
<p>This is on the low side of spending compared to what Benz S-class owners spend for an oil change ($300 on average) and full service (around $1,400).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">Best Low-Maintenance Mercedes Benz Cars for Tech Guys</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
