<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Market Survey &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/category/market-survey/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 09:13:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Market Survey &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Oraimo&#8217;s Deceptive Marketing Strategy: Is It Sustainable in the Long Run?</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 09:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Market Survey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Oraimo (stylized as oraimo) is a well-known smart accessories manufacturing firm that designs, develops, and distributes smartwatches, power banks, audio, and other accessories for consumers in over 13 countries. However, their marketing strategy has come into question recently, and people are starting to ask whether it is sustainable in the long run. If you visit [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/">Oraimo&#8217;s Deceptive Marketing Strategy: Is It Sustainable in the Long Run?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/brand-logos/download/oraimo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Oraimo</a> (stylized as <em><strong>oraimo</strong></em>) is a well-known smart accessories manufacturing firm that designs, develops, and distributes smartwatches, power banks, audio, and other accessories for consumers in over 13 countries. However, their marketing strategy has come into question recently, and people are starting to ask whether it is sustainable in the long run.</p>
<p>If you visit the official Oraimo Nigeria store <strong>(https://ng.oraimo.com/)</strong>, you will notice that they only approve positive comments and outrightly decline negative, but valid ones.</p>
<div id="attachment_17966" style="width: 1541px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17966" class="size-full wp-image-17966" title="Oraimo's NG Store" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store.png" alt="Oraimo's NG Store" width="1531" height="889" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store.png 1531w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-300x174.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-1024x595.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-768x446.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-480x279.png 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-1320x766.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1531px) 100vw, 1531px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17966" class="wp-caption-text">Oraimo&#8217;s NG Store</p></div>
<p>In fact, it&#8217;s suspicious that no product has less than a 5/5 star rating on their store.  This raises questions about whether they generate artificial positive comments and star ratings to influence purchasing decisions.</p>
<p>Moreover, Oraimo is known to hire local influencers such as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=miss+techy+oraimo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>MissTechy</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=Fosudo+oraimo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Fisayo Fosudo</strong></a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=Kegan+Tech+oraimo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Kegan Tech</strong></a>, to put their products in good light while &#8220;deliberately&#8221; downplaying the cons. &#8220;Commercial&#8221; tech influencers have contributed to this rot as they do not live long enough with these products to genuinely form an opinion.</p>
<p>As a consumer, whenever you openly criticize Oraimo on their Facebook posts, they delete the comment. Even if you repost the comment a hundred times, they will delete all of them in a matter of minutes. There seem to be people specifically employed to carry out this task, but how about they use that same energy to reach out to the pained customer via DM?</p>
<p>While this might seem to them like a clever PR strategy in the short run, the question is, how long can a brand keep up with this strategy? Deceptive marketing practices can only work for so long before people start to catch on. Once people realize that they can&#8217;t trust a brand, it&#8217;s challenging to regain their trust.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the internet is too vast to control every negative comment about your brand. Social media has made it easier for people to share their experiences with a brand, and if a brand tries to control information, it could end up doing them more harm than good.</p>
<p>In conclusion, Oraimo&#8217;s deceptive marketing strategy raises questions about the sustainability of such practices in the long run. While it might seem like a good idea to control information about your brand, it&#8217;s not sustainable in the long run.</p>
<p>What do you think? Let&#8217;s discuss this in the comments section below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/">Oraimo&#8217;s Deceptive Marketing Strategy: Is It Sustainable in the Long Run?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s How Much The MTN MiFi Costs, and 6 Places to Puchase It.</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/how-much-is-the-mtn-mifi/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/how-much-is-the-mtn-mifi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Market Survey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ever since posting a review of the MTN 4G Mi-Fi MF927U , I have gotten quite a number of questions on where to purchase the MTN Mi-Fi device and how much it is currently sold for. For this reason, I have created this page, which I would keep updating from time to time as the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-much-is-the-mtn-mifi/">Here&#8217;s How Much The MTN MiFi Costs, and 6 Places to Puchase It.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ever since posting a <a href="https://branditechture.agency/reviews/mtn-mifi-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">review of the MTN 4G Mi-Fi MF927U</a> , I have gotten quite a number of questions on where to purchase the MTN Mi-Fi device and how much it is currently sold for. For this reason, I have created this page, which I would keep updating from time to time as the price of the device changes.</p>
<p>If you contact MTN to enquire about the device, they would usually advise you to go to the closest MTN Yello! Experience Center to purchase it, but one thing they won&#8217;t remember to tell you is that the device is subject to availability. In other words, it is possible for you to get to their Yello! Experience Center(s) and still be told that the <a href="https://branditechture.agency/reviews/mtn-mifi-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MTN Mi-Fi</a> is <strong><em>out of stock. </em></strong></p>
<p>Before I finally got my own <a href="https://branditechture.agency/reviews/mtn-mifi-review/"><strong>MTN MF927U Broadband Mi-Fi</strong></a>, I had been to two Yello! Experience Centers but I was told in both places that the device is out of stock. Anyways, I finally got it at Victoria Island, at their Adeola Odeku branch, but there is no guarantee that you would always find it there.</p>
<p>To save you of all of these stress, here are different ways with which you could purchase the MTN Mi-Fi as well the price range you would typically get it for.</p>
<p>If you do a quick search on Facebook using the keyword &#8220;<em>MTN MiFi</em>&#8221; you&#8217;ll see quite a lot of people selling the device for over ₦20,000 NGN which is saddening. However, to avoid overpaying or getting cheated on, aways bear in mind that <strong>the current recommended retail price for the MTN Mi-Fi is ₦8000 NGN. </strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17066" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17066" class="size-full wp-image-17066" title="MTN 4G MiFi Devices on Display" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/MTN-4G-MiFi-Devices-on-Display.jpg" alt="MTN 4G MiFi Devices on Display" width="720" height="720" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/MTN-4G-MiFi-Devices-on-Display.jpg 720w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/MTN-4G-MiFi-Devices-on-Display-300x300.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/MTN-4G-MiFi-Devices-on-Display-150x150.jpg 150w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/MTN-4G-MiFi-Devices-on-Display-480x480.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17066" class="wp-caption-text">MTN 4G Broadband Mi-Fi (MF927U) Devices on Display</p></div>
<h2>Cheapest Ways to Get the MTN Mi-Fi</h2>
<h3>1. Our Telegram Group: ₦7,500</h3>
<p>By <a href="https://t.me/+BIDkw4btJ5U4NjM0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">joining our Telegram Group,</a> I will show you where you can get the MTN Broadband Mi-Fi Device for just ₦7,500. Yes, ₦7,500! So hurry up and join now. This offer is valid while stocks lasts. Delivery is possible anywhere in Nigeria.</p>

<h2>Other Ways to Get the MTN Mi-Fi and Their Price Range</h2>
<h3>2. On Konga: (Between <strong>₦</strong>12,000 to <strong>₦</strong>30,000)</h3>
<p>If for some reason you are unable to join our Telegram group, you can shop the MTN Mi-Fi on <a href="https://www.konga.com/search?search=MTN%204G%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Konga.com</a> by clicking <a href="https://www.konga.com/search?search=MTN%204G%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">here.</a> Since you would be buying from unofficial sources, expect to pay between <strong>₦12,000 to as high as</strong> <strong>₦30,000.</strong></p>
<h3>3. On Jumia: (Between ₦13,000 to ₦40,000)</h3>
<p>Checking out the MTN Mi-Fi device on <a href="https://www.jumia.com.ng/catalog/?q=MTN+Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Jumia.com.ng</a>, you would notice that there are quite a number of vendors there too, waiting to exploit uninformed buyers by selling the device for as high as ₦40,000, which is <strong>5 times</strong> the amount they bough it.</p>
<p>Well, if you still want to check it out, click <a href="https://www.jumia.com.ng/catalog/?q=MTN+Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><strong>HERE.</strong></a></p>
<h3>4. On Facebook Marketplace (Between ₦10,000 to ₦14,000)</h3>
<p>You can get the device on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/marketplace/106265246077413/search/?query=MTN%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Facebook Marketplace,</a> both in new and used conditions. But it may shock you to find out that many people are selling the used MTN Mi-Fi device at a higher price than we sell the brand new device from our source. 😆😆😆</p>
<pre><strong>Please do note, however, that by buying a used MTN Mi-Fi device, you automatically lose out on the 30GB Welcome bonus that comes with it.  </strong></pre>
<p>Facebook Marketplace is an online shopping arm of the Facebook social media network. It&#8217;s an online peer-to-peer commerce platform where Facebook users can buy and sell items from each other. Unlike <a href="https://www.jumia.com.ng/catalog/?q=MTN+Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><strong>Jumia</strong></a>, <strong><a href="https://www.konga.com/search?search=MTN%204G%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Konga</a> </strong>and our <a href="https://t.me/+BIDkw4btJ5U4NjM0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Telegram source</a>, you need to be very careful when buying from people on Facebook Marketplace in order to avoid getting duped. This is Facebook Marketplace does not offer any level of protection to you as a buyer, so if you decide to use Facebook Marketplace to purchase the device, make sure you do your research and trust the vendor.</p>
<h3>5. Facebook Post Search (Between ₦8,500 and ₦30,000)</h3>
<p>Yes!  If other methods of getting the device proves futile, you can try <a href="https://www.facebook.com/search/posts?q=MTN%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">searching Facebook</a> just as you would search for the name of a friend. Just type &#8220;<em>MTN MiFi</em>&#8221; in your Facebook search bar, click <strong>Posts </strong>to filter by Facebook Posts, then scroll through the rendered search results for sellers&#8217; contact phone numbers and prices or just click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/search/posts?q=MTN%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><strong>HERE</strong></a>.</p>
<h3>6. On Jiji.ng (Between ₦10,200 and ₦35,000)</h3>
<p>Jiji.ng is a Nigerian online peer-to-peer marketplace that provides buyers and sellers with an avenue to meet and exchange goods and services. You can <a href="https://jiji.ng/search?query=MTN%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">get the MTN Mi-Fi device on Jiji.ng</a> by clicking <a href="https://jiji.ng/search?query=MTN%20Mifi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">HERE.</a> When shopping for items on Jiji, make sure you only buy from reputable vendors with lots of good reviews. Otherwise, it is best to collect their addresses and visit them at their physical store.</p>
<p>As it is with most methods, please be careful when carrying out transactions with strangers online.</p>
<hr />
<ol>
<li>Which of these options sound like the cheapest, safest and most convenient to you?</li>
<li>If you already have the device. How did you get yours?</li>
<li>Did you get your free 30GB after activating the SIM?</li>
</ol>
<p>Share with us using the comments below 👇🏽.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-much-is-the-mtn-mifi/">Here&#8217;s How Much The MTN MiFi Costs, and 6 Places to Puchase It.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/how-much-is-the-mtn-mifi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
