<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 09:54:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Shutterstock Acquires Envato in Groundbreaking Creative Powerhouse Merger</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/shutterstock-acquires-envato-in-groundbreaking-creative-powerhouse-merger/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/shutterstock-acquires-envato-in-groundbreaking-creative-powerhouse-merger/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 09:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=19820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a groundbreaking move that is set to reshape the creative content landscape, Shutterstock, a leading global creative platform, has entered into a definitive agreement to acquire Envato, a leader in digital creative assets and templates. This strategic acquisition promises to be a game-changer, combining the strengths of two industry titans and unleashing a wealth [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/shutterstock-acquires-envato-in-groundbreaking-creative-powerhouse-merger/">Shutterstock Acquires Envato in Groundbreaking Creative Powerhouse Merger</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">In a groundbreaking move that is set to reshape the creative content landscape, Shutterstock, a leading global creative platform, has entered into a definitive agreement to acquire Envato, a leader in digital creative assets and templates. This strategic acquisition promises to be a game-changer, combining the strengths of two industry titans and unleashing a wealth of opportunities for creatives, brands, and businesses worldwide.</p>
<h2 class="font-bold">The Envato Advantage: Unlimited Creative Content at Your Fingertips</h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">At the heart of this acquisition lies Envato&#8217;s flagship product, Elements – a creative subscription service that offers unlimited downloads of a diverse array of assets, templates, and more. Elements has gained a reputation as an intelligent creative companion, empowering creatives to bring their visions to life and leave a lasting mark on a global scale.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">With Envato Elements under its wing, Shutterstock will complement its existing offering with a leading unlimited multi-asset subscription, catering to the ever-growing demand for a comprehensive creative solution. This acquisition expands Shutterstock&#8217;s reach into faster-growing audiences, including freelancers, hobbyists, small businesses, and agencies.</p>
<h2 class="font-bold">A Fusion of Creative Forces</h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">The combination of Shutterstock and Envato promises to be a powerful force in the creative content industry. By joining forces, the companies will:</p>
<ul class="list-disc pl-8 space-y-2 -mt-1">
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Bolster Shutterstock&#8217;s subscriber base to a staggering 1.15 million, more than doubling its current reach.</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Enhance Shutterstock&#8217;s content library with an impressive 10 million images, 6 million videos, 1 million audio clips, 0.5 million templates, and 0.2 million graphics and fonts.</li>
<li class="whitespace-normal break-words">Diversify Shutterstock&#8217;s offerings into new content types, including code and web themes, product mock-ups, fonts, and templates for slides, PowerPoint, Keynote, WordPress, video, social media designs, gaming, podcasts, and print-on-demand.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="font-bold">A Shared Vision for Creativity and Innovation</h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">&#8220;We&#8217;re thrilled about this transaction and looking forward to welcoming the Envato team to Shutterstock,&#8221; said Shutterstock CEO Paul Hennessy. &#8220;Envato is perfectly positioned to serve a growing customer need for an unlimited multi-asset subscription to a library of creative content, with an emphasis on videos, audio, graphics, fonts and templates. By extending our reach to faster growing audiences and into additional content types, this acquisition will help Shutterstock fulfill its mission of connecting customers to the content they need, wherever they are so they can create, build and share their next big idea.&#8221;</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Envato CEO Hichame Assi shared his excitement, stating, &#8220;Since its humble beginnings in a Sydney garage, Envato has generated more than $1.3 billion in earnings for its author community and scaled to 650k subscribers. I feel an immense sense of pride in the team for achieving this global scale as an independent business. As we enter this next chapter, we remain laser focused on empowering the creative community to thrive and excited to achieve this shared goal with Shutterstock.&#8221;</p>
<h2 class="font-bold">A Promising Future for Creatives and Customers</h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">With this acquisition, Shutterstock and Envato are poised to redefine the creative content industry, delivering unparalleled value and empowering creatives and businesses alike to bring their boldest ideas to life. As the companies embark on this exciting journey, their shared commitment to innovation, creativity, and customer satisfaction will undoubtedly shape a future where limitless possibilities await.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">Stay tuned for further updates as this groundbreaking merger unfolds, promising to unlock new horizons in the world of creative content.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/shutterstock-acquires-envato-in-groundbreaking-creative-powerhouse-merger/">Shutterstock Acquires Envato in Groundbreaking Creative Powerhouse Merger</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/shutterstock-acquires-envato-in-groundbreaking-creative-powerhouse-merger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Benefits of Hiring an Expert SEO Consultant for SaaS Businesses</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/10-benefits-of-hiring-an-expert-seo-consultant-for-saas-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/10-benefits-of-hiring-an-expert-seo-consultant-for-saas-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 11:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO TIps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=19817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The world of digital marketing is complex, and SaaS companies need a strong online presence to compete. Search engine optimization (SEO) is essential to drive traffic and expand your customer base. Handling SEO internally can be time-consuming and requires constant learning.  By outsourcing to an experienced SEO expert, you gain valuable time and tap into [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/10-benefits-of-hiring-an-expert-seo-consultant-for-saas-businesses/">10 Benefits of Hiring an Expert SEO Consultant for SaaS Businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world of digital marketing is complex, and SaaS companies need a strong online presence to compete. Search engine optimization (SEO) is essential to drive traffic and expand your customer base. Handling SEO internally can be time-consuming and requires constant learning.  By outsourcing to an experienced SEO expert, you gain valuable time and tap into specialized knowledge. At Profit By PPC, we offer customized <a href="https://profitbyppc.com/digital-marketing-consultant" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>digital marketing consulting</b></a> and PPC solutions for ambitious SaaS companies.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s discuss how partnering with an SEO specialist can propel your SaaS business forward.</p>
<h2><b>1. Deep Understanding of SaaS-Specific SEO</b></h2>
<p>The world of SaaS (software-as-a-service) comes with unique SEO challenges and opportunities. Search engines evaluate SaaS websites through a different lens compared to traditional business or e-commerce sites. An expert <b>SEO consultant for SAAS Company</b> has honed their skills within this specific domain. They possess the intricate knowledge to craft strategies tailored to your industry, ensuring your website&#8217;s content and structure align perfectly with how potential customers search for your type of solution.</p>
<h2><b>2. Expertise in Technical SEO</b></h2>
<p>Technical SEO forms the bedrock of a high-ranking website. Seemingly small errors like broken links, slow loading speeds, or indexing issues can significantly impede your visibility in search results. An SEO consultant conducts a comprehensive technical audit, pinpointing these potential roadblocks and fixing them. This attention to detail ensures that search engine crawlers can easily understand and index your website effectively, leading to improved rankings.</p>
<h2><b>3. Effective Keyword Research</b></h2>
<p>Identifying the right keywords is like finding the hidden treasure map to SEO success. An SEO consultant understands your target audience deeply. They&#8217;ll delve into their pain points, their needs, and, most importantly, the words and phrases they use to search for solutions like yours. This research forms the basis of your content strategy and marketing campaigns, ensuring you&#8217;re strategically targeting those high-value keywords.</p>
<h2><b>4. High-Quality Content Creation</b></h2>
<p>Content is truly king in the SEO world, but not just any content. An SEO expert understands the delicate balance between search intent and valuable, informative content. They can collaborate with your team to develop blog posts, product pages, landing pages, and thought-leadership articles that resonate with your audience. This high-quality, keyword-optimised content builds trust, establishes authority, and draws in the right visitors.</p>
<h2><b>5. Optimised On-Page SEO</b></h2>
<p>Beyond your website&#8217;s content, numerous on-page factors affect your search engine rankings. A skilled SEO consultant pays meticulous attention to elements such as:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Meta Titles and Descriptions</b>: These snippets of text displayed in search results need to be compelling and keyword-rich to entice clicks.</li>
<li><b>Header Tags</b>: Proper structure (H1, H2, etc.) helps search engines understand the hierarchy of your content.</li>
<li><b>Image Optimisation:</b> Alt-text and file sizes play a role in how images are indexed and contribute to page load speed.</li>
<li><b>Internal Linking:</b> A well-structured internal linking strategy distributes authority throughout your site, improving navigation for both visitors and search engines.</li>
</ul>
<h2><b>6. Link-Building Strategies</b></h2>
<p>Link building, also known as backlinking, involves acquiring high-quality links to your website from other reputable sources. Search engines view these links as endorsements of your content, boosting your authority and trustworthiness. An SEO consultant won&#8217;t rely on spammy tactics but will develop legitimate link-building campaigns aligned with your niche. The result is a stronger backlink profile and an upward trajectory in search rankings.</p>
<h2><b>7. Competitive Analysis</b></h2>
<p>Gaining an edge in a competitive market requires knowing your rivals&#8217; moves. An experienced SEO consultant dissects your competitors&#8217; online presence, uncovering their strengths, weaknesses, and areas where you can outsmart them. Armed with these insights, we&#8217;ll develop SEO tactics that put you ahead of the pack.</p>
<h2><b>8. Local SEO</b></h2>
<p>SaaS businesses often serve clients across the globe. However, if your customer base is concentrated in a particular location or region, local SEO is essential. An SEO consultant helps you rank prominently in &#8220;near me&#8221; searches, driving leads from your geographic area. Tactics include optimising your Google My Business listing and targeting locally relevant keywords.</p>
<h2><b>9. Data-Driven Insights</b></h2>
<p>SEO isn&#8217;t a set-it-and-forget-it activity. Success depends on continuous analysis and improvement. An expert consultant leverages analytics tools to track an array of metrics, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Search Rankings</b>: Monitoring Your Position for Essential Keywords</li>
<li><b>Website Traffic</b>: Understanding Traffic Sources and Visitor Demographics</li>
<li><b>Conversions</b>: tracking leads, trials, and subscriptions generated from organic search</li>
<li><b>Bounce Rate</b>: Identifying pages that need optimisation to retain visitors</li>
</ul>
<p>These data-driven insights illuminate what&#8217;s working and what needs adjustment, allowing us to refine your SEO strategy for maximum impact.</p>
<h2><b>10. Saves You Time and Money</b></h2>
<p>Building a robust internal SEO team is a costly endeavour.  Hiring a dedicated SEO expert, plus investing in necessary tools and subscriptions, quickly adds up. Partnering with a skilled SEO consultant for SaaS companies offers several financial benefits, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Specialised Expertise</b>: You gain immediate access to proven knowledge and strategies without the expense of hiring and training in-house.</li>
<li><b>Scalability</b>: <a href="https://profitbyppc.com/seo-services-for-saas-company" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>SEO services for SaaS Company</b></a> can scale alongside your business growth without the need to expand your payroll.</li>
<li><b>Focused Investment</b>: Your budget is directed towards results-driven strategies, avoiding inefficient spending on tactics that don&#8217;t deliver.</li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Let Us Drive Your SaaS Growth </b></h2>
<p>At Profit By PPC, we&#8217;re passionate about helping SaaS businesses excel in the digital landscape. Our team of digital marketing and PPC experts understands the intricacies of SaaS SEO. We tailor solutions aligned with your unique goals, taking a methodical, data-informed approach.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re ready to unlock the full potential of SEO and propel your SaaS business forward, schedule a consultation with us today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/10-benefits-of-hiring-an-expert-seo-consultant-for-saas-businesses/">10 Benefits of Hiring an Expert SEO Consultant for SaaS Businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/10-benefits-of-hiring-an-expert-seo-consultant-for-saas-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring Business Growth with CRM Software</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/exploring-business-growth-with-crm-software/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/exploring-business-growth-with-crm-software/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 01:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=19813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In modern business, customer management is vital for success. As businesses expand, handling more customers becomes tougher but essential. Onboarding new customers can strain services, hinder sales, and lower satisfaction. To tackle this challenge, businesses rely on CRM software to manage customers, boost sales, and improve service. What is CRM and Why do You Need [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/exploring-business-growth-with-crm-software/">Exploring Business Growth with CRM Software</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In modern business, customer management is vital for success. As businesses expand, handling more customers becomes tougher but essential. Onboarding new customers can strain services, hinder sales, and lower satisfaction. To tackle this challenge, businesses rely on CRM software to manage customers, boost sales, and improve service.</p>
<h2>What is CRM and Why do You Need It?</h2>
<p>Customer Relationship Management (CRM) encompasses the technology utilized to oversee all interactions and relationships with both current and potential customers within a company. The primary aim is to enhance business connections. A CRM system aids in maintaining customer engagement, streamlining operations, and ultimately boosting profitability.</p>
<p>Typically, when discussing CRM, reference is made to a CRM system or platform—an instrument facilitating contact management, sales supervision, productivity enhancement, and more.</p>
<p>CRM software directs attention towards nurturing relationships within your organization, whether with customers, service recipients, colleagues, or suppliers, across their entire lifecycle. This includes acquiring new customers, securing their patronage, and providing ongoing support and additional services throughout the association.</p>
<p>Through the utilization of a CRM solution, the sales and marketing team can monitor and follow a customer’s journey(check out <a href="https://www.sprinklr.com/cxm/customer-journey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>what is customer journey</b></a>) of engagement with the business. This meticulous oversight enables the refinement of each customer interaction, thereby enriching their overall experience.</p>
<h2>Functionality of CRM Software</h2>
<h3>Sales Forecasting</h3>
<p>CRM software uses historical data and predictive analytics for accurate sales forecasting. By analyzing trends, businesses make informed decisions about resource allocation and planning. Forecasting helps anticipate demand fluctuations, optimize production, and minimize risks.</p>
<h3>Incentive Compensation</h3>
<p>CRM solutions offer transparent tools for tracking and calculating incentive compensation for sales teams. Accurate recording of sales activities fosters accountability and motivates performance. Transparent structures encourage healthy competition and drive sales success.</p>
<h3>Opportunity Management</h3>
<p>CRM empowers sales teams with tools to manage opportunities throughout the sales cycle. Centralizing data enables prioritization, tracking, and nurturing of leads. Advanced features streamline processes, increase efficiency, and maximize conversion rates.</p>
<h3>Time Tracking</h3>
<p>CRM software includes time-tracking capabilities for sales activities. Capturing detailed data helps identify inefficiencies and improve resource allocation. Monitoring performance enables targeted coaching and enhances productivity.</p>
<h3>Real-Time Reporting</h3>
<p>CRM solutions offer customizable reporting tools for instant visibility into key metrics. Stakeholders can monitor progress, identify trends, and address issues proactively. Real-time insights enable agile decision-making, driving continuous improvement and business success.</p>
<h3>Customer Management</h3>
<p>At the heart of CRM lies a robust framework for managing customer information comprehensively. It enables businesses to create detailed profiles, capturing data like purchase history, preferences, and interactions. This holistic view empowers tailored interactions, personalized marketing, and informed decision-making. By consolidating data from various touchpoints, CRM enhances understanding, leading to better <a href="https://www.sprinklr.com/cxm/customer-retention/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>customer retention</b></a> and loyalty.</p>
<h2>Top 15 Features of CRM Software</h2>
<p>As businesses navigate the vast landscape of CRM solutions, several key features emerge as indispensable for driving efficiency and effectiveness:</p>
<ol>
<li><b> Contact Management:</b> Efficiently organize and access customer information, communication history, and preferences.</li>
<li><b> Workflow Automation:</b> Streamline repetitive tasks, reduce errors, and accelerate task completion.</li>
<li><b> Marketing Automation:</b> Reach the right audience with personalized messaging, boosting engagement and ROI.</li>
<li><b> Customization</b>: Tailor features to specific business needs, enhancing effectiveness and satisfaction.</li>
<li><b> Third-Party Integrations:</b> Seamlessly integrate external applications for enhanced productivity and customer interaction.</li>
<li><b> Customer Service:</b> Provide comprehensive support for timely query resolution and positive customer relationships.</li>
<li><b> Employee Tracking:</b> Monitor performance to optimize resources and foster accountability.</li>
<li><b> Task Management:</b> Efficiently assign and track tasks for improved productivity and project delivery.</li>
<li><b> Social Media Integration:</b> Engage customers and gather insights for brand promotion and lead generation.</li>
<li><b> Lead Management:</b> Effectively track and manage leads to drive revenue growth.</li>
<li><b> Real-Time Data Access:</b> Access up-to-date data for informed decision-making and seizing opportunities.</li>
<li><b> CRM Analytics:</b> Gain insights to optimize strategies and identify growth opportunities.</li>
<li><b> Reporting:</b> Generate customizable reports for performance monitoring and strategic decision-making.</li>
<li><b> Pipeline Management:</b> Visualize and manage sales pipelines for maximum efficiency.</li>
<li><b> Sales Forecasting:</b> Predict future sales trends to adjust strategies and meet targets.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>CRM software has transformed business management, enabling better customer relationships, streamlined operations, and increased profits. With its insights and automation, CRM enhances personalized interactions, targeted marketing, and informed decision-making, boosting satisfaction and loyalty. Features like automated marketing and sales forecasting optimize resources and sales potential. Future integration of AI will bring further innovation, automating tasks and providing personalized insights.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/exploring-business-growth-with-crm-software/">Exploring Business Growth with CRM Software</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/exploring-business-growth-with-crm-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Reset and Regain Access To Your MTN MiFi WiFi Password</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/how-to-reset-and-regain-access-to-your-mtn-mifi-wifi-password/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/how-to-reset-and-regain-access-to-your-mtn-mifi-wifi-password/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 16:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the most annoying mistakes MTN made with their latest MiFi device is putting the sticky paper label OUTSIDE the body of the MiFi device. Perhaps, this could be because this particular Mi-fi model has no removable battery cover, but they could have at least, laminated it. The sad news, however, is that many [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-reset-and-regain-access-to-your-mtn-mifi-wifi-password/">How to Reset and Regain Access To Your MTN MiFi WiFi Password</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most annoying mistakes MTN made with their latest MiFi device is putting the sticky paper label OUTSIDE the body of the MiFi device. Perhaps, this could be because this particular Mi-fi model has no removable battery cover, but they could have at least, laminated it. The sad news, however, is that many MTN Mi-Fi owners have lost the default WLAN Key written on the sticky label due to the rubbing off of the ink used to print the details.</p>
<p>But do not fret&#8230; My name is Yusuf Odukoya, and as a freelancer and digital guy myself, I understand that losing that little sticker with your WLAN key can be quite frustrating. I have got you covered with this simple and effective solution to regain access to your Wi-Fi connection by checking or setting a new WLAN Key.</p>
<p>In this step-by-step guide, I will walk you through the process of resetting or checking your MTN MiFi WLAN key (Also known as WiFi password) using just a USB cable and your computer. Whether you&#8217;ve got the latest MTN Mi-Fi model or an older one, this method just works for ALL MTN Mi-Fi models. So, let&#8217;s dive in and get your Wi-Fi back up and running!</p>
<p><strong>Materials You&#8217;ll Need:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Your MTN MiFi device</li>
<li>A USB cable</li>
<li>A computer or laptop with a web browser</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Step 1: Connect MiFi to Your Computer</strong> Start by powering on your MTN MiFi device. Then, take your trusty USB cable and connect your MiFi device to your computer. Ensure the connection is snug and secure.</p>
<p><strong>Step 2: Accessing the Web Interface</strong> Open up your favorite web browser on your computer—whether it&#8217;s Chrome, Firefox, Edge, or another. Now, in the address bar at the top, type in the following: <code>192.168.0.1</code> and hit Enter. This magical combination of numbers will lead you to your MiFi device&#8217;s settings.</p>
<p><strong>Step 3: Logging In</strong><br />
You&#8217;ll be greeted by the MTN MiFi web interface. Sometimes, it might ask you for a username and password. If you&#8217;ve never changed these before, no worries! The default credentials are often &#8220;admin&#8221; for both the username and password. Go ahead and enter those in.</p>
<div id="attachment_18010" style="width: 849px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18010" class="size-full wp-image-18010" title="Dashboard login page" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Dashboard-login-page.png" alt="Dashboard login page" width="839" height="589" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Dashboard-login-page.png 839w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Dashboard-login-page-300x211.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Dashboard-login-page-768x539.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Dashboard-login-page-480x337.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 839px) 100vw, 839px" /><p id="caption-attachment-18010" class="wp-caption-text">Dashboard login page</p></div>
<p><strong>Step 4: Finding WLAN Settings</strong><br />
Now comes the fun part—finding the section that&#8217;s all about your Wi-Fi settings because this depends on your MiFi or router model. You must look for labels like &#8220;WLAN Settings,&#8221; &#8220;WiFi Settings,&#8221; or something similar. Once you&#8217;ve located it, click on it.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s mine:</p>
<div id="attachment_18011" style="width: 1008px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18011" class="size-full wp-image-18011" title="WiFi Settings" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/WiFi-Settings.png" alt="WiFi Settings" width="998" height="486" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/WiFi-Settings.png 998w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/WiFi-Settings-300x146.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/WiFi-Settings-768x374.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/WiFi-Settings-480x234.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 998px) 100vw, 998px" /><p id="caption-attachment-18011" class="wp-caption-text">WiFi Settings</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Step 5: Generating a New WLAN Key</strong><br />
Inside the WLAN settings, you&#8217;ll find an option to generate a fresh WLAN key or password. This could be called &#8220;Security Key,&#8221; &#8220;Password,&#8221; or &#8220;WPA Key.&#8221; Click on that option and follow the instructions to generate a new key. If you&#8217;re feeling creative, some devices might even let you create your own.</p>
<div id="attachment_18012" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18012" class="size-full wp-image-18012" title="Update your WiFi password" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Update-your-WiFi-password.png" alt="Update your WiFi password" width="1024" height="609" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Update-your-WiFi-password.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Update-your-WiFi-password-300x178.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Update-your-WiFi-password-768x457.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Update-your-WiFi-password-480x285.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-18012" class="wp-caption-text">Updating your WiFi password</p></div>
<p><strong>Step 6:Saving Your Changes</strong><br />
After you&#8217;ve generated or updated your WLAN key, it&#8217;s time to save the day! Look around for a &#8220;Save&#8221; or &#8220;Apply&#8221; button on the web interface. Click it with confidence, knowing that your changes are about to be locked in.</p>
<p><strong>Step 7: Disconnect, Restart, and Reconnect</strong><br />
Safely disconnect your MTN MiFi device from your computer. Now, give your MiFi a moment of rest by turning it off and then back on. Wait patiently for it to fully reboot. Once it&#8217;s up and running, connect to your MiFi&#8217;s Wi-Fi network using the new WLAN key you&#8217;ve just set.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> And there you have it, a straightforward way to reset your MTN MiFi WLAN key and reclaim your Wi-Fi connection. Remember, this guide is your trusty companion whether you&#8217;re using the latest MiFi model or an older one. The next time you find yourself without that precious sticker, just grab your USB cable and computer (or laptop) and follow the above steps to restore your connection in no time.</p>
<p>Happy browsing!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-reset-and-regain-access-to-your-mtn-mifi-wifi-password/">How to Reset and Regain Access To Your MTN MiFi WiFi Password</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/how-to-reset-and-regain-access-to-your-mtn-mifi-wifi-password/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oraimo&#8217;s Deceptive Marketing Strategy: Is It Sustainable in the Long Run?</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 09:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Market Survey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Oraimo (stylized as oraimo) is a well-known smart accessories manufacturing firm that designs, develops, and distributes smartwatches, power banks, audio, and other accessories for consumers in over 13 countries. However, their marketing strategy has come into question recently, and people are starting to ask whether it is sustainable in the long run. If you visit [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/">Oraimo&#8217;s Deceptive Marketing Strategy: Is It Sustainable in the Long Run?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/brand-logos/download/oraimo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Oraimo</a> (stylized as <em><strong>oraimo</strong></em>) is a well-known smart accessories manufacturing firm that designs, develops, and distributes smartwatches, power banks, audio, and other accessories for consumers in over 13 countries. However, their marketing strategy has come into question recently, and people are starting to ask whether it is sustainable in the long run.</p>
<p>If you visit the official Oraimo Nigeria store <strong>(https://ng.oraimo.com/)</strong>, you will notice that they only approve positive comments and outrightly decline negative, but valid ones.</p>
<div id="attachment_17966" style="width: 1541px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17966" class="size-full wp-image-17966" title="Oraimo's NG Store" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store.png" alt="Oraimo's NG Store" width="1531" height="889" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store.png 1531w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-300x174.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-1024x595.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-768x446.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-480x279.png 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Oraimos-NG-Store-1320x766.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1531px) 100vw, 1531px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17966" class="wp-caption-text">Oraimo&#8217;s NG Store</p></div>
<p>In fact, it&#8217;s suspicious that no product has less than a 5/5 star rating on their store.  This raises questions about whether they generate artificial positive comments and star ratings to influence purchasing decisions.</p>
<p>Moreover, Oraimo is known to hire local influencers such as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=miss+techy+oraimo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>MissTechy</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=Fosudo+oraimo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Fisayo Fosudo</strong></a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=Kegan+Tech+oraimo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Kegan Tech</strong></a>, to put their products in good light while &#8220;deliberately&#8221; downplaying the cons. &#8220;Commercial&#8221; tech influencers have contributed to this rot as they do not live long enough with these products to genuinely form an opinion.</p>
<p>As a consumer, whenever you openly criticize Oraimo on their Facebook posts, they delete the comment. Even if you repost the comment a hundred times, they will delete all of them in a matter of minutes. There seem to be people specifically employed to carry out this task, but how about they use that same energy to reach out to the pained customer via DM?</p>
<p>While this might seem to them like a clever PR strategy in the short run, the question is, how long can a brand keep up with this strategy? Deceptive marketing practices can only work for so long before people start to catch on. Once people realize that they can&#8217;t trust a brand, it&#8217;s challenging to regain their trust.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the internet is too vast to control every negative comment about your brand. Social media has made it easier for people to share their experiences with a brand, and if a brand tries to control information, it could end up doing them more harm than good.</p>
<p>In conclusion, Oraimo&#8217;s deceptive marketing strategy raises questions about the sustainability of such practices in the long run. While it might seem like a good idea to control information about your brand, it&#8217;s not sustainable in the long run.</p>
<p>What do you think? Let&#8217;s discuss this in the comments section below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/">Oraimo&#8217;s Deceptive Marketing Strategy: Is It Sustainable in the Long Run?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/oraimos-deceptive-marketing-strategy-is-it-sustainable-in-the-long-run/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Chrome&#8217;s Memory Saver Feature Can Slow Down Your Productivity</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/how-chromes-memory-saver-feature-can-slow-down-your-productivity/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/how-chromes-memory-saver-feature-can-slow-down-your-productivity/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 13:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google Chrome is without a doubt one of the most popular web browsers available today, thanks to its simplicity, reliability, and ecosystem of browser extensions. However, due to its high resource demands, users who are running low on system resources, such as RAM or CPU, may find it challenging to keep the browser running smoothly. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-chromes-memory-saver-feature-can-slow-down-your-productivity/">How Chrome&#8217;s Memory Saver Feature Can Slow Down Your Productivity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google Chrome is without a doubt one of the most popular web browsers available today, thanks to its simplicity, reliability, and ecosystem of browser extensions. However, due to its high resource demands, users who are running low on system resources, such as RAM or CPU, may find it challenging to keep the browser running smoothly. To address this issue, Chrome comes with a feature called &#8220;Memory saver,&#8221; which can help save system resources by suspending tabs that are not in use.</p>
<p>While this feature can be a boon to some users, it is a curse for others: Take, for example, Graphic Designers or Product Designers who switch frequently between <em>Shutterstock</em>, <em>icons8</em>, and <em>Figma</em>. To summarize this scenario, the Chrome Memory Saver feature will slow down your workflow and spike CPU resource usage if you frequently switch between multiple tabs or need to access certain previously opened websites very often and quickly. This is because the page would need to be reloaded after being idle for, say 5 minutes.</p>
<h2>How Chrome&#8217;s Memory Saver Works</h2>
<p>The Chrome browser memory saver feature works by identifying tabs that have been inactive for a specific period, typically five minutes. Once a tab is deemed inactive, the browser suspends it, freeing up system resources that would have been used to keep the tab running in the background. When a user clicks on the suspended tab, the page is automatically reloaded and the user can continue from where they left off. This process is designed to help users save system resources and keep the browser running smoothly, especially on devices with limited RAM or CPU.</p>
<h2>The Drawbacks of Enabling Memory Saver on Chrome</h2>
<p>The downside of the memory saver feature is that it can slow down your workflow, especially if you frequently switch between tabs or use certain websites regularly. For instance, if you are working on a research project and need to refer to multiple web pages simultaneously, the memory saver feature may suspend some of your tabs, making it difficult to access the information you need quickly. You may have to wait for a few seconds for the tab to reload, which can be frustrating and time-consuming, especially if you are working on a tight deadline.</p>
<p>Moreover, the memory saver feature can also interfere with certain web applications, such as online banking, user registration, survey websites, or shopping websites. These types of sites often require constant updates and real-time data transmission to stay alive, and suspending them can cause errors or glitches in the application. This can result in frustration for the user and may even lead to data loss or financial losses in the case of online banking.</p>
<p>Luckily, you can create exceptions by &#8220;whitelisting&#8221; some websites from inside Chrome&#8217;s <strong>performance</strong> settings, or you can disable Chrome&#8217;s memory saver feature altogether.</p>
<h3>How To Disable Chrome&#8217;s Memory Saver</h3>
<div id="attachment_17862" style="width: 752px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17862" class="size-full wp-image-17862" title="Memory Saver toggle screen" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Memory-Saver-toggle-screen.png" alt="Memory Saver toggle screen" width="742" height="281" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Memory-Saver-toggle-screen.png 742w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Memory-Saver-toggle-screen-300x114.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Memory-Saver-toggle-screen-480x182.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 742px) 100vw, 742px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17862" class="wp-caption-text">Memory Saver toggle screen</p></div>
<p>Chrome&#8217;s Memory Saver is often enabled by default in recent versions of the browser. However, if you have made up your mind to disable this feature, you can follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Open Chrome on your computer.</li>
<li>Click on the <strong>three dots</strong> icon in the top-right corner of the browser window.</li>
<li>Select &#8220;<strong>Settings</strong>&#8221; from the drop-down menu.</li>
<li>Look at the pane on your left, and click on &#8220;<strong>Performance</strong>&#8220;.</li>
<li>Use the switch to toggle the <strong>Memory Saver</strong> feature.</li>
</ol>
<p>You can also add a list of sites to be kept active even though memory saver is left enabled. The choice is all yours.</p>
<p>Note that disabling the Memory Saver feature may cause Chrome to use more system resources and may slow down your browser&#8217;s performance. If you have a device with very limited RAM or CPU, and switch tabs less frequently, it is better to keep the feature enabled.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>In conclusion, while Chrome&#8217;s memory saver feature can be a helpful tool for users who are struggling with limited system resources, it can also slow down your workflow, especially if you frequently switch between tabs or use multiple websites regularly. If you find yourself missing deadlines often, it&#8217;s time to look towards the memory saver feature, you may consider disabling it. Ultimately, it is really up to you to decide whether the memory saver feature is a helpful tool or a hindrance to your workflow.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-chromes-memory-saver-feature-can-slow-down-your-productivity/">How Chrome&#8217;s Memory Saver Feature Can Slow Down Your Productivity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/how-chromes-memory-saver-feature-can-slow-down-your-productivity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is &#8220;Copy&#8221; in Content Marketing Terms?</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You may have come across the word &#8220;copy&#8221; in a different context before, but in content marketing, &#8220;copy&#8221; refers to the text that is used to communicate a message to an audience. The word, &#8220;Copy&#8221; can be used to refer to anything from blog posts and articles to sales pages and product descriptions. The goal [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/">What is &#8220;Copy&#8221; in Content Marketing Terms?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You may have come across the word &#8220;copy&#8221; in a different context before, but in <a href="https://branditechture.agency/20-content-generation-ideas-for-your-brands-marketing/">content marketing</a>, &#8220;copy&#8221; refers to the text that is used to communicate a message to an audience.</p>
<p>The word, &#8220;Copy&#8221; can be used to refer to anything from blog posts and articles to sales pages and product descriptions. The goal of copy in content marketing is to inform, educate, or persuade the reader to take a specific action, such as purchasing a product or signing up for a newsletter.</p>
<p>Copywriting is the act of creating this written content, and a person who specializes in this type of writing is called a copywriter.</p>
<h3>What is the Difference between copywriting and content writing?</h3>
<p>Copywriting and <a href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/">content writing</a> are similar in that they both involve creating written content, but they have some key differences.</p>
<p>Copywriting is focused on creating persuasive, sales-oriented text that is designed to get the reader to take a specific action, such as purchasing a product or signing up for a service. Content writing, on the other hand, is focused on creating informative and engaging text that provides value to the reader.</p>
<p>Content writing is often used to support the goals of a content marketing strategy by providing useful information to the reader and building trust and credibility for the brand.</p>
<h3>What are the types of copy we have in marketing?</h3>
<p>There are many different types of copy used in marketing. Some examples include:</p>
<ol>
<li>Sales copy: This type of copy is used to persuade the reader to make a purchase. It typically includes a highlight of the benefits of the product or service being sold, and a strong call-to-action <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-amazing-microcopy-tips-for-ux-designers/">microcopy</a> to nudge the reader to make a purchase.</li>
<li>Landing page copy: This type of copy is used on a website&#8217;s landing page, which is the first page a visitor sees when they arrive on the site. It is designed to grab the reader&#8217;s attention and convince them to take a specific action, such as filling out a form or making a purchase.</li>
<li>Email copy: This type of copy is used in email marketing campaigns. It is designed to engage the reader and encourage them to take a specific action, such as clicking a link or making a purchase.</li>
<li>Social media copy: This type of copy is used on social media platforms to engage followers and promote products or services. It is often concise and attention-grabbing, and may include hashtags and links to relevant content.</li>
<li>Blog post copy: This type of copy is used in blog posts and articles. It is designed to inform and educate the reader and may include links to other resources or calls-to-action.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are just a few examples of the many types of copy used in marketing. The specific type of copy that is used will depend on the goals of the marketing campaign and the target audience.</p>
<h3>What are the features of an effective copy?</h3>
<p>An effective copy should have several key features, including:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>A clear and compelling message:</strong> The copy should have a clear and concise message that is easy for the reader to understand. It should convey the value of the product or service being offered and convince the reader to take action.</li>
<li><strong>A strong call-to-action:</strong> The copy should include a strong call-to-action that tells the reader exactly what they should do next. This could be to make a purchase, sign up for a newsletter, or follow the business on social media.</li>
<li><strong>Relevance to the target audience:</strong> The copy should be relevant to the target audience and address their needs and concerns. By understanding the audience&#8217;s pain points and interests, businesses can create copy that resonates with them and motivates them to take action.</li>
<li><strong>Use of persuasive techniques:</strong> The copy should use persuasive techniques, such as testimonials, social proof, and scarcity, to convince the reader to take action. By leveraging these techniques, businesses can create copy that is more effective at persuading the reader.</li>
<li><strong>Proper grammar and spelling:</strong> The copy should be well-written, with proper grammar and spelling. This helps to ensure that the message is clear and easy to understand, and it helps to build trust and credibility with the reader.</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, an effective copy should be clear, concise, persuasive, and relevant to the target audience. By incorporating these features, businesses can create copy that is more effective at achieving their marketing goals.</p>
<h3>What are the benefits of effective copy?</h3>
<p>Effective copy has many benefits, both for the business and for the audience. Some of the key benefits of effective copy include:</p>
<p><strong>Increased sales:</strong> Effective copy is designed to persuade the reader to take a specific action, such as making a purchase. By creating compelling and persuasive copy, businesses can increase their sales and revenue.</p>
<p><strong>Improved customer engagement:</strong> Good copy is engaging and interesting, which can help to keep the reader&#8217;s attention and encourage them to take action. By providing valuable and interesting information, businesses can build trust and credibility with their audience.</p>
<p><strong>Increased website traffic:</strong> Effective copy can help to drive more traffic to a business&#8217;s website. This can be achieved through search engine optimization (SEO) techniques, such as using relevant keywords, or through social media marketing and email marketing campaigns.</p>
<p><strong>Better brand awareness:</strong> Effective copy can help to improve a business&#8217;s brand awareness. By creating consistent and compelling messaging, businesses can build their brand and <a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-build-a-unique-brand/">differentiate themselves from their competitors</a>.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Effective copy can be a powerful tool for your business. It can help you to increase sales, improve customer engagement, drive website traffic, and build brand awareness. Good copywriting practices will increase the overall value of your website.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading! If you have questions, kindly use the comment section below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/">What is &#8220;Copy&#8221; in Content Marketing Terms?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Email Signature Banners is A Killer Marketing Tool, and Here&#8217;s Why</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/email-signature-banners-as-a-marketing-tool/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/email-signature-banners-as-a-marketing-tool/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 11:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A professional email signature banner can serve many purposes. It can be a useful tool for branding, building trust, and making a good first impression. It can also help to provide important information about the sender, such as their name, title, and contact information. Here are a few key reasons why professionals should have a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/email-signature-banners-as-a-marketing-tool/">Email Signature Banners is A Killer Marketing Tool, and Here&#8217;s Why</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A professional email signature banner can serve many purposes. It can be a useful tool for branding, building trust, and making a good first impression. It can also help to provide important information about the sender, such as their name, title, and contact information.</p>
<div id="attachment_17804" style="width: 646px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17804" class="size-full wp-image-17804" title="Sample Email Signature Banner with a Clear Message" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Sample-Email-Signature-Banner-with-a-Clear-Message.png" alt="Sample Email Signature Banner with a Clear Message" width="636" height="357" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Sample-Email-Signature-Banner-with-a-Clear-Message.png 636w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Sample-Email-Signature-Banner-with-a-Clear-Message-300x168.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Sample-Email-Signature-Banner-with-a-Clear-Message-480x269.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17804" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot of my e-mail Signature banner. Notice the clear <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-amazing-microcopy-tips-for-ux-designers/">copy</a> and CTA. This signature banner automatically appends itself directly below every email I send.</p></div>
<p>Here are a few key reasons why professionals should have a creative email signature banner:</p>
<h3>1. Branding</h3>
<p>A professional email signature banner is a great way to showcase your personal or professional brand. It can include your logo, tagline, or other brand-related imagery, helping to make your emails more recognizable and memorable.</p>
<h3>2. Expertise</h3>
<p><span>Your email signature banner is a great place to showcase your expertise and highlight your unique selling points. You can include links to your website, blog, or social media profiles, which can help to promote your <a href="https://branditechture.agency/our-story/">services</a> and drive traffic to your online presence.</span></p>
<h3>3. Trust</h3>
<p>A well-designed email signature banner can help to build trust with the recipient. It provides important information about the sender, such as their name, title, and contact information, which can help to establish credibility and professionalism.</p>
<h3>4. First impressions</h3>
<p>Your email signature banner is often the first thing that the recipient will see, so it&#8217;s important to make a good impression. A well-designed banner can help to convey a sense of professionalism and attention to detail, which can be very important in the business world.</p>
<h3>5. Contact information</h3>
<p>A <a href="https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/">professional </a>email signature banner is a great place to include your contact information, such as your phone number, email address, and website. This can make it easy for the recipient to get in touch with you, and can also help to promote your personal or professional brand.</p>
<h3>Verdict</h3>
<p>Overall, a creative email signature banner is an important tool for professionals. It can help with branding, building trust, making a good first impression, and providing important contact information.</p>
<p>I personally use email signature banners as a silent marketing tool because they are a subtle yet effective way to promote my brand, showcase my expertise, and provide important contact information to recipients of my emails. Since email signature banners are automatically included in every email that a person sends,  it simply means that it can reach a wide audience without the need for additional effort or resources.</p>
<p>By now, you should agree with me that an email signature banner is a non-intrusive way to promote your brand or services. It is included at the bottom of the email, so it does not disrupt the main content of the message. This can make it more effective than more overt forms of marketing, such as advertisements, promotional emails, email blasts, or WhatsApp broadcasts.</p>
<p>I hope you enjoy reading. If you have any questions, kindly drop your comments below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/email-signature-banners-as-a-marketing-tool/">Email Signature Banners is A Killer Marketing Tool, and Here&#8217;s Why</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/email-signature-banners-as-a-marketing-tool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Inemesit Etim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 08:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tech guys are all about the value their car gives them, not the money; that is not their problem. They want to park at the gym on a hot Saturday morning and be the center of attraction, not the guy whose car blows thick clouds every time. If you are that tech guy looking for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/">Top 5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span>Tech guys are all about the value their car gives them, not the money; that is not their problem. They want to park at the gym on a hot Saturday morning and be the center of attraction, not the guy whose car blows thick clouds every time.</span></p>
<p><span>If you are that tech guy looking for a car in Nigeria, there are car brands you should avoid, including the Toyota Sienna. Trust me, I have nothing against this car brand, but even you will agree that it doesn&#8217;t go with your style, and the list goes on and on.</span></p>
<p><span>Some cars will cause you more trouble than they&#8217;re worth, and you don&#8217;t want to worry about car repairs when there&#8217;s a code to crack. If you&#8217;re that tech guy who just hit the <em>milli</em> and wants a nice car, you&#8217;re in the right place.</span></p>
<p><span> At the end of this article, I will give you a heads-up on what to look out for in a car as a tech bro. I&#8217;m considering everything from aesthetics to speed, <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lifestyle/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">reliability and safety</a>.</span></p>
<h2>5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Guy</h2>
<div id="attachment_17778" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17778" class="wp-image-17778 size-large" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1024x736.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro" width="940" height="676" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1024x736.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-300x216.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-768x552.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-480x345.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro.jpg 1057w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17778" class="wp-caption-text">Toyota Sienna</p></div>
<h3>1. Avoid The Toyota Sienna</h3>
<p><span>The Toyota Sienna is one of the best minivans on the market. It is roomy, comfortable, and stylish, with a powertrain that provides 245 horsepower. It has an EPA fuel rating of 36 mpg in the city and 36 mpg on the highway. </span></p>
<p><span>On the interior, you&#8217;ll see a center console that runs from the dashboard to the center armrest. The Toyota Sienna&#8217;s newest infotainment system is a 9.0-inch touchscreen display that sits upright over the climate controls on the dashboard. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CarPlay" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple CarPlay</a>, Android Auto, and Amazon Alexa connection are standard, and the van&#8217;s interior has seven USB outlets. </span></p>
<p><span>As for safety, the Toyota Sienna comes with blind-spot monitoring and its Safety Sense 2.0 bundle of driver-assistance features. It earned five stars from the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, <a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/vehicle/2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NHTSA</a>, for safety and a predicted reliability score of 74 out of 100. </span></p>
<p><span>Why, then, should you avoid it? We can all agree that Siennas are meant for large families because which tech guy needs an 8-seater car? And the aesthetics are basic, not cool. Remember, you&#8217;ll see and drive your car every day. It better looks good.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17779" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17779" class="size-large wp-image-17779" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-1024x752.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 1" width="940" height="690" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-1024x752.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-300x220.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-768x564.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1-480x353.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-1.jpg 1055w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17779" class="wp-caption-text">Kia Soul</p></div>
<h3>2. Stay Away From The Kia Soul</h3>
<p><span>The Kia Soul is a small, boxy, subcompact car offered in various trims and powertrain configurations. Beautiful car but too problematic; the Kia Soul is prone to oil leaks. Such repairs are expensive, but the most annoying part is that it is frequent. </span></p>
<p><span>Kia Soul owners also say the car has suspension issues. The front wheel bearings and suspension springs are prone to failure. Furthermore, steering pins and tie rod system components might break, resulting in ongoing suspension troubles and costly repairs.</span></p>
<p><span>That&#8217;s not the only problem Kia Souls have; there are reports that the Kia Soul could lose power unexpectedly while driving. Most of them are caused by catalytic converter damage induced by high exhaust temperatures. Imagine you&#8217;re cruising on Third Mainland bridge, and your car ceases, not cool. </span></p>
<p><span>The power problem causes engine components to fail and, in extreme cases, can result in a fire beneath the hood. Yes, the Soul is prone to catching fire. It is a serious issue, and Kia recalled nearly 380,000 vehicles due to fire risks in 2021. But you&#8217;re in Nigeria, so even if there were a recall, you wouldn&#8217;t benefit from it.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17780" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17780" class="size-large wp-image-17780" title="2012 Acura TL" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-1024x755.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 2" width="940" height="693" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-1024x755.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-300x221.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-768x567.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2-480x354.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-2.jpg 1052w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17780" class="wp-caption-text">2012 Acura TL</p></div>
<h3>3. Leave The 2012 Acura TL Alone</h3>
<p><span>The 2012 Acura TL is one of the best-equipped sedans in its class, offering a strong V6 engine, excellent handling and braking ability, and a comfortable ride. Standard equipment on the 2012 Acura TL includes leather upholstery, heated front seats, a power sunroof, automatic climate control, and Bluetooth. </span></p>
<p><span>2012 Acura is not bad on fuel efficiency either. It has an EPA rating of 20/29 mpg city/highway. So when fuel prices go up at year-end, you can trust your car not to empty your bank account. </span></p>
<p><span>Some reviewers say the brake is powerful, while others say it feels numb. You need a sound brake system for the Nigerian road where most drivers aren&#8217;t very sane but let&#8217;s not forget safety. </span></p>
<p><span>No one plans to ram their car onto another one, but if it happened, you&#8217;d trust your car to save you, right? The 2012 Acura TL is not that car. It has an NHTSA rating of two over five for the frontal crash test and an overall NHTSA safety rating of three over five stars. Dear tech guy, you work so hard to make millions; there&#8217;s no way you want your career to end because your car couldn&#8217;t protect you.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17781" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17781" class="size-large wp-image-17781" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 3" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-1024x665.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 3" width="940" height="610" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-1024x665.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-300x195.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-768x498.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3-480x312.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-3.jpg 1228w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17781" class="wp-caption-text">Tesla</p></div>
<h3>4. Don&#8217;t Buy A Tesla</h3>
<p><span>I know you didn&#8217;t see this coming, but that Tesla car you admire is not suitable for you. Sure, you love Elon Musk&#8217;s technology, and I agree, the guy is a tech genius, but you&#8217;re a tech guy in Nigeria, not Canada. The <a href="https://www.tesla.com/models" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Model S</a> has a 396-mile range, 1,020 horsepower, and an overall top speed of 200 miles per hour, a true classic. Plus, the Model S has cutting-edge technology and a lovely interior. </span></p>
<p><span>Nigerians love luxury cars; no matter how expensive a car is, at least two people in Nigeria will buy it. I&#8217;ve seen a Tesla before in Nigeria, and more may be on their way, but someone else should buy them, not you.</span></p>
<p><span>Charging will always be a problem. An electric vehicle needs to be charged in a proper electric charging station. Furthermore, the S model has suspension, body components, and electronics issues.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_17782" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17782" class="size-large wp-image-17782" title="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 4" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-1024x672.jpg" alt="Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro 4" width="940" height="617" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-1024x672.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-300x197.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-768x504.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4-480x315.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Cars-To-Avoid-As-A-Tech-Bro-4.jpg 1182w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17782" class="wp-caption-text">Subaru Outback</p></div>
<h3>5. Don&#8217;t Buy A Subaru Outback</h3>
<p><span>Yes, the Subaru Outback is a great wagon. It combines car-like handling and small-SUV performance with a slew of standard and optional technology, comfort, and driver-assistance systems. In the 2022 Outback, Subaru offers two versions of their Starlink infotainment system. </span></p>
<p><span>The entry-level models have a pair of 7-inch touch screens and a few buttons and knobs for quick navigation. However, the top speed of any Outback model is roughly 130 mph, which is too sluggish for you. You can get it for your significant other.</span></p>
<h2>What Should Tech Guys Look For In A Car?</h2>
<p><span>Many people buy cars only because it&#8217;s cheap that&#8217;s why we outlined <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lifestyle/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the best 10 luxury cars under 7 million naira for naija techies</a>, but if you want the best of what is available, you must stop thinking about the cost. But tech guys supposedly have money because there’s money in the IT industry. With all that being said, here are some things that tech guys look out for when buying a car.</span></p>
<h3>Class</h3>
<p><span>Men love to drive in style, and tech guys raise the bar; they go for class. In case you haven’t noticed, perception is everything. When you’ve achieved a certain status in life, you no longer want the basic things. Your car choice will go beyond what helps you move faster to what gives you that stylish excellence. Tech guys and excellence go so well together.</span></p>
<h3>A Sound Navigation System</h3>
<p><span>GPS navigation systems help drivers navigate through unfamiliar locations. They can also show traffic conditions and even allow you to search for nearby restaurants, hotels, and other businesses. Some navigation systems also have voice control, so you can ask for directions without taking your hands off the wheel.</span></p>
<h3>Connectivity</h3>
<p><span>Connected cars allow you to check your vehicle&#8217;s status remotely to adjust climate control settings while you&#8217;re away from home or work using your smartphone. Many newer cars have built-in Wi-Fi hotspots so passengers can connect their smartphones and other devices while on the road.</span></p>
<p><span>Bluetooth allows you to connect your smartphone or another device to your car&#8217;s stereo system to listen to music or make calls while driving. For tech guys, music is therapeutic; what use is a car without music?</span></p>
<h3>Reliability</h3>
<p><span>If you&#8217;re buying a new car, don&#8217;t just focus on what looks good and drives well — take the time to find out how well it will hold up over time. Cars go through a lot during their lifetimes. They should handle everyday wear and tear without breaking down or needing expensive repairs too often. </span></p>
<p><span>A vehicle that gets excellent reliability ratings from <a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Consumer Reports</a> or JD Power will probably be more dependable than one that doesn&#8217;t perform as well in these tests.</span></p>
<h3>Safety</h3>
<p><span>Safety is important in cars. When you&#8217;re driving, you need to be able to trust your car will keep you and your passengers safe. If you&#8217;re not comfortable with the safety of your vehicle, it&#8217;s time to get it checked out by a mechanic before driving it again. </span></p>
<p><span>The NHTSA has made progress in getting car companies to manufacture vehicles with better safety features. They test car safety on side crashes, front crash, and over-lapping. If your car gets five out of five stars on safety, it&#8217;s a good buy.</span></p>
<h3>Fuel Economy</h3>
<p><span>If you&#8217;re buying an SUV because you want more space for your family but don&#8217;t want gas bills that rival those of a yacht owner, check out fuel economy before committing yourself to anything too big or powerful. Smaller cars tend to get better gas mileage than larger ones. </span></p>
<h2>Wrap Up</h2>
<p><span>Cars aren’t just machines for transportation; in a way, your car reflects your personality. Just like clothes can make or break your style, cars can make or break your image, which is why aesthetics are important. But beyond that, consider how safe, reliable, and fuel-efficient the car is before you buy.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/">Top 5 Nigerian Cars To Avoid As A Tech Bro</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/top-5-nigerian-cars-to-avoid-as-a-tech-bro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Techies in Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Inemesit Etim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 07:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17738</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When buying a luxury car, you usually have two options: buy pre-owned or buy new. If you&#8217;re drooling for a new ride but don&#8217;t want to pay too much, you have to decide how much you’re willing to spend on a car and stick to the budget. One of the best luxury cars in Nigeria [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/">Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Techies in Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="normal" style="margin-bottom: 10.0pt">When buying a luxury car, you usually have two options: buy pre-owned or buy new. If you&#8217;re drooling for a new ride but don&#8217;t want to pay too much, you have to decide how much you’re willing to spend on a car and stick to the budget.</p>
<p class="normal" style="margin-bottom: 10.0pt">One of the best luxury cars in Nigeria is the Kia Rio 1.4L which you can get for less than 7 million Naira. This car offers the standard and comfortable driving experience you crave at a lower price. The Toyota Venza is cool too, but for this budget, you can only get a used one.</p>
<p class="normal" style="margin-bottom: 10.0pt">Luxury cars have always been expensive, but there are some great bargains out there. You just need to look in the right place. This article will save you stress by highlighting the best luxury cars under 7 million naira for young tech guys in Nigeria.</p>
<h2>10 Best Affordable Luxury Cars Under 7 Million</h2>
<div id="attachment_17786" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17786" class="size-large wp-image-17786" title="luxury cars" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1024x764.jpg" alt="luxury cars" width="940" height="701" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1024x764.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-300x224.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-768x573.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-480x358.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars.jpg 1155w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17786" class="wp-caption-text">Lexus ES 330</p></div>
<h3>1. Lexus ES 330</h3>
<p>Here’s another luxury innovation by the Toyota Motor Corporation. Lexus ES 330 doesn’t just tick the list of luxurious cars but prides itself in allowing its users to enjoy a thrilling ride with safety and confidence without spending so much.</p>
<p>Lexus ES 330 isn’t your regular car; the aesthetics are superb. It features an incredible 3.3L 6-cylinder engine that produces 225 Horsepower and 240lb-ft of torque that transforms into a five-speed automatic transmission.</p>
<p>If you’re not tall and you wish to get the Lexus ES 330, don’t worry. This model has an adjustable driver’s seat that can increase or reduce the height. This seat also has lumbar support that enhances comfort. This model also prides itself on the large cabin, which can contain up to eight people.</p>
<p>Whether locally or foreign fairly used, you can get Lexus ES 330 in Nigeria for as low as 2.5 million Naira. However, the price sometimes depends on the condition of the car. Depending on this, the price can increase to 3.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.5 to 3.5 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 2.7 to 5.1 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17787" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17787" class="size-large wp-image-17787" title="luxury cars 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-1024x762.jpg" alt="luxury cars 1" width="940" height="699" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-1024x762.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-300x223.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-768x571.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1-480x357.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-1.jpg 1167w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17787" class="wp-caption-text">2005 Nissan Xterra</p></div>
<h3>2. 2005 Nissan Xterra</h3>
<p>From a sleek design to superfast acceleration, the 2005 Nissan Xterra is a luxurious ride that allows you to enjoy a more practical and thrilling ride without spending so much. It prides itself in being an excellent ride that satisfies your cravings with standard features and quality infotainment at an affordable rate.</p>
<p>With a 6.0L engine, 265 Horsepower, 284lb-ft of torque, and a five-speed automatic transmission, you’ll surely enjoy a thrilling ride experience. Talk of the lightweight, beautiful exterior and interior features, and the standard infotainment systems, the 2005 Nissan Xterra has it all polished to impress you.</p>
<p>It offers fine features like traction control, electronic brakeforce distribution, tire pressure monitoring, and an adjustable driver’s seat. Its tire pressure monitoring device ensures safety and value for your money.</p>
<p>The price for this vehicle ranges from 2.5 million Naira to 5.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.5 million Naira to 4.5 million Naira.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Foreign used: Between 3.5 million Naira to 5.5 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17789" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17789" class="size-large wp-image-17789" title="luxury cars 2" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-1024x533.jpg" alt="luxury cars 2" width="940" height="489" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-1024x533.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-300x156.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-768x400.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-480x250.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2-1320x687.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-2.jpg 1469w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17789" class="wp-caption-text">Honda Cr-V</p></div>
<h3>3. Honda Cr-V</h3>
<p>Here’s another mid-range model of Honda that gives you that classy and sleek SUV feeling without taking so much from your pocket. Honda CR-V is one of the luxurious car brands with standard features that offer a high-quality and comfortable riding experience.</p>
<p>According to Honda, CR-V represents a Comfortable Roundabout Vehicle. Asides from being fuel efficient, the Honda CR-V has quality inbuilt technology and high-quality infotainment systems to keep you entertained on the road.</p>
<p>It also offers a sleek and stylish performance with its 39.2 cubic feet that expands up to 75.8, 148 Horsepower, and 350lb-ft of torque with manual transmission gear.</p>
<p>Honda CR-V ranks the second best on SUVs compact list. Currently, it is 15.5 million Naira in the Nigerian automobile market. However, you can get a fairly used one for 5.5 million Naira. And not to worry! The fairly used ones are just as good as the brand-new ones.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 3.5 million Naira to 5.5 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 4.1 million Naira to 5.7 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17790" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17790" class="size-large wp-image-17790" title="luxury cars 3" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-1024x649.jpg" alt="luxury cars 3" width="940" height="596" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-1024x649.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-300x190.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-768x487.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3-480x304.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-3.jpg 1269w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17790" class="wp-caption-text">Honda Accord</p></div>
<h3>4. Honda Accord</h3>
<p>A million thanks to Honda for crafting this supermodel. This luxury car offers peerless driving dynamics, quality infotainment systems, and fuel efficiency. It’s standard at its peak; isn’t that what we all want?</p>
<p>The Honda Accord is equipped with five comfortable seats, a 2.0L engine, and a ten-speed automatic transmission, so your car glides through Nigerian roads smoothly.</p>
<p>The Honda Accord also has dual-zone automatic climate control, soft leather seats, Apple CarPlay, and Android Auto smartphone integration, which combine to wow your ride experience. For safety, you get low-speed anti-collision braking.</p>
<p>If you’re looking forward to buying a honda accord in Nigeria, you need to budget 13 million Naira. However, you can get fairly used between 2.5 to 6.5 million Naira. The fairly-used ones are as good as the brand-new ones.</p>
<p>You may notice glitches with the ignition switch coupled with excess oil usage, but, the Honda Accord tops ranks 85 out of 100 in reliability.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.2 to 5.2 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 5.7 to 6.2 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17791" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17791" class="size-large wp-image-17791" title="luxury cars" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-1024x652.jpg" alt="luxury cars 4" width="940" height="599" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-1024x652.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-300x191.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-768x489.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4-480x306.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-4.jpg 1256w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17791" class="wp-caption-text">Kia Rio</p></div>
<h3>5. Kia Rio 1.4L Top</h3>
<p>Kia Rio is a luxurious mid-sedan that comes in four colors; Aurora black, Bright Silver, Clear White, and Signal Rendall. It rates high in performance, style, and speed.</p>
<p>With a cabin that offers a five-seat interior comfort, standard infotainment, an inbuilt air conditioner, brake assistance, adjustable seats, and central locking to keep you protected inside, this car sets the standard for comfort and safety.</p>
<p>The Kia Rio 1.4L offers a sleek and stylish performance with its 107 Horsepower, 136 lb-ft, and a four-speed automatic transmission. Users also praise it for its top speed in delivering at 183 km/hour.</p>
<p>What’s more? Kia Rio 1.4L Top rates are high in the list of reliable cars, which offers good value for your money. The starting price is 5.4 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.5 to 4.8 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 3.8 to 6.3 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17792" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17792" class="size-large wp-image-17792" title="luxury cars 5" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-1024x735.jpg" alt="luxury cars 5" width="940" height="675" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-1024x735.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-300x215.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-768x551.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5-480x344.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-5.jpg 1169w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17792" class="wp-caption-text">Toyota Venza</p></div>
<h3>6. Toyota Venza</h3>
<p>You can say that Toyota Venza is a ride that’s excellent in all forms, and you wouldn’t be wrong. Riding in this luxurious and sleek ride will give you value for your money while allowing you to enjoy comfort at its peak with quality infotainment systems and a  ride experience.</p>
<p>The seats of this beautiful model are soft. Covered with smooth feathers, they offer comfort at any trim level and are easy to clean. It also has a digital rearview mirror that doesn’t just display a reflection when in use but also displays the camera from the rearview mirror.</p>
<p>With its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hybrid_vehicle" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hybrid engine</a>, it has a continuous-variable automatic speed. It doubles up on-road performance providing 219 HorsePower and 1,029 torque power.</p>
<p>The driver’s seat in Toyota Venza is adjustable and offers lumbar support. What’s more? The tires can survive on any terrain, rough or smooth. For reliability rating, it rates 78 out of 100.</p>
<p>The price of Toyota Venza in Nigeria ranges from 2.3 million Naira to 6.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.3 to 5.5 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 5.5 to 6.5 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17793" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17793" class="size-large wp-image-17793" title="luxury cars 6" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-1024x649.jpg" alt="luxury cars 6" width="940" height="596" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-1024x649.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-300x190.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-768x487.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6-480x304.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-6.jpg 1315w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17793" class="wp-caption-text">Nissan X-trail</p></div>
<h3>7. Nissan X-trail</h3>
<p>The Nissan X-trail is a spectacular mid-sized SUV. With its top-quality infotainment systems and smooth ride, you cannot help but rate this model high.</p>
<p>Talking about the interior, this model can easily pass for a family car as it has a large interior; you’d appreciate this extra space if you have a bunch of tech kids growing under your roof. The seating system is flexible, and you can adjust it to suit your style.</p>
<p>The price range for Nissan x-trail in Nigeria ranges from 10 million to 12 million Naira. However, you can get a fairly used Nissan X-trail between 2.5 million Naira to 6.8 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.5 to 5.8 million Naira.<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 2.6 to 6.8 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17794" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17794" class="size-large wp-image-17794" title="luxury cars" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-1024x547.jpg" alt="luxury cars" width="940" height="502" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-1024x547.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-300x160.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-768x410.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-480x256.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX-1320x705.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Acura-MDX.jpg 1477w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17794" class="wp-caption-text">Acura MDX</p></div>
<h3>8. Acura MDX</h3>
<p>For luxurious cars, it’s the faster, the better, and Acura MDX ticks all the boxes. It is super fast, reliable, and safe.  With its lightweight, standard interior and sleek exterior, this car is everything a tech guy would love. Everything about Acura MDX speaks style and class.</p>
<p>It is a good choice if you want to go low on fuel consumption and the premium safety features allow you to feel a sense of comfort while in motion. The most interesting part is that you can get this model for as low as 2.8 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between 2.3 million Naira to 4.5 million Naira<br />
</strong><strong>Foreign used: Between 2.8 million Naira to 6.8 million Naira</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17795" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17795" class="size-large wp-image-17795" title="luxury cars 7" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-1024x577.jpg" alt="luxury cars 7" width="940" height="530" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-1024x577.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-768x433.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-480x270.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7-1320x744.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-7.jpg 1480w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17795" class="wp-caption-text">Hyundai Grand</p></div>
<h3>9. Hyundai Grand</h3>
<p>Despite its ups and downs, Hyundai Grand still strives to be among the best luxurious and affordable vehicles for tech guys.</p>
<p>This model has 256 liters of cargo space. With five seating capacities, a 7.0-inch touchscreen infotainment system with android and apple CarPlay,  automatic ORVMs that lock and unlock, 81.86 horsepower, 13.75 torque power, and manual transmission speed, this model prides itself in standard features that add up to its premium qualities.</p>
<p>As for reliability rating, Hyundai ranks 75 out of 100, which is a pretty impressive score. The price depends on the model and condition, but the starting price in Nigeria is 8.5 million Naira. However, you can get a fairly used one for 3.8 million Naira.</p>
<p><strong>Nigeria used: Between  2.8 to 4.5 million Naira.<br />
Foreign used: Between 5.5 to 6.8 million Naira.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_17796" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17796" class="size-large wp-image-17796" title="luxury cars 8" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-1024x511.jpg" alt="luxury cars 8" width="940" height="469" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-1024x511.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-300x150.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-768x383.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-480x239.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8-1320x659.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/luxury-cars-8.jpg 1327w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17796" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-Benz C-300</p></div>
<h3>10. Mercedes-Benz C-300 (2010)</h3>
<p>Talk about strength, durability, and class; the Mercedes-Benz C-300 has got it all. It doesn’t matter if you buy a fairly used one; with good servicing, this vehicle can last you as long as seven years before needing an <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lifestyle/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">expensive repair</a>.</p>
<p>The Mercedes-Benz C-300 is fitted with a 3.0L hybrid engine that generates 228 Horsepower and a seven-speed shiftable transmission for a comfy and pleasurable performance. It can go as fast as 130 miles per hour.</p>
<p>It also prides itself on premium features like a four-wheel independent suspension, an adjustable driver seat with lumber support, five seating capacity, and descent control. If you’re not tall, don’t worry, this model has height-adjustable seats for your comfort. Asides from the roomy interior, it has traction control which is perfect for Nigerian terrains.</p>
<p>In Nigeria, the start price for Mercedes-Benz C-300 is quite expensive, but you can get a fairly used one for as low as 6.5 million Naira.</p>
<p><b>Nigeria used: Between 6.5 million to 6.9 million Naira.</b></p>
<p><b>Foreign used: Between 6.9 million to 7 million Naira.</b></p>
<h2>Wrap Up</h2>
<p>There you have it! The 10 Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Tech Guys in Nigeria. These car models are super fast, sleek, and classy. So, if you want to buy a luxury but affordable car, you have those ten car models to choose from.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/">Best Luxury Cars Under 7 Million Naira for Young Techies in Nigeria</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/best-luxury-cars-under-7-million-naira-for-young-techies-in-nigeria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
