<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Power Banks &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/category/reviews/power-banks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 10:31:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Power Banks &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Review of the Oraimo Power Bank Series &#8211; Things to Know Before Buying One</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/oraimo-power-bank-series/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/oraimo-power-bank-series/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 05:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Power Banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Backup power supply (or BPS) is the subject of conversation for many freelancers and social media enthusiasts in developing countries, but no thanks to the never-ending epileptic supply of electric power, especially in West Africa. The Oraimo™ power bank is a compact device that is used to store charges for use in the absence of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/oraimo-power-bank-series/">Review of the Oraimo Power Bank Series &#8211; Things to Know Before Buying One</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Backup power supply (or BPS) is the subject of conversation for many freelancers and social media enthusiasts in developing countries, but no thanks to the never-ending epileptic supply of electric power, especially in West Africa. The Oraimo™ power bank is a compact device that is used to store charges for use in the absence of AC power or when on the move.</p>
<div id="attachment_17197" style="width: 653px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17197" class="size-full wp-image-17197" title="Meme Oraimo CEO right now" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Meme-Oraimo-CEO-right-now.jpg" alt="Meme Oraimo CEO right now" width="643" height="500" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Meme-Oraimo-CEO-right-now.jpg 643w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Meme-Oraimo-CEO-right-now-300x233.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Meme-Oraimo-CEO-right-now-480x373.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 643px) 100vw, 643px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17197" class="wp-caption-text">Meme: Oraimo CEO right now</p></div>
<p>The Oraimo power banks have gained popularity on social media due to their durability.</p>
<p>Out of genuine excitement, some Oraimo fans even claim their power bank &#8220;can charge all the smartphones on their street and still not run out of battery juice&#8221;. But how good are the Oraimo power bank series? Continue reading my hands-on review to find out.</p>
<p>For the sake of this review, I bought two Oraimo Power Banks; the 27,000mAh and the 40,000mAh variants. I purchased them two months ago from the official Oraimo Store. And since I would like this review to be more extensive, I went in search of people who use other models of the Oraimo power banks ( the 20,000mAh, and the 30,000mAh variants ) and I finally got them all from our <a class="thirstylink" title="Telegram Group" href="https://branditechture.agency/recommends/telegram/">Telegram group</a>.</p>

<h2>How to Interpret the Capacity of Power Banks</h2>
<p>When choosing what Oraimo power bank to buy, you would often come across some technical jargon like <em><strong>mAh</strong>, <strong>Watt</strong>, <strong>Output Voltage</strong> e.t.c.,</em> but I would explain them in bits so that they make more sense to you.</p>
<p><strong>mAh: </strong> Just so you know, <strong><em>mAh</em></strong> is a unit that is commonly used to measure the energy storage capacity of a battery. The higher the mAh, the more energy the power bank will store.  The more mAh a power bank has, the longer it takes to discharge.</p>
<p><strong>Watt:</strong> Another metric to consider when rating power banks is the <strong>Wattage</strong>, which is measured in <em><strong>Watts. </strong></em>In power banks and other electronic appliances, &#8220;Watt&#8221; is the unit used to describe the maximum speed of electric current that a power bank (or charger) can output. That is why we have fast-charging technology today. Fast Chargers usually have a Wattage of between <strong>18 Watts to 27 Watts. </strong>Please note that for fast charging to work, the connected device needs to support the Fast Charging technology.</p>
<p><strong>Dual Charging Ports:</strong> Power Banks that allow more than one device to be charged at the same time are said to have dual charging ports. Some Oraimo power banks have two output charging ports, while some have just one.</p>
<p><strong>Output Voltage: </strong>The standard output voltage for smartphone and power bank chargers is between 3.5V -5V. But the new Anifast Technology in some Oraimo power banks brings this to as high as 9V. Some bigger models can even deliver an amazing 12V. Don&#8217;t worry though, Oraimo power banks have intelligent microchips that prevent using the wrong output voltage for an unsupported device.</p>
<p><strong>Amperage:</strong> Measured in <em>Amps (A). </em>This is the amount of electric charge moving out of a power source at any given time. A good power bank should have at least 2A. Though you&#8217;d mostly see Oraimo power banks with 3A, and that&#8217;s perfect for charging our smartphones. Amperage (measured in Amps), in combination with Wattage (measured in Watts), determines how long a power bank would take to fully charge a device, although the battery capacity of the device that is being charged is another variable that should be considered at all times.</p>
<p>Apologies for all the technical details above, but they might help you better understand what you are paying for. Now let&#8217;s take a look at the complete list of Oraimo power banks currently available on sale today.</p>
<h2>Full List of Oraimo Power Banks and Their Battery Capacity</h2>
<p>Here is a full list of power bank models currently offered by Oraimo and their battery capacity in milliamp hours (mAh).</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Model Name</th>
<th>Capacity</th>
<th>Price (NGN)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>oraimo PowerBox 400</td>
<td>40000mAh</td>
<td>₦24,000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo PowerBox 300</td>
<td>30000mAh</td>
<td>₦18,000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Traveler 3 Byte</td>
<td>27000mAh</td>
<td>₦16,500</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Traveler 4 Pro</td>
<td>20000mAh</td>
<td>₦11,500</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Traveler 4</td>
<td>20000mAh</td>
<td>₦9,500</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Traveler 160</td>
<td>16000mAh</td>
<td>₦9,500</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Pilot</td>
<td>20000mAh</td>
<td>₦10,900</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Toast 10 Byte</td>
<td>10000mAh</td>
<td>₦6,800</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Toast 10 PD</td>
<td>10000mAh</td>
<td>₦8,200</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Toast 10 PD Pro</td>
<td>10000mAh</td>
<td>₦7,200</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Toast 10 Lite</td>
<td>10000mAh</td>
<td>₦5,900</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>oraimo Slice</td>
<td>10000mAh</td>
<td>₦6,000</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>How Good are the Oraimo Power Banks?</h2>
<p>Generally speaking, Oraimo power banks are pretty good. Asides from the wide range of models to choose from, Oraimo power banks boast one of the best battery life on the market. After a couple of charging cycles over my two months of use, there seemed to be no degradation of the battery life.</p>
<p>Some Oraimo power banks also have an LCD display that allows you to check the exact battery level at any point in time. Apparently, this is a handy feature.</p>
<p><strong><em>The following</em> Oraimo Power bank models feature an LCD Display;</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>✅ <strong>oraimo PowerBox 400,</strong> 40,000mAh (₦24,000)</li>
<li>✅<strong> oraimo PowerBox 300,</strong> 30,000mAh (₦18,000)</li>
<li>✅ <strong>oraimo Traveler 3 Byte,</strong> 27,000mAh (₦16,500)</li>
<li>✅ <strong>oraimo Traveler 160,</strong> 16,000mAh (₦9,500)</li>
<li>✅ <strong>oraimo Toast 10 Byte</strong> 10,000mAh (₦6,800)</li>
</ul>
<p>The <strong>20,000mAh Oraimo Traveler 4 Pro</strong> doesn&#8217;t feature an LCD display despite being over 4,000 NGN more expensive than the <em><strong>Toast 10 Byte</strong></em>. However, it is twice the capacity. So if you have a low to medium budget, you might find yourself having to choose between an LCD display or a bigger battery capacity. 😁<span> </span></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>This post would be updated in the coming weeks to cover areas such as Fast Charging, PD (Power Delivery), Dual Ports, and so on. So stay tuned and subscribe. </em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/oraimo-power-bank-series/">Review of the Oraimo Power Bank Series &#8211; Things to Know Before Buying One</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/oraimo-power-bank-series/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>85</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
