<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Natalia Bachmann &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/author/nataliabachmann/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Natalia Bachmann &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Why Fashion Nova was Built on Shopify</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natalia Bachmann]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=15832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Fashion Nova (www.fashionnova.com) is one of the world&#8217;s leading fast-fashion and lifestyle companies known for delivering the season&#8217;s hottest looks to millions of consumers across the world. It is a Los Angeles-based e-commerce firm that basically operates online with five retail outlets around Southern California which sell collections for women, men, curves, and kids. Fashion [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/">Why Fashion Nova was Built on Shopify</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fashion Nova (www.fashionnova.com) is one of the world&#8217;s leading fast-fashion and lifestyle companies known for delivering the season&#8217;s hottest looks to millions of consumers across the world. It is a Los Angeles-based e-commerce firm that basically operates online with five retail outlets around Southern California which sell collections for women, men, curves, and kids.</p>
<p>Fashion Nova was established in 2006 by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/style/luxury/article/3170404/who-fashion-nova-ceo-richard-saghian-new-owner-las-biggest" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Richard Saghian,</a> who is worth $1.4 billion (US Dollars) as of 2022. Richard began his career in the fashion retail industry by working at his father&#8217;s Los Angeles apparel boutique. Fashion Nova currently has over 600 employees.</p>
<p>In 2018, it was Google’s #1 most-searched Fashion brand with over 21 million followers on social media especially Instagram, including celebrity admirers and partners. In exchange for promoting the brand, models, celebrities, and others are paid or given free apparel.</p>
<h2>Is Fashion Nova Built Using Shopify?</h2>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-15840" title="Fashion Nova standing ipad mockup" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup.png" alt="Fashion Nova standing ipad mockup" width="2800" height="2100" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup.png 2800w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-300x225.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-1024x768.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-768x576.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-1536x1152.png 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-480x360.png 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-1320x990.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2800px) 100vw, 2800px" /></p>
<p>Yes, we can 100% confirm that <a href="http://fashionnova.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Fashion Nova</a> is built and hosted on Shopify. For many successful e-commerce companies, Shopify is a top choice, and these are some important reasons why Fashion Nova was built using Shopify:</p>
<ol>
<li>The Shopify theme is adaptable and responsive with over 100 free and premium templates for all types of eCommerce enterprises. Its eCommerce framework allows you to easily add new features to your website and adjust the look to fit your preferences.</li>
<li>Shopify stores are simple to set up, and even a novice can get them up and running in a matter of days.</li>
<li>Fashion Nova is basically an online store and using the Shopify platform is quite affordable. Their monthly plans start at just $29 per month. They also provide a 14-day risk-free trial</li>
<li>Just like other eCommerce platforms, Shopify handles things like site hosting and other technicalities to remove obstacles to business ownership.</li>
<li>Even during the trial time, there is support for customers. Shopify provides 24/7 customer care via alternatives like live chat.</li>
<li>For Shopify, sustainability is a priority, and store owners like Fashion Nova love this idea. Shopify has social-impact programs in place, such as using renewable energy and minimizing carbon emissions.</li>
</ol>
<p>Currently, Fashion Nova has employed the use of a <a title="Shopify theme" href="https://branditechture.agency/recommends/shopify-theme/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Shopify theme</a>, known as&#8221;Shopify-Nova&#8221;. This theme is both mobile and SEO-friendly. Because of the abundance of user-generated content such as reviews on the site, it will appeal to people of all ages. The content will boost site engagement, which is crucial for the company.</p>

<h2>Fashion Nova&#8217;s Sales Strategy</h2>
<p>In the fashion industry, it&#8217;s no longer considered an option to want your business to have a social media presence; it&#8217;s now a necessity. Fashion Nova understands this and has been using the online platform to its advantage. To date, Fashion Nova has made sales of over 1 billion US Dollars by just being an online store. With Google search volumes that beat out Chanel and Dior in 2017, it has one of the most effective online marketing techniques among fashion brands today.</p>
<p>Although the online store boasts of lightning-fast delivery and a steady stream of new high-quality items, this isn&#8217;t the cause for its current success as the leading fashion store. Fashion Nova simply knows how to advertise their goods properly. Its social media marketing has reached millions, if not billions, of individuals using models, celebrities, and even customers. It is one of the largest online fashion stores with also one of the largest social media presences.</p>
<h3>The Secret of Fashion Nova’s Success Exposed</h3>
<div id="attachment_15837" style="width: 1820px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15837" class="size-full wp-image-15837" title="Richard Saghian and Cardi B" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-scaled.jpg" alt="Richard Saghian and Cardi B" width="1810" height="2560" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-scaled.jpg 1810w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-212x300.jpg 212w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-724x1024.jpg 724w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-768x1086.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-1086x1536.jpg 1086w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-1448x2048.jpg 1448w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-480x679.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-1320x1867.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1810px) 100vw, 1810px" /><p id="caption-attachment-15837" class="wp-caption-text">CEO of Nova Fashion, Richard Saghian and Cardi B</p></div>
<p>Building a store on Shopify does not automatically guarantee success, and Richard Saghian, the founder of Fashion Nova, was one of the first to understand the importance of social media platforms in marketing his business when the company was founded in 2006. Their great social media strategy and usage of user-generated content made them really stand out.</p>
<p>Their huge success was due to their collaborative influencer approach. They had celebrities like Kylie Jenner, Cardi B, Nicki Minaj, and Khloe Kardashian post photos of themselves wearing the brand&#8217;s clothing on Instagram. A single post from any of these celebrities can bring in millions of dollars for the brand.</p>
<p>Fashion Nova also encourages its Instagram followers to share photos of themselves wearing their clothes for a chance to be featured on the homepage of their <a href="https://branditechture.agency/recommends/shopify-theme/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Shopify-based</a> website. This function has proven to be really beneficial to them.</p>
<p>Also, it is recommended that a brand makes at least three posts per day to be relevant on Instagram; however, Fashion Nova, whose objective is to reach as many people as possible, posts at least <strong>30 times per day</strong>. This is how they ensure that every Instagram user on the planet sees a post from them at least once a day in their news feed.</p>
<p>Fashion Nova has been mentioned in the lyrics of songs by prominent rappers like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/6ix9ine" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">6ixnine </a>and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/21_Savage" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">21 Savage</a>, this has also made them more popular and successful in the fashion world.</p>
<p>Finally, they have amassed a mind-boggling 21.2 million Instagram followers and can get over 64,000 plays on each video in less than 10 hours. That is a whole lot of numbers which directly lead to sales.</p>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>“Does Fashion Nova Use Shopify?”</strong> Adebisiadewusi, 2 March 2022, https://adebisiadewusi.com/does-fashion-nova-use-shopify/. Accessed 8 May 2022.</li>
<li><strong>“Fashion Nova.”</strong> <a href="http://Wikipedia,/ https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fashion_Nova" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Wikipedia, https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fashion_Nova</a>. Accessed 8 May 2022.</li>
<li><strong>Nataly, Juanita:</strong> <strong>“How Fashion Nova became a leading fashion brand through its social media presence.”</strong> LinkedIn, 29 October 2019, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-fashion-nova-became-leading-brand-through-its-carballeira." target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-fashion-nova-became-leading-brand-through-its-carballeira.</a> Accessed 9 May 2022.</li>
</ol>
<div id="gtx-trans" style="position: absolute; left: -34px; top: 1292.36px;">
<div class="gtx-trans-icon"></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/">Why Fashion Nova was Built on Shopify</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Achieve Breakthrough in Your Online Business With These Three Easy Steps</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/breakthrough-in-your-online-business-with-these-three-easy-steps/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/breakthrough-in-your-online-business-with-these-three-easy-steps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natalia Bachmann]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[E-Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet online business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=14369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There is this common misconception that because internet marketing requires no prior experience, it is a simple profession. False! An online business endeavour works in the same manner as any business would do. Here are some pointers to help you to avoid the pitfalls of running an internet business. 1. Always Have A Plan Make [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/breakthrough-in-your-online-business-with-these-three-easy-steps/">Achieve Breakthrough in Your Online Business With These Three Easy Steps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is this common misconception that because internet marketing requires no prior experience, it is a simple profession.</p>
<p>False!</p>
<p>An online business endeavour works in the same manner as any business would do. Here are some pointers to help you to avoid the pitfalls of running an internet business.</p>
<h2>1. Always Have A Plan</h2>
<p>Make sure you have a plan in place at all times. How can you be successful in this type of business if you have no idea what you&#8217;re doing?</p>
<p>It would be really beneficial for you to find out where to begin before diving into the realm of internet marketing. Will you use the internet to offer items or services, or will you produce articles for various businesses? Being a master at any online business requires having a clear notion of what your next steps should be at any given time.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HAGnKEpMaW"><p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/common-internet-marketing-mistakes/">Common Internet Marketing Mistakes Business Owners Make</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Common Internet Marketing Mistakes Business Owners Make&#8221; &#8212; Branditechture" src="https://branditechture.agency/common-internet-marketing-mistakes/embed/#?secret=bFwWBfoD1c#?secret=HAGnKEpMaW" data-secret="HAGnKEpMaW" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<h2>2. Make Strategic Investments</h2>
<p>Make strategic investments in the most vital aspects of your online business. You may begin by <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lets-build-your-website/">creating your own website,</a> which you will be responsible for <a href="https://branditechture.agency/website-maintenance-plans/">maintaining</a>. If you already have one, the next step is to come up with <a href="https://branditechture.agency/20-content-generation-ideas-for-your-brands-marketing/">relevant articles</a> that will resonate with your target audience. Of course, once you&#8217;ve completed these two phases, you should continue to expand your research so that you can easily support your business going forward.</p>
<h2>3. Always Strive to Improve</h2>
<p>Finally, remember that you must always strive to improve. If your business does not go as planned the first time around, try again, but this time with more attention and initiative. Online commerce is a competitive field, and you&#8217;ll need to put in all of your efforts if you want to succeed.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/breakthrough-in-your-online-business-with-these-three-easy-steps/">Achieve Breakthrough in Your Online Business With These Three Easy Steps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/breakthrough-in-your-online-business-with-these-three-easy-steps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>8 ECommerce Website Design Practices That Will Help You Sell More</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/8-ecommerce-website-design-practices-that-will-help-you-sell-more/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/8-ecommerce-website-design-practices-that-will-help-you-sell-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natalia Bachmann]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[E-Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=14362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Every day, more businesses are migrating to the digital space. Both the seller and the buyer are now on the internet. With the rising demand for Ecommerce Web Development, there are a few things to consider before getting started! 1. Responsive Web Design The most important thing to remember when creating an eCommerce site is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/8-ecommerce-website-design-practices-that-will-help-you-sell-more/">8 ECommerce Website Design Practices That Will Help You Sell More</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every day, more businesses are migrating to the digital space. Both the seller and the buyer are now on the internet. With the rising demand for Ecommerce Web Development, there are a few things to consider before getting started!</p>
<h3>1. Responsive Web Design</h3>
<p>The most important thing to remember when creating an <a href="https://branditechture.agency/e-commerce-for-small-businesses/">eCommerce site</a> is to make it responsive. Because people are always on their phones, it&#8217;s critical to design your website in such a way that it&#8217;s easy for them to use on a mobile device.</p>
<div id="attachment_13289" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://branditechture.agency/e-commerce-for-small-businesses/"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13289" class="wp-image-13289 size-medium" title="Launch your ecommerce store " src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Launch-your-ecommerce-store-min-300x128.png" alt="Launch your ecommerce store min" width="300" height="128" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Launch-your-ecommerce-store-min-300x128.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Launch-your-ecommerce-store-min-1024x436.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Launch-your-ecommerce-store-min-768x327.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Launch-your-ecommerce-store-min-1536x655.png 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Launch-your-ecommerce-store-min-480x205.png 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Launch-your-ecommerce-store-min-1320x563.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-13289" class="wp-caption-text">Launch your ecommerce store. <a href="https://branditechture.agency/e-commerce-for-small-businesses/"><strong>Get Started &gt;&gt;</strong></a></p></div>
<h3>2. Easy Website Navigation</h3>
<p>To attract your target audience, your website should be appealing and attractive, but don&#8217;t overcomplicate it for the sake of aesthetics. If it&#8217;s too complicated, the user may become irritated and depart before even seeing your goods. Your website should be appealing to the eye while also being simple to use.</p>
<p>To keep things simple, your visitor should be able to get a clear and succinct picture of your company and product as soon as they arrive on your page. It should be straightforward and easy to find your stuff on your website. Avoid using jargon or terms that are too difficult to understand.</p>
<h3>3. Convincing Call to Action</h3>
<p>Your call to action buttons should be simple to use and find so that your visitors don&#8217;t feel as if they&#8217;ve wasted time looking for things they can&#8217;t even afford. Avoid needless adverts and call-to-action buttons that aren&#8217;t genuine. Help your visitors even more by providing a <a href="https://support.branditechture.agency/docs/what-does-the-live-chat-feature-mean/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">live chat</a> option or a designated area for them to submit their questions.</p>
<h3>4. Appealing Images</h3>
<p>&#8220;A picture is worth a thousand words,&#8221; as the saying goes. This is something you will have to adhere to religiously. Use high-resolution and clear images of your products; visitors want to know what they&#8217;re getting for their money. To make it more appealing and clear, use several strategies such as a 360-degree perspective. If as all possible, use product videos to increase your chances of selling.</p>
<h3>5. Highly Detailed Product Descriptions &amp; Specifications</h3>
<p>This is the most crucial factor that most newcomers overlook. Nobody is going to spend money on something they don&#8217;t understand. Attempt to respond to all pertinent questions and provide a detailed description of the product, including the material, quality, and any other characteristics that may affect the buying choice.</p>
<p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-build-a-unique-brand/">Promote</a> your product, but don&#8217;t go too far. You can also provide<a href="https://branditechture.agency/why-your-small-business-should-blog/"> product-related blogs</a> or videos. Add &#8220;items you might enjoy&#8221; or &#8220;similar products&#8221; to demonstrate that you have a diverse choice of products to sell and can meet customer needs.</p>
<h3>6. Reviews and Ratings</h3>
<p>It is quite rare for a customer to visit a website and purchase something without first conducting thorough research. Include a rating and review feature to boost your sales and improve your visitors&#8217; experience. It provides trust and confidence to your visitors that they might otherwise lack when visiting a new site. It establishes a trustworthy source for your consumers and significantly boosts your chances of making a deal.</p>
<h3>7. A Check-out Process That Is Both Efficient and Quick</h3>
<p>Customers despise having to go through a variety of pages to complete a transaction. If it&#8217;s unreasonably long and complicated, there&#8217;s a 99 per cent chance the buyer will change their mind halfway through.  Add guest check-out options, as well as quick payment flow and other check-out alternatives.</p>
<h3>8. Customization</h3>
<p>There are thousands of vendors offering the same items as you. It is now up to you to provide clients with that one critical factor that will influence their decision to choose you. Adding a personal touch to your website and giving it a distinctive appearance. Give your guests a unique experience by including your own custom features and making them feel special. Create a customised list and preference items based on the customer&#8217;s previous activities, such as &#8220;commonly bought together&#8221; or something similar.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>To summarise, everyone is online, but not everyone is successful. There are many people attempting to make it successful, but only a few are successful. To ensure optimum success, keep these ideas in mind when <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lets-build-your-website/">developing your website</a>.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Q8rhMYArWz"><p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/top-7-essential-elements-every-small-website-needs/">The Top 7 Essential Elements Every Small Website Needs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;The Top 7 Essential Elements Every Small Website Needs&#8221; &#8212; Branditechture" src="https://branditechture.agency/top-7-essential-elements-every-small-website-needs/embed/#?secret=B5V8BRsupO#?secret=Q8rhMYArWz" data-secret="Q8rhMYArWz" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/8-ecommerce-website-design-practices-that-will-help-you-sell-more/">8 ECommerce Website Design Practices That Will Help You Sell More</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/8-ecommerce-website-design-practices-that-will-help-you-sell-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
