<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Branding Tips &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/category/branding-tips/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 05:45:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Branding Tips &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Improve Your Social Media Brand&#8217;s Health With These 5 techniques</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/improve-your-social-media-brands-health-with-these-5-techniques/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/improve-your-social-media-brands-health-with-these-5-techniques/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mercy Saviour]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 05:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=16846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brand health is a metric that measures how customers perceive and interact with your company. So if you want to know how healthy your brand is, look no further than social media, where someone, somewhere, will be talking about it.  Mike Baglietto, global head of market insights at next-generation consumer analytics and market intelligence platform [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/improve-your-social-media-brands-health-with-these-5-techniques/">Improve Your Social Media Brand&#8217;s Health With These 5 techniques</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brand health is a metric that measures how customers perceive and interact with your company. So if you want to know how <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-secrets-to-building-and-sustaining-brand-equity/">healthy</a> your brand is, look no further than social media, where someone, somewhere, will be talking about it. </p>
<p><em>Mike Baglietto</em>, global head of market insights at next-generation consumer analytics and market intelligence platform <a href="https://branditechture.agency/marketing-tips/treating-your-customers-like-you-met-at-a-party-top-lead-conversion/">NetBase Quid,</a> describes social media as &#8220;the world&#8217;s largest focus group.&#8221; &#8220;You are not required to purchase a research report, you don&#8217;t have to do a survey. People on social media share anything and everything, and they&#8217;re pretty unfiltered, so you can find out exactly how people feel about your brand, competitors, and even your market. </p>
<p>However, there is a significant distinction between social media and any other focus group, big or small. Once you&#8217;ve found out how people perceive your brand, only social media also allows you to change that perception. </p>
<h3>Social media&#8217;s top trends</h3>
<p>Baglietto was one of the speakers on The Drum&#8217;s<em><strong> Consumer &amp; Market Intelligence in 2022: What&#8217;s Affecting Your Brand Health?</strong> </em>webinar, which was to be co-hosted by <em>NetBase Quid.</em> Baglietto, and his colleague Harvey Raola, NetBase Quid&#8217;s global head of media intelligence, discussed the following during the session: </p>
<ul class="gt3_styled_list">
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle"></i>This year&#8217;s <a href="https://branditechture.agency/heres-a-forecast-of-top-graphic-design-trends-for-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">top social media trends</a></li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle"></i>The mass adoption of augmented reality </li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle"></i>TikTok and Reddit&#8217;s increasing importance</li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle"></i>The need to create a baseline so you can track the health of your <a href="https://branditechture.agency/8-simple-business-branding-techniques-that-work-all-the-time/">brand over time</a>. </li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle"></i>How influencers and critics might be identified by <a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-create-and-manage-your-brand-architecture/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">brand managers</a></li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle"></i>The necessity to establish a baseline so you can track the health of your brand over time. </li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle"></i>Baglietto presented the key parameters that marketers could use to assess their brand&#8217;s health. </li>
</ul>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s the number of posts or mentions about my brand; how do customers feel about it, my net sentiment score; and how many people will really see it, my net potential impressions.&#8221; Then there&#8217;s the issue of how many people are writing those posts. </p>
<p>&#8220;Then we&#8217;ll look into where your audience is talking about your brand, and which social media platforms are hosting those conversations.&#8221; We&#8217;d also like to investigate the possibilities for your brand on such platforms.&#8221;</p>
<p>One of Baglietto&#8217;s key points was that different channels appeal to attract a different audiences. For example, the Tiktok audience is more female, whereas the Reddit audience is more male. Rather than creating &#8220;social media content&#8221; and pushing it out across all channels, marketers need to target their content by channel. </p>
<p>&#8220;The people who follow your brand on Twitter may not be the same people who follow your brand on TikTok or Instagram,&#8221; he explained. &#8220;So, in order to unlock additional income and  retention possibilities, you need to fully understand who that audience is.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Do not be concerned about the Kardashians. </h3>
<p>The other major topic for discussion was influencers and in particular micro-influencers. </p>
<p>&#8220;Micro-influencers &#8211; the folks with 5,000 to 25,000 followers on social media, generate a lot of potential for your brand and have the most impact,&#8221; Baglietto added. &#8220;They provide you the ability to connect with them in a genuine way.&#8221; It&#8217;s fantastic to have a Kardashian tweet about your company. But do customers really take action as a result? If I were an activewear brand, I would search for yoga instructors or personal trainers with a following. They&#8217;ll engage their target audience, and they&#8217;re true to the category and to my users.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, as Ranola pointed out, authenticity is a two-way street. When it came to interacting with Reddit groups, he emphasized the importance of striking a balance between knowledge and promotion. </p>
<p>&#8220;One of the things Reddit is known for is how brutally honest people are and how easily they can spot something that isn&#8217;t genuine,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Toeing the line of being able to provide value while remaining authentic is something that businesses must be very careful about.&#8221; I know this from a personal experience at a company I previously worked for, where we were a little bit too salesy and we got called out pretty quickly and banned from the Subreddit we were promoting.&#8221; </p>
<p>Baglietto concluded with a list of recommendations for marketers looking to monitor and improve the health of their brand:</p>
<ul class="gt3_styled_list">
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle" style="color: #81d742;"></i>At least once a month, evaluate your success with all of your important audiences across all of your main channels. </li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle" style="color: #81d742;"></i>Understand the types of <a href="https://branditechture.agency/the-importance-of-big-data-in-content-writing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">content that are most important</a> for each segment on each channel. </li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle" style="color: #81d742;"></i>Look for influencers who have the same personality as your company. </li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle" style="color: #81d742;"></i>In real-time, monitor the response to anything you and your team post, as well as what your influencers post. </li>
<li><i class="gt3_list__icon fa fa-check-circle" style="color: #81d742;"></i>Make any necessary course corrections. </li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/improve-your-social-media-brands-health-with-these-5-techniques/">Improve Your Social Media Brand&#8217;s Health With These 5 techniques</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/improve-your-social-media-brands-health-with-these-5-techniques/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Delivering on Your Brand Promise is Key to Your Brand&#8217;s Success</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/your-brand-promise-is-key-to-your-brands-success/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/your-brand-promise-is-key-to-your-brands-success/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=15181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So you&#8217;ve been working hard to grow your small business. You&#8217;ve centred your efforts around marketing. You&#8217;ve gone out there and posted on social media sites like Facebook, Instagram and Twitter. Your brand story and mission has been shared on all of your sales pages. You&#8217;ve started a blog. You&#8217;ve even produced articles and distributed [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/your-brand-promise-is-key-to-your-brands-success/">Delivering on Your Brand Promise is Key to Your Brand&#8217;s Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So you&#8217;ve been working hard to grow your small business. You&#8217;ve centred your efforts around <a href="https://branditechture.agency/8-proven-ways-to-market-your-business/">marketing</a>. You&#8217;ve gone out there and posted on social media sites like Facebook, Instagram and Twitter. Your brand story and mission has been shared on all of your sales pages. You&#8217;ve <a href="https://branditechture.agency/why-your-small-business-should-blog/">started a blog</a>. You&#8217;ve even <a href="https://branditechture.agency/20-content-generation-ideas-for-your-brands-marketing/">produced articles</a> and distributed them widely on the internet. You&#8217;ve lurked in forums and posted until you&#8217;ve been handed a ban. You&#8217;ve been working tirelessly to establish your brand.</p>
<p>&#8230;But there&#8217;s something you have forgotten</p>
<p>Marketing isn&#8217;t the most important component of brand success. Marketing is really about following through on your <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-secrets-to-building-and-sustaining-brand-equity/">promises</a>. It&#8217;s about providing your customers with those high-quality products and top-notch services that surpass their expectations. You have just published an irresistible copy, but can you make sure you are worth the hype?</p>
<p>And for those of us who create courses and other digital learning resources, this also means that <a href="https://www.productplan.com/learn/what-is-product-development/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">product development</a> is the most important aspect of our brand&#8217;s success. The majority of your quality will be built in — or left out — during product design and creation.</p>
<p>People pay attention to your branding efforts in the short run. Your marketing has a big role in how they perceive your quality. They consider your brand&#8217;s promises, both explicit and implicit, before making a decision. Your marketing will persuade them that you are an expert in your field. Also, that you will produce a high-quality output.</p>
<p>However, in the long run, people will judge you based on how successfully you follow through on your promises. They evaluate you based on the quality of your goods or service delivery. This would define the quality of the relationship they will form with you.</p>
<p>In the world of online marketing, building a long-term relationship with your customers is key to your brand&#8217;s success, and this is one of the reasons why creating a list is so important.</p>
<p>How you create and develop your products has the greatest impact on their overall quality.</p>
<h3>A Case Study</h3>
<p>In an effort to explain the relationship between delivering on your brand promises and your brand&#8217;s success, let&#8217;s take an educational content producer as a case study.</p>
<p><strong>There are three levels of quality in an educational content product:</strong></p>
<p>👉🏽 The first is the subject matter. This isn&#8217;t about your knowledge of the subject. It is about your knowledge of your consumers — your target audience. A huge percentage of these people will enrol in your course precisely because your marketing copy arouses their curiosity, and although unfamiliar with your brand, they are still curious enough to want to buy your course.</p>
<p>After buying and consuming the material, their assessments of the content&#8217;s quality would likely differ. This is what makes up what we popularly call <strong><em>reviews</em></strong>. No matter how good you are in your field,  you would occasionally get poor reviews.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_15585" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15585" class="size-full wp-image-15585" title="Customer submitting a review" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Customer-submitting-a-review.jpg" alt="Customer submitting a review" width="1024" height="583" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Customer-submitting-a-review.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Customer-submitting-a-review-300x171.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Customer-submitting-a-review-768x437.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Customer-submitting-a-review-480x273.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-15585" class="wp-caption-text">A customer submitting a review</p></div></p>
<p>Clients often evaluate your content based on how well it satisfies their requirements and expectations. Did you create the product to address a specific issue they&#8217;re experiencing? Did you create your product with their goals in mind? That is how they will assess the quality of your content.</p>
<p>👉🏽 The second criterion they will use to evaluate you is your organisational skills. Do you appear to have a good enough understanding of the subject to deliver it to them?  Do you offer your ideas in a logical manner? Do you employ an inclusive teaching style?</p>
<p>👉🏽 Finally, they will assess your performance depending on how well you deliver. Does it appear to be professional? What&#8217;s your spelling like? How is your grammar? Do you appear to be approachable and friendly?</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>You see, delivering high-quality content means carefully identifying and targeting your target audience. And you&#8217;ll use the same target consumer you identified during the product design and creation process for all of your customer interactions. This includes tailoring your marketing to your ideal customer. As a matter of fact, how well you deliver your brand promise would ultimately determine your brand&#8217;s success.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/your-brand-promise-is-key-to-your-brands-success/">Delivering on Your Brand Promise is Key to Your Brand&#8217;s Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/your-brand-promise-is-key-to-your-brands-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Underrated Habits That Can Grow Your Brand by 500%</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/habits-that-will-grow-your-brand/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/habits-that-will-grow-your-brand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=10261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Starting and managing a small business brand is no child&#8217;s play. Based on data seen on the US Bureau of Labor Statistics, around 20 percent of small businesses fail after their first year of launch, and around 50 percent fail by their fifth anniversary. Those are some horrific figures right there, but to save you from becoming [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/habits-that-will-grow-your-brand/">6 Underrated Habits That Can Grow Your Brand by 500%</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Starting and managing a small business brand is no child&#8217;s play. Based on data seen on the<a href="https://www.bls.gov/bdm/entrepreneurship/entrepreneurship.htm" class="extlink" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> US Bureau of Labor Statistics</a>, around 20 percent of small businesses fail after their first year of launch, and around 50 percent fail by their fifth anniversary.</p>
<p>Those are some horrific figures right there, but to save you from becoming a part of this horrible statistics, we have prepared 6 habits that successful brands employ to grow and sustain their brand.</p>
<p>You can implement all these right away to set yourself and your employees up for success.</p>
<h2>1. Taking Breaks</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taking breaks can lead to breakthroughs. When you just can&#8217;t figure it out and your mind gets stuck on the same problem, it&#8217;s best to take a break or do something completely different for a while. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While this might seem counterintuitive, t</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rying the same thing over and over again will lead to nothing but frustration. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are a few activities that can help:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clear out your inbox or answer a few emails</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Read a hardcover book or magazine</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clear out your desk or office</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take on a simple task</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ride a bicycle</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Play a mobile game like PUBG, Call of Duty, Asphalt or any simulation game on your mobile phone.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Watch an adrenaline-packed movie</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We conducted a two-month study comprising a group of five web developers who took regular breaks and another group of five web developers who had the habit of staying glued to their seat all day long. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The study revealed that the productivity and commitment to work increased for the first group of web developers. They were also able to find solutions to certain bugs faster than their counterparts who stuck to their screens all day long.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This also had a measurable impact on the company’s sales figures as they were able to complete their respective assignments as expected. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_10264" style="width: 606px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3028909-inline-googleofficeimg3.webp"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10264" class="wp-image-10264 size-full" title="Google Office In Zurich" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3028909-inline-googleofficeimg3.webp" alt="Google Office In Zurich" width="596" height="397" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3028909-inline-googleofficeimg3.webp 596w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3028909-inline-googleofficeimg3-300x200.webp 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/3028909-inline-googleofficeimg3-480x320.webp 480w" sizes="(max-width: 596px) 100vw, 596px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-10264" class="wp-caption-text">Google&#8217;s Office In Zurich. Image Credit: Fast Company.</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some companies and workplaces know this, hence the reason why you would normally see relaxation and recreation spots within the confinement of their workspaces.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So taking a break would not only improve focus and concentration, but would also provide the much needed room for a mental refresh. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After a break, work can resume with more energy and motivation. Working without taking one or more breaks would only result in mental and physical fatigue. It can even lead to low creativity levels and ultimately, burnout.</span></p>
<h2>2. Having an entrepreneurial mindset</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you are an employer or an employee, you’ll always have an image and a reputation to grow and sustain. Therefore, it’s safe to say that</span><a href="https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/"><b> you have a brand</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">To this end, there is always a need to think from the standpoint of an entrepreneur.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The entrepreneurial mindset is a special one: It is a way of thinking that enables you to overcome challenges associated with both work and life. It also enables you to differentiate between activities that strengthen your brand from ones that can potentially cause harm or retrogression to your brand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can’t afford to be indecisive. You must also learn to accept responsibility for your outcomes. It is a constant need to improve your skills, learn from your mistakes, and make better decisions. Anyone with a job can develop an entrepreneurial mindset.</span></p>
<pre><strong>ALSO READ:</strong><a href="https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8 Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding</a></pre>
<h2>3. Buying and examining your competitor’s products or services</h2>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-10266 size-full" title="Entrepreneur Examining A Product" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Entrepreneur-Examining-A-Product.jpg" alt="Entrepreneur Examining A Product" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Entrepreneur-Examining-A-Product.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Entrepreneur-Examining-A-Product-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Entrepreneur-Examining-A-Product-768x432.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Entrepreneur-Examining-A-Product-480x270.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buying and Examining your competitor’s products and services is one step closer to getting firsthand information on what competitive advantages your competitors may have over your brand. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are other good reasons to buy from your competitors;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You will get the much needed insights into making your products, services and marketing strategy stand out. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It will enable you to set your prices more competitively. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You will be in a better position to respond to rival marketing campaigns with your own initiatives.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It equips you with the knowledge required to create marketing strategies that take advantage of your competitors&#8217; weaknesses, and improve your own overall business performance. </span></li>
</ul>
<h2>4. Hiring an accounting and bookkeeping expert or company</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your decision to hire a bookkeeper should depend on what stage of growth your business has reached and how comfortable you are doing your own bookkeeping. There&#8217;s no doubt, however, that hiring a bookkeeper comes with a lot of advantages to your business. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Should you hire a bookkeeper? Here are a few reasons why you should;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You get fully detailed financial information about your business.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You gain the potential to incur less in taxes through proper financial advice.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ll free up some valuable time for yourself.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It will help you to measure your business financial performance at a glance</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Helps make external (e.g government) audits much easier and stream-lined. </span></li>
</ul>
<h2>5. Outsourcing the things you aren’t really skilled at</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What Is Outsourcing? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Outsourcing is the business practice of hiring a party outside a company to perform services that are typically beyond the scope of the company&#8217;s in-house staff.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Outsourcing tasks to the right company can help you reduce and control overhead operating costs and improve your inhouse employees’ focus. Outsourcing also provides the opportunity to expand your company’s talent pool. By outsourcing, you are also sharing liability risks with another company. </span></p>
<h2>6. Aiming for on-time delivery</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Logistics, Consultancy, Graphic Design, Website Design — No matter what type of business you operate, the importance of on-time delivery cannot be over-emphasized. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On-time delivery breeds consumer dependability and trust. Unfortunately, timely delivery may clash with the </span><b>quality of delivery</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is because quality assessments also need time, this is often not factored when giving ETA. So you might often be faced with the dilemma of choosing between delivering a project on time, and delivering a more quality version a little bit late. However, it&#8217;s always a good idea to strive for a balance.</span></p>
<pre><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>TIP:</strong> When giving an ETA for a project, always consider the time it would take for quality assessments.</span></pre>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">ETA stands for </span><b>Estimated Time of Arrival</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It is a broadly used industry standard term in the logistics and transportation industry, but in the world of project management, it is often used to refer to an estimated due date of a project. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/habits-that-will-grow-your-brand/">6 Underrated Habits That Can Grow Your Brand by 500%</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/habits-that-will-grow-your-brand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>8 Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathaniel Ajayi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=7955#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=7955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hello there :), I&#8217;m sure you must have heard a lot about branding and brand identity by now, eh? For ages, businesses have used branding to give their products and services a unique identification and feel. This process may involve having a specified name, symbol or even an image or mascot that acts as a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/">8 Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello there :), I&#8217;m sure you must have heard a lot about <strong>branding</strong> and <strong>brand identity</strong> by now, eh?</p>
<p>For ages, businesses have used <strong>branding</strong> to give their products and services a unique identification and feel.</p>
<p>This process may involve having a specified name, symbol or even an image or mascot that acts as a unique identifier.</p>
<p><strong>You May Want To Read: <a href="https://branditechture.agency/top-6-factors-to-consider-when-naming-a-brand/" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="noopener">Naming A Brand — Top 6 Factors To Consider</a></strong></p>
<p>Ever wondered how investing in effective branding can turn your small business around and for the better?</p>
<p>Here are some ways we&#8217;ve outlined for you:</p>
<h2>1. Branding &#8211; All About Identity</h2>
<p>You know how people always remember what brand of soap, washing powder and chips they like best? And repeatedly purchase them afterwards?</p>
<p>What if those products were brandless? That would make repeated purchases extremely difficult or almost impossible.</p>
<p>Branding solves this problem by making you a recognized force in the market. To a large extent, branding also helps to protect your product from counterfeiting.</p>
<h2>2. Familiarity</h2>
<p>Branding helps you identify, target and effectively connect to your audience at a deeper level.</p>
<p>It helps to make your product associate itself with a particular market segment.</p>
<p>Keeping consistent branding techniques also fosters assurance in your standard of quality.</p>
<h2>3. Identity</h2>
<p>You, should not put the loyalty of your audience to test by staying brandless, as this leaves more room for others to impersonate your particular catalogue and sell off products of inferior quality by being unreasonably as close to your products as possible.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-8392" title="Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/8-Ways-Your-Small-Business-Can-Benefit-From-Branding.jpg" alt="Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/8-Ways-Your-Small-Business-Can-Benefit-From-Branding.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/8-Ways-Your-Small-Business-Can-Benefit-From-Branding-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/8-Ways-Your-Small-Business-Can-Benefit-From-Branding-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/8-Ways-Your-Small-Business-Can-Benefit-From-Branding-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Should you decide to stay brandless, it is going to remain difficult for your customers to tell whether or not &#8220;your&#8221; product is from an authorized source.</p>
<p>And since counterfeit products may cause harm or bodily injuries to consumers, you could land yourself a legal problem that may cost you thousands of dollars and your entire business.</p>
<h2>4. Attractiveness</h2>
<p>The word &#8216;attractiveness&#8217; is defined by the Oxford Dictionary as &#8220;the quality of being pleasing or appealing to the senses&#8221;.</p>
<p>This word may have a lot of implications, but in this instance, it refers to making your target audience market not only accept your brand but also find it appealing altogether.</p>
<p>Some customers go to great lengths to avoid brands that look too shabby or grotesque.</p>
<p>A brand slogan should use unique, fancy and catchy words that are common and also colloquial to your audience.</p>
<p>Images and symbols should use alluring designs and colourations that not only look good but psychologically compel consumer action.</p>
<h2>5. Uniqueness</h2>
<p>Every human being on the face of the earth most probably have a name or means of identification to go by.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8390" style="width: 1116px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8390" class=".wp-image-7808 wp-image-8390 size-full" title="Cocacola Brands" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Cocacola-Brands.jpg" alt="Cocacola Brands" width="1106" height="674" /><p id="caption-attachment-8390" class="wp-caption-text">Cocacola Brands</p></div></p>
<p>Products and even services should have unique identifiers to enable them to be noticed as a singularity in their target market. Noticeably, manufacturers with a large catalogue of similar products <a href="https://www.coca-colacompany.com/brands/coca-cola" class="extlink" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="noopener">e.g. Coca-Cola, still have different brands of the same product with each distinguished factors e.g. Coca-Cola Original, Coca-Cola Zero, Coca-Cola Vanilla, Diet Coke, Coca-Cola Life.</a></p>
<h2>6. Information</h2>
<p>Branding and packaging give you a means of adding personal information, notice messages and even advertisement for related products.</p>
<p>You can add self-service instructions and your contact information to assist customers who struggle with using your product.</p>
<p><strong>Read More: <a target="_blank" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-build-a-unique-brand-in-2021/" title="Branding in 2021 — How to Build a Unique Brand" rel="noopener">Branding in 2021 — How to Build a Unique Brand</a></strong></p>
<h2>7. Loyalty</h2>
<p>When customers are used to getting quality from a particular brand and are assured of committed after-sales support, they definitely find that product reliable and this creates <strong>brand loyalty</strong>.</p>
<p>According to <em>Skyword.com, </em><strong>brand loyalty </strong>is the tendency of consumers to continuously purchase one brand&#8217;s products over another.</p>
<p>Consumer behaviour patterns demonstrate that consumers will continue to buy products from a company that has fostered a trusting relationship&#8221;.</p>
<h2>8. Revenue</h2>
<p>I deliberately saved the best for last!</p>
<p>Yes, creating a recognized brand takes time, effort and a reasonable amount of resources.</p>
<p>Some entrepreneurs may believe that branding is unnecessary, as it ultimately doesn&#8217;t affect the overall quality of a product.</p>
<p>While this may be true to some extent, it is an obvious fallacy as <a class="extlink" href="https://sproutsocial.com/insights/data/social-media-connection/" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="noopener">research has proved that customers would stick with a brand they can identify and have a relationship with</a>.</p>
<p>This builds up to enable more repeated and bulk purchases and depending on the niche of the brand, impulsive buying.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/">8 Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Create and Manage Your Brand Architecture</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/how-to-create-and-manage-your-brand-architecture/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/how-to-create-and-manage-your-brand-architecture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dick David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand architecture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=8443#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=8443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Understanding, choosing, and implementing a Brand Architecture for your company is one of those hard things you have to do to make every other thing easier. And yes, creating and managing a brand architecture is very hard (and that is why we wrote this article.) Creating and managing a brand isn’t difficult because it involves [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-create-and-manage-your-brand-architecture/">How to Create and Manage Your Brand Architecture</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Understanding, choosing, and implementing a Brand Architecture for your company is one of those hard things you have to do to make every other thing easier. And yes, creating and managing a brand architecture is very hard (and that is why we wrote this article.)</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Creating and managing a brand isn’t difficult because it involves creating something convoluted, but because it involves simplifying something very complex.</span></p>
<h2><span data-preserver-spaces="true">What is Brand Architecture?</span></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In simple terms, it is about what and how a company chooses to brand itself – how they chose to organize and present themselves. Brand Architecture refers to the way a company organizes its teams, divisions, products, services, and subsidiaries. It is the way a company chose to execute its brand strategy. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">And while this sounds simple on the surface, it can drive one batty – especially when the organization is <a class="extlink" href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-Blitzscaling" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="nofollow noopener">blitz-scaling.</a> or already big. But this doesn’t mean a small business should ignore brand architecture, no. Brand architecture is essentially the “engine fine-tuning” of a business, and the earlier you get it right, the better for everyone.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This is because, brand architecture doesn’t just streamline work within the organizations, but it also brings about other advantages</span></p>
<h2><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Advantages Of Brand Architecture</span></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Having a good brand architecture…</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Helps customers understand and enjoy patronizing the business. Too many subdivisions and offerings can confuse the customers and drastically reduce sales</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Short-circuits unhealthy competition within sectors of the same company (hence eliminating <a class="extlink" href="https://www.ictshore.com/project-management/duplication-of-effort/" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="nofollow noopener">effort duplication</a>)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Boosts employee’s productivity since their tasks are streamlined</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Make recruitment of talents much more intentional, purposeful and easier (both for the company and the talent being recruited)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Increases revenue through cross-selling</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Grows<a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-a-brand-ambassador-can-help-grow-your-company/" data-schema-attribute=""> brand awareness</a> through cross-promotion</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Reassures investors, and partners (as they can easily understand where their investments are going into)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Gives the media the correct perception of the organization</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Optimizes the company’s <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-secrets-to-building-and-sustaining-brand-equity/">equity</a> and portfolio (which can be good for getting funding’s and other evaluations)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Helps the company to focus (on specific goods and services), thereby bringing clarity</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Encourages <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/k/kaizen.asp" class="extlink" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kaizen </a></span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Differentiates the company from its competitors – which reduces competition as well</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Brings about faster growth</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Outlines the company’s goals and values, which also aids in crafting a clear message</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> And most importantly, drastically reduces the cost of running the company (as money is put into only the right things, in the right way).</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Creating a Brand Architecture sounds like the “magic fairy dust” that makes all your company’s dreams come through, and that’s because it is. There is no successful organization that hasn’t taken the time to organize its affairs. In fact, the cliché goes “<a href="https://branditechture.agency/27-causes-of-brand-failure/" data-schema-attribute="">People don’t fail, systems do</a>”.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">As pointed out earlier, “simplicity” is the key. However, this doesn’t mean you have to shed off important parts of the company, no. What it means is that you need to create synergy between them.</span></p>
<p>Read Also:</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">You must approach Brand Architecture the way you approach the task of building a “house of cards”. Everything needs to be considered, yet put in the right place. And, just like a house of cards, if you remove one aspect the whole deck would come crashing down.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">What this means is that you also need to be comprehensive when simplifying things. It shouldn’t be so simple that it loses its value and effectiveness. If you want a car to go faster, you would want to reduce the weight, but that doesn’t mean you should remove the engines or tires. You just have to optimize them.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">That said, below are the basic architectures your company can adopt;</span></p>
<h2><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Types Of Brand Architectures</span></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">A lot of factors come to play when picking a brand architecture to adopt (and would be discussed in the next section of this post), but below are the fundamental brand architectures a company can adopt:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Monolithic (Branded House)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Pluralistic (House of Brands)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Endorsed</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Hybrid</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Monolithic</span></h3>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The monolithic or Branded house architecture involves organizing several divisions, features, offers, and brands under a single Master brand. This means every sector of the company (no matter how distinguished) serves to promote a single name – the master brand.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_8727" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8727" class="size-full wp-image-8727" title="brand architecture fedex branded house monolithic" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brand-architecture-fedex-branded-house-monolithic.jpg" alt="brand architecture fedex branded house monolithic" width="1024" height="467" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brand-architecture-fedex-branded-house-monolithic.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brand-architecture-fedex-branded-house-monolithic-300x137.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brand-architecture-fedex-branded-house-monolithic-768x350.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brand-architecture-fedex-branded-house-monolithic-480x219.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8727" class="wp-caption-text">FedEx Brands <span>—</span> Monolithic (or House of Brands)</p></div></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The advantage of this brand architecture is that it</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Inspires customer loyalty: As they come to enjoy a wide gamut of goods and services under one roof</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Reduces the cost of marketing: Since all efforts and resource are put into promoting a single brand, and</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Improves <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-secrets-to-building-and-sustaining-brand-equity" data-schema-attribute="">brand equity</a></span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Examples of prominent companies which employ this architecture include;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> FedEx:</strong> FedEx Express, FedEx Freight, FedEx Services, etcetera.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Virgin:</strong> Virgin Mobile, Virgin Records, Virgin Media</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> GE:</strong> GE Capital, GE Healthcare, General Electric, etcetera.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Pluralistic</span></h3>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The Pluralistic or House of Brands architecture is a form of decentralized system where each division functions independently though “owned” by one brand.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">By nature, this architecture is more complicated, costly, and harder to run. The major benefits this form of brand architecture has is that </span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> It helps companies/brands that are not compatible (based on their offerings) to still unite, and</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> It helps individual brands focus (and niche down) on a particular market (without being distracted)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8726" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8726" class="size-large wp-image-8726" title="Coca Cola Brands min min" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Coca-Cola-Brands-min-min-991x1024.png" alt="Coca Cola Brands min min" width="940" height="971" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Coca-Cola-Brands-min-min-991x1024.png 991w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Coca-Cola-Brands-min-min-290x300.png 290w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Coca-Cola-Brands-min-min-768x793.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Coca-Cola-Brands-min-min-480x496.png 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Coca-Cola-Brands-min-min.png 1002w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8726" class="wp-caption-text">Coca Cola Brands Pluralistic Brands (or House of Brands)</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Some brands which employ this architecture include</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Coca-Cola:</strong> Coke, Sprite, Powerade, Fanta, etc.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Unilever:</strong> Dove, Ben &amp; Jerry’s, Lipton</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Procter &amp; Gamble:</strong> Tide, Gillette, Old Spice</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Endorsed </span></h3>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Similar to the pluralistic architecture, individual brands still maintain their identity but are (as the name suggests) endorsed by a parent brand. Unlike the pluralistic architecture, the parent brand may choose to remain anonymous – and only known by investors.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The benefit of this architecture is that</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Subdivisions can benefit from the equity of the parent brand</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The credibility of the main brand is also transferred to the newer subdivisions</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Examples of companies that employ this model include</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Apple:</strong> Shazam, Siri, iPhone, Mac</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Facebook:</strong> Instagram, WhatsApp, Oculus </span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Nestle:</strong> Cheerios, Nesquik, KitKat</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Hybrid </span></h3>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Consider this a brand architecture &#8220;chimera&#8221;. It is a combination of several brand architectures into one mega-brand architecture. It could be any combination of the Monolithic, Pluralistic, and Endorsed brands.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This is the most complex form of brand architecture to adopt. It is usually adopted by organizations that have grown very large (either by expansion, mergers, or acquisitions). </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8729" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8729" class="wp-image-8729 size-large" title="Amazon Hybrid Brand Architecture" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture-1024x576.jpeg" alt="Amazon Hybrid Brand Architecture" width="940" height="529" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture-768x432.jpeg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture-1536x864.jpeg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture-480x270.jpeg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture-1320x743.jpeg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amazon-Hybrid-Brand-Architechture.jpeg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8729" class="wp-caption-text">Amazon Hybrid Brand Architecture</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The major advantages of this architecture are;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> It allows the brand to grow very fast and wide (dominating several markets), and</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Allows the coexistence of new, old, and diverse products.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Some popular brands that have been able to pull off this form of brand architecture include</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Alphabet:</strong> Google (YouTube, Gmail, Drive, Hangout, etcetera), Waymo, Android, etcetera</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Amazon:</strong> Amazon Echo, Amazon Kindle, Amazon AWS, Prime Video, Audible. etcetera</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong> Microsoft:</strong> Xbox, Skype, Microsoft Windows, etcetera.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Now that you know the buffet of choices available to you, the next step is to get pragmatic.</span></p>
<h2><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Key Steps To Creating Your Brand Architecture</span></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">As your company grows and expands (especially when it acquires other products, or merge with other companies) the cost of creating, branding, marketing, and legal implications multiply almost exponentially. This is why creating a robust Brand Architecture to handle this shock, and even transform the colossal nature of the brand into a juggernaut, is crucial. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">When creating or deciding on a Brand Architecture to adopt, you should first consider</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Your long term goals</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> Your chances of winning with the strategy</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The possibility of it increasing your profits, and</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The amount of leverage it (the Brand Architecture) gives you</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">After which you can then take these 3 major steps to start creating the chosen architecture: </span></p>
<ul>
<li>Research,</li>
<li>Strategy, and</li>
<li>Migration</li>
</ul>
<h3><span data-preserver-spaces="true">1. Research: </span></h3>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Before you start building anything, you need to first understand what the customers want. You need to find out how they perceive your brand – how aware and loyal they are. You also need to know what offer of yours they are most interested in. This would help you know what to focus on – improve or add.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This phase includes qualitative research, quantitative research, brand equity studies, and audits. No stone should be left unturned. The company needs to thoroughly understand </span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> How the different sections within the organization are interacting with each other (i.e. consider your brand&#8217;s strengths and weaknesses)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The nature of the brand’s portfolio</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> How they are currently serving the customers</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Customers&#8217; opinions and perceptions of its services/goods (i.e. consider how and where you can improve)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> What the customers wish for (i.e. find out what your organization can add)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> What its competitors are doing better</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> And so on.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This phase involves carrying out surveys and calling for meetings to discuss with all subsidiaries. It is perhaps the most important phase of creating the brand architecture. And, depending on the size and nature of the company, this task can be easy or gruelling – but is worth being clinical about nonetheless.</span></p>
<h3><span data-preserver-spaces="true">2. Strategy:</span></h3>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">After having a thorough understanding of the market&#8217;s needs, and the company’s strengths, you can then go on to decide what architecture would give you the most <a class="extlink" href="https://www.tonyrobbins.com/career-business/the-power-of-leverage/" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="nofollow noopener">leverage</a> (based on what you have and want to achieve.)</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This phase involves deciding how the brands and offerings should be presented, how much they are to be cross-referenced, promoted, or kept independent.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This phase also requires making decisions on how the resources (money, manpower, connections, etcetera) are to be spent.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Once these decisions are made, the next phase is initiated…</span></p>
<h3><span data-preserver-spaces="true">3. Migration:</span></h3>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This is the part where you name and assign responsibilities to the sub-brands. For this to work out, all divisions/subsidiaries need to agree with the decision made so as to create synergy. In essence, this is when you develop, announce, and implement the<a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-align-your-brand-with-your-brand-strategy" data-schema-attribute=""> blueprint for the organization</a></span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This blueprint clearly states…</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The role of each subsidiary (brand, or sub-brand)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The market of each brand (demographics, and offers)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The nature of affiliation with the master brand</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The positioning and presentation of each brand, and </span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> A clear system, and hierarchy – for making decisions – within the organization</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">With all these in place – fully supported and understood by all – the agreed-upon architecture can be implemented right away. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">But the job doesn’t end there…</span></p>
<h2><span data-preserver-spaces="true">How to manage Brand Architecture</span></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Once the brand architecture has been decided and implemented, the next task to be carried out is the management of that framework.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The task is a continuous and dynamic one, hence, it cannot be summarized. However, there are a few general things that must be kept in constant check, else the whole Brand Architecture would crumble. They are…</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The Rules: The demands, boundaries, rights, and limits of each subsidiary must be clearly stated and communicated. This information should also be dispensed to each employee and third parties.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The Workflow: The responsibilities of each part of the company should be clearly stated. This would allow for more productivity, collaboration, and fewer issues or effort duplication. Each part of the architecture must be able to play its part irrespective and independent of the other.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The Assets: The brand assets should be properly used, taken care of, and protected. This involves brand equity, recognition, and loyalty. It is also good practice to centralize the brand assets – which aids accessibility and transparency.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The Promotion: Promotion/marketing should be a top priority for any brand because lack of visibility equals lack of existence, which translates to no sales and ultimate collapse of the structure. The<a href="https://branditechture.agency/content-ideas-for-your-content-marketing/" data-schema-attribute=""> promotion</a> also helps the brand build authority and improves its relevance to the market.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The Customers: The brand should also be sensitive to what the customers are saying about it. Your Brand Architecture should be robust yet flexible. It sounds contradictory, but it isn’t. It simply means the company should be willing to reassess their decisions based on customer reactions because they are the reason the structure exists in the first place.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> The Profitability: Finally, the company should ensure that profits are being maximized. If the new Brand Architecture is too costly to maintain, then something is terribly wrong somewhere, and you should return to the drawing boards.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The golden rule for creating a Brand Architecture is that it must make the customers more willing to buy whilst reducing the difficulty the company faces in seeing that happen. Simply put, it must drive sales up (hopefully to stratospheric heights), whilst reducing friction within your organization(s).</span></p>
<hr />
<p>Are you in need of a one-on-one brand strategy/brainstorming session? Schedule a meeting by first <a href="https://branditechture.agency/contact/" data-schema-attribute=""><em><strong>contacting us.</strong></em></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-create-and-manage-your-brand-architecture/">How to Create and Manage Your Brand Architecture</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/how-to-create-and-manage-your-brand-architecture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Elon Teaches Us About Brand Naming</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/what-elon-teaches-us-about-branding/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/what-elon-teaches-us-about-branding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=8594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Elon, in fact, was nowhere near Mark Zuckerberg a couple of years back, but he did see a meteoric rise in his net worth over the past few years. But still, Elon doesn&#8217;t really care about these things. In his words: &#8220;I really couldn&#8217;t care less. These numbers rise and fall but what really matters [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-elon-teaches-us-about-branding/">What Elon Teaches Us About Brand Naming</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon, in fact, was nowhere near Mark Zuckerberg a couple of years back, but he did see a meteoric rise in his net worth over the past few years. But still, Elon doesn&#8217;t really care about these things. In his words: <strong>&#8220;I really couldn&#8217;t care less. These numbers rise and fall but what really matters is <em>making products</em> that people love&#8221;.  </strong>But there&#8217;s always one thing that strikes different about Elon&#8217;s products — their brand names. As any &#8220;<span class="gt3_custom_tooltip" data-gt3-tooltip="Public Relations">PR</span>-conscious&#8221; business person would advise, the first thing your brand needs is a catchy name.</p>
<p>Africans, most notably, South Africans, love to claim Elon Musk as one of their own people. After all, he was birthed in Pretoria, a capital city in South Africa. He even schooled in South Africa, so most Africans seem not to <em><strong>give a hoot</strong></em> if Elon made his goodwill and fortune in the United States of America.</p>
<p>With a net worth of 147 Billion US Dollars ($147bn), Elon is now filthy rich (and over 12 times richer than the richest man in the whole of Africa, who currently stands at $11.7bn as of May 2021, according to <strong>Forbes</strong>).</p>
<p>Absolutely, business is all about delivering products or services that people love, but how does one give an identity to these products or services? How do you brand them? How or where do you find the inspiration for a suitable brand name?</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s learn some lessons from Elon.</h2>
<p>On the 31st March 2017,  <em>The Economist</em>, an international newspaper agency published an article titled <a class="extlink" href="https://www.economist.com/1843/2017/03/31/the-novelist-who-inspired-elon-musk" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-schema-attribute=""><strong>&#8220;The novelist who inspired Elon Musk&#8221;</strong></a>. The article gave an intriguing insight as to where Elon sources his brand names from:</p>
<p>&#8220;Not satisfied with reusable rockets, electric cars, giant batteries, vacuum trains and underground roads, his latest firm, <strong>Neuralink</strong>, hopes one day to build a working brain-machine interface (BMI), which would let its user control computers simply by thinking. The idea is not new – scientists have been experimenting with BMIs in labs for years – but Musk’s involvement will sprinkle it with stardust.&#8221;</p>
<p>It carried on: &#8220;As any entrepreneur will tell you, <span class="gt3_highlighter">the first thing your product needs is a catchy name</span><span class="gt3_highlighter">.</span> &#8220;Brain-machine interface&#8221; is a bit clunky, so Musk has plumped instead for neural lace, which is short, memorable and glamorous. Science fiction fans will recognise it from the &#8216;Culture&#8217; novels of Iain M. Banks, a Scottish writer who died in 2013.&#8221;</p>
<p>So, it is safe to conclude that one vital source of Elon Musk&#8217;s brand names is<span class="gt3_highlighter" style="background-color: #eeee22;"> science fiction!</span></p>
<p>Another likely source is <span class="gt3_highlighter" style="background-color: #eeee22;">scientific facts.</span> According to a report published in <em>The Independent</em> on the 2nd of December 2019, Elon, being an industrial designer, was &#8220;desperate&#8221; for the name, <strong>Tesla</strong>, because it happens to be the name of an inventor that he apparently has so much respect for — <strong>Nikola Tesla. </strong></p>
<p>But, as many entrepreneurs can relate, the name he wanted had already been taken.</p>
<p>Elon did something that many can&#8217;t; he bought it. He paid the original owner some $ 75 000, in 2014.</p>
<p>Consequentially, he needed and of course, wanted the <strong>.com</strong> TLD for Tesla too. But that proved to be far more of a challenge – It took longer for Tesla to acquire the rights to use the domain name <strong>Tesla.com</strong> than it took to design, build and sell its first car!</p>
<p>It took some 11 million US dollars ($11m) and almost 10 years of negotiation to finally convince Silicon Valley engineer, Stuart Grossman to sell him the rights to Tesla.com. The company had been using TeslaMotors.com, but Elon has always had a broader vision than Tesla being just a car company, which explains his keen desire to acquire the more simple domain name, Tesla.com.</p>
<p><iframe title="Third Row Tesla Podcast – Elon&#039;s Story – Part 1" width="940" height="529" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NxmO_QuD4Do?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&#8220;That took us 10 years to buy that Tesla.com domain,&#8221; Musk said on the <a class="extlink" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NxmO_QuD4Do&amp;feature=youtu.be" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Third Row Tesla Podcast</a>. &#8220;That cost us like, $10 million.&#8221;</p>
<p>Musk had earlier taken to Twitter in 2018 to inform us that it actually cost him $11 million, plus an &#8220;amazing amount of effort,&#8221; to get the domain name off Grossman.</p>
<p>It was said that if Elon had failed to acquire the rights to Tesla, he would&#8217;ve chosen Faraday, which is also the name of an inventor.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8597" style="width: 985px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8597" class="size-full wp-image-8597" title="Tesla Motor" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Tesla-Motor.jpg" alt="Tesla Motor" width="975" height="650" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Tesla-Motor.jpg 975w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Tesla-Motor-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Tesla-Motor-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Tesla-Motor-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 975px) 100vw, 975px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8597" class="wp-caption-text">Tesla Motors Logo</p></div></p>
<p>So, is it all just a matter of going with a catchy name? Well, remember our last discussion on the <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lessons-to-learn-from-lil-nas-xs-satan-shoes-saga/">Lil Nas X and MSCHF vs Nike Saga?</a>  We learnt some branding lessons which certainly raised our awareness on trademarking your intellectual property (or IP) so you can have enforceable rights to it.</p>
<p>We also talked about the need to keep your IP as unique as possible in order to avoid any &#8220;<strong>likelihood of confusion&#8221;</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Read Also: <a href="https://branditechture.agency/top-6-factors-to-consider-when-naming-a-brand/" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="noopener">Naming A Brand — Top 6 Factors To Consider</a> </strong></p>
<p>For a trademark to be eligible for registration, <a href="https://branditechture.agency/top-6-factors-to-consider-when-naming-a-brand/">the name must be peculiar</a>, or as the law tends to put it, capable of distinguishing the product or service offerings of one brand from that of another. But how distinctive is distinctive enough?</p>
<p>A brand name can either be naturally or inherently distinctive, or it can become distinctive of a brand&#8217;s offerings via considerable levels of usage (or LoU).</p>
<p>This generally excludes words that are generic, overly obvious and descriptive of the brand.</p>
<p>It excludes words that are flattering or overhype the product. It excludes important geographical names like Nassau, Macau, Barbados e.t.c. It also excludes a very huge percentage of personal names we have today.</p>
<p>But made-up words are so good. So are existing words used out of context. Obscure arcane references can also work, as with words from ancient languages.</p>
<p>The most important thing is that the name must, of course, also be available.</p>
<p>No matter how distinguished you think it is, chances are it may already have been registered by someone else, or perhaps, something similar to that may have been registered. This is where a trademark database query is required.</p>
<p>That is where we come in. <a href="https://branditechture.agency/contact/" data-schema-attribute="">Branditechture</a> can help with this.</p>
<p>Yes, I told you in the previous paragraph that personal names are very unlikely to work as trademarks. Well, there are exceptions to every rule, and once again Elon Musk is one.</p>
<p>Admittedly, Elon is a very rare name and it&#8217;s reasonably safe to say that it&#8217;s now automatically connected with one person. (Which is why I didn&#8217;t need to write his full name in the title before you knew who this article was about).</p>
<p>You can&#8217;t say the same with popular names like Mark, John, Doe, Mary, Jane, Bill, or Jeff.</p>
<p>Elon, being a futuristic thinker, appears to have made sure that his son bears a name that will easily work out as a trademark. Beyonce and Jay-Z also did the same thing when they named their daughter Blue Ivy.</p>
<p>In the case of Elon&#8217;s son, you&#8217;d agree with me that his name is better read silently than pronounced. Just for the record, Elon&#8217;s son is named: <strong>X Æ A-12</strong> which rather seems more to me like he&#8217;s showing off his naming skills.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8598" style="width: 950px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8598" class="size-large wp-image-8598" title="Elon Musks Naming Skills Elon Musks Son" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Elon-Musks-Naming-Skills-Elon-Musks-Son-1024x768.jpg" alt="Elon Musks Naming Skills Elon Musks Son" width="940" height="705" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Elon-Musks-Naming-Skills-Elon-Musks-Son-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Elon-Musks-Naming-Skills-Elon-Musks-Son-300x225.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Elon-Musks-Naming-Skills-Elon-Musks-Son-768x576.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Elon-Musks-Naming-Skills-Elon-Musks-Son-480x360.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Elon-Musks-Naming-Skills-Elon-Musks-Son.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8598" class="wp-caption-text">Elon Musk and Son, X Æ A-12.</p></div></p>
<hr />
<p>Need Brand Naming services? Select <strong>Brand Naming <a href="https://branditechture.agency/start-a-project/">HERE</a></strong> and we&#8217;ll get on a virtual meeting with you as scheduled.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-elon-teaches-us-about-branding/">What Elon Teaches Us About Brand Naming</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/what-elon-teaches-us-about-branding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Personal Brand or Corporate Brand; How To Choose.</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chisom Nnachi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=8197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coming to a final decision of how to professionally present oneself to the world can prove to be a confusing task. You certainly have multiple questions running through your mind and seeking clear answers; Should I have a personal brand? Do I need a personal brand? What’s the difference between a personal brand and a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/">Personal Brand or Corporate Brand; How To Choose.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coming to a final decision of how to professionally present oneself to the world can prove to be a confusing task. <span style="font-weight: 400;">You certainly have multiple questions running through your mind and seeking clear answers; Should I have a personal brand? Do I need a personal brand? What’s the difference between a personal brand and a corporate brand?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Until these questions are properly addressed, you will continue to find it difficult to define your public identity.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most individuals believe that a corporate brand works better than a personal brand and you must keep your identity off your business. This makes it hard to decide which one to choose.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the long argument of <strong>personal brand vs corporate brand</strong> boils down to which type of branding works well for your future marketing plans and structure.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This article is carefully curated to offer you a detailed guideline on setting up your brand and choosing between a personal brand or a corporate brand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Initially, branding processes entail all representations that build or portray a company. These days, the nature of digital marketing has introduced the use of personal identity for official representations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The definition of a brand has far evolved beyond the stables of a corporate organization to common positions like social media influencers and digital marketers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevertheless, there are certain factors to consider.</span></p>
<h2>Personal brand</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A personal brand is built around your identity and personality. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This also includes your lifestyle, interests, and endeavours. Personal brands are built around your name and persona. This means your business is branded with your name (or something very related e.g your nickname).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal branding attributes the brand to <strong>an individual,</strong> rather than a corporate enterprise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This gives individuals the opportunity of building authority around their niche market. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People that choose the path of personal branding present themselves as a go-to source for solutions and an expert in their career path. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This includes the coordinated effort of your skills, experience, and authenticity.</span></p>
<h2>Corporate brand</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate branding on the other hand builds an identity around your business enterprise. <strong>This presents your brand as a structured organization,</strong> with defined work ethics, dedicated customer-care services, and a catalogue of products and services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate branding portrays you as just a member of a larger corporate organization (which may also be your brand.)</span></p>
<p>With a <span style="font-weight: 400;">corporate </span>brand, public relations, brand communications, client onboarding processes are characteristically kept formal. Corporate brands are also known for things like Official Statements, Press Releases, Annual Reports e.tc.</p>
<p><strong>Read Also: <a href="https://branditechture.agency/10-common-branding-mistakes-you-must-avoid/" title="10 Common Branding Mistakes You Must Avoid" data-schema-attribute="" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10 Common Branding Mistakes You Must Avoid</a></strong></p>
<h2>Should I have a Personal Brand?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-9419" title="Personal Brand or Corporate Brand" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1024x683.jpg" alt="Personal Brand or Corporate Brand" width="940" height="627" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-480x320.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1320x880.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiple factors determine if you should have a personal brand. These factors cut across what you wish to achieve with your identity and if it is necessary to put out yourself as an individual brand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the beginning of your decisions for personal branding lies in understanding personal branding and why it is important for your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are few reasons why you should have a personal brand.</span></p>
<h3>· Personal brands are adaptive</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal brands are developed to easily adapt to trends and updates. You can easily change your product line and service offerings without posing any threat to your brand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3>· Personal brands are entrepreneurial</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal brands are usually portrayed as a one-man business. This makes personal branding a nice option for career paths that require individual establishment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This includes but not limited to being an author, graphic designer, painter, coach, or public speaker. If you are considering setting your business in the one-man industry field, personal branding is a better option.</span></p>
<h2>Differences</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal branding offers the opportunity to market your services with your own personalized identity. However, depending on the context in which your personal brand name is found, it is still very possible for a prospective client to be unable to associate your name with your products or services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although business branding offers a clearer view of your business, it does not offer a flexible structure.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p><strong>Read Also:  <a href="https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/">8 Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding</a> </strong></p>
<h2>How To Choose</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are three factors to consider when choosing between a personal brand and a business brand;</span></p>
<h4>· Type of business<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike business brands, personal brands are great options for freelancers.</span></p>
<h4>· Size of business</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You might have the option of setting up a large-scale business with different managerial arms. This makes it important to portray your business as an organization other than a personal representation of your lifestyle.</span></p>
<h4>· Business Interest</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your business line and area of specialization should help you determine whether to go for a personal brand or a business brand. Your business can pose the approach of a startup building it around yourself alone could limit your reach and expansion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This entails that before choosing between a business brand or a personal brand, you must be able to decide what your business stands for, and areas you wish to explore in the business economy.</span></p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you decide to go for a personal brand or a business brand, you must stick to authenticity and value.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Great brands are built on the level of services they offer, and how wide they spread the word about what do.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This means whatever type of branding you wish to explore, visibility, authenticity, and quality assurance should be your yardstick for growth.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/">Personal Brand or Corporate Brand; How To Choose.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What To Do When Your Brand Gets Messed Up</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/what-to-do-when-your-brand-gets-messed-up/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/what-to-do-when-your-brand-gets-messed-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand crisis management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand naming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=8619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Believe me, It is never a fun experience when you unintentionally choose an unfortunate brand name, especially when you gave it your best shot all through the brand discovery and naming process. One of the very first steps before establishing a business is to search for a brand name  — A name that would drive [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-to-do-when-your-brand-gets-messed-up/">What To Do When Your Brand Gets Messed Up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article-author-info-container">
<div class="article-title">Believe me, It is never a fun experience when you unintentionally choose an unfortunate brand name, especially when you gave it your best shot all through the brand discovery and naming process. <span>One of the very first steps before establishing a business is to search for a brand name  </span><span>— </span><span>A name that would drive the <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-secrets-to-building-and-sustaining-brand-equity/">brand’s equity</a> in the right direction. </span><span>But what can you do to guard your brand in a situation where your brand’s equity is under threat by an otherwise unrelated circumstance — like the 2020 Coronavirus outbreak?</span></div>
<div class="article-author-info">
<h2>The Scape Goat Brand of 2020</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_8628" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8628" class="wp-image-8628 size-full" title="The Scapegoat Brand Name of 2020 - Corona Extra; What To Do When Your Brand Gets Messed Up" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/The-Scapegoat-Brand-of-2020-Corona-Extra.jpg" alt="The Scapegoat Brand of Corona Extra" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/The-Scapegoat-Brand-of-2020-Corona-Extra.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/The-Scapegoat-Brand-of-2020-Corona-Extra-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/The-Scapegoat-Brand-of-2020-Corona-Extra-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/The-Scapegoat-Brand-of-2020-Corona-Extra-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8628" class="wp-caption-text">Corona Extra <span>— </span>The Scapegoat Brand of 2020</p></div></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s begin with <strong>Corona (Beer).</strong></p>
<p><b>Corona Beer</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a well-known alcoholic beverage worldwide, although it is mostly consumed in Europe and America. Corona is a pale-looking lager produced by Mexican brewery </span><b>Cervecería Modelo</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and owned by Belgian company </span><b>AB InBev.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The name of the beer was reportedly inspired by the crown on a church in Puerto Vallarta, a resort town on Mexico’s Pacific coast. “Corona” in Latin means halo or crown, and that’s how the beer brand got its name in 1925.</span></p>
<h2>The Coronavirus Pandemic and Corona Beer</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coronavirus belongs to a family of viruses having spikes which include the SARS and MERS viruses. They got their name from resembling little crowns. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Coronavirus (COVID-19) epidemic that originated from Wuhan China in 2019 has no connection whatsoever with Corona lager beer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet, Google searches have been trending for search queries such as “Corona beer virus” and “beer virus.”  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some mischievous internet users also started <em><strong>polluting</strong> </em>the internet with memes and videos linking the beer to the virus.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, Jen Davies was seen in a video emptying the contents of Corona beer bottles down the sink because she is “trying to get rid of this virus in their house.” 👇</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8626" style="width: 825px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8626" class="size-full wp-image-8626" title="Jen Davies Corona Beer" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Jen-Davies-Corona-Beer.png" alt="Jen Davies Corona Beer" width="815" height="714" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Jen-Davies-Corona-Beer.png 815w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Jen-Davies-Corona-Beer-300x263.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Jen-Davies-Corona-Beer-768x673.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Jen-Davies-Corona-Beer-480x421.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 815px) 100vw, 815px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8626" class="wp-caption-text">Jen Davies as seen in a video emptying the contents of Corona beer bottles into a sink.</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>More Similar Examples</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have seen cases where a company has “carelessly” adopted a trade name with an unpleasant meaning in another language or dialect. </span></p>
<p>Here are just a few examples:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><span>Ford launched its </span><b>Ford Pinto</b><span> automobile in 1971 before learning that in Brazil, “Pinto” meant a small-sized male genital. &#8220;</span><strong>Pinto&#8221;</strong> is a relatively unworthy name for a car model that sold so well in Europe, so they eventually had to rename it to <strong>Corcel</strong> in Brazil.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A food manufacturer based in Britain excitedly launched its</span><b> “Bundh” Curry Sauce </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">before learning that “Bundh” meant butts 🍑 in Punjabi (relating to the Punjab community in India).  </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">India’s largest car company, Tata, announced its </span><b>Zica car</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an abbreviation of “zippy car,” but had to rename it to </span><b>Tiago</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the Portuguese name for James, because of its possible incorrect association with the Zica virus. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><b>Chevrolet Nova</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or “Chevy Nova”  could be translated as “no go” in Spanish, which reportedly had a negative impact on sales in Spain.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3>Unfortunate Events</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some brands have been linked to an unfortunate event despite having no connection to it. All because of a similarity with the brand name. For example:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Isis Pharmaceuticals</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> irresistibly changed its name to </span><b>Ionis Pharmaceuticals</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2015 because of the rising popularity of ISIS terrorism in the media.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A PR and events agency in Edinburgh named </span><b>Tsunami</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> decided to undergo a renaming process following the </span><b>2004 Indian Ocean disaster</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a class="extlink" href="https://www.chicagotribune.com/news/ct-xpm-1986-02-15-8601120299-story.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><b>Tylenol</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was banned in several states in the US</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> after capsules laced with potassium cyanide killed seven people in the Chicago area in 1982. Johnson &amp; Johnson, the manufacturer, recalled over 31 million bottles of Tylenol capsules </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">—</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A move that saw the company spend more than 100 million USD ($100m) at the time. They did a </span><a href="https://branditechture.agency/branding-packages/"><b>complete product rebranding</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> before reintroducing the product into the market.  </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">An appetite suppressant named </span><b>Ayds</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the 1970s reportedly suffered a huge drop in sales in the 1980s, no thanks to the </span><b>AIDS crisis</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2>What to do to protect your brand</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s largely not your fault, alright? but what can you do to protect your brand in a situation where your brand’s equity is under threat by an otherwise unrelated circumstance? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regardless of the strategy employed, there no guarantee that your brand would ever recover. However, some brands have managed to come back and claim a higher market share post-crisis. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An example is <strong>Johnson &amp; Johnson,</strong> which was once known for consumer products like baby shampoo and band-aid bandages. It has now become a pharmaceutical giant. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the start of the new millennium (2021), a whopping 45 per cent of sales had come from prescription drugs alone, up from just 18 per cent before the </span><b>Tylenol crisis</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 1980.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2021, Johnson &amp; Johnson was granted the rights to commercially produce and market the Janssen COVID-19 Vaccine under its pharmaceutical arm, <a class="extlink" href="https://www.janssen.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Janssen Pharmaceuticals.</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The vaccine was even marked safe by the World Health Organization. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What a comeback!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your own approach towards this issue may depend on the following factors;</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your trademark’s existing mindshare (or public recognition) </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The number of people who inadvertently connect your brand name to the disaster, and</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The intensity of the effect on your sales or reputation.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are a few of the strategies you might consider, but you should be decisive in your approach before things spin irreversibly out of control:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do nothing (Although not recommended.) Wait it out until everything blows over</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make major changes to the product packaging to counter the problem</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start an advertising and publicity campaign to inform consumers of your brand’s position in the event.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Send take down-notices to internet service providers (or ISPs) aiding the misleading videos or websites</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Report it on social media and charge your loyal fans to do the same</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Send official complaints to misguided media outlets asking for corrections</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Submit to major newspapers editorials explaining the facts</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If everything fails and you still sense a serious loom, change your brand name.</span></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p>Need one-on-one brand advice? Book a session <a href="https://branditechture.agency/contact/">by contacting us.</a> Charges may apply.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-to-do-when-your-brand-gets-messed-up/">What To Do When Your Brand Gets Messed Up</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/what-to-do-when-your-brand-gets-messed-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lessons To Learn from Lil Nas X&#8217;s &#8220;Satan Shoes&#8221; Saga</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/lessons-to-learn-from-lil-nas-xs-satan-shoes-saga/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/lessons-to-learn-from-lil-nas-xs-satan-shoes-saga/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=8563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>On Saturday, March 27, 2021,  social media went into a craze after Lil Nas X announced that he would be releasing ‘Satan Shoes.’ Satan Shoes are a series of customized Nike Air Max 97 shoes, created as a collaboration between musician Lil Nas X and MSCHF, a streetwear company. The news came shortly after the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/lessons-to-learn-from-lil-nas-xs-satan-shoes-saga/">Lessons To Learn from Lil Nas X&#8217;s &#8220;Satan Shoes&#8221; Saga</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Saturday, March 27, 2021,  social media went into a craze after Lil Nas X announced that he would be releasing<strong> ‘Satan Shoes.’ </strong>Satan Shoes are a series of customized Nike Air Max 97 shoes, created as a collaboration between musician Lil Nas X and MSCHF, a streetwear company.</p>
<p>The news came shortly after the release of his song <a class="extlink" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6swmTBVI83k" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="nofollow noopener">‘Montero (Call me by your name)’</a> on March 26.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lil Nas X - MONTERO (Call Me By Your Name) (Official Video)" width="940" height="529" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6swmTBVI83k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The controversial kicks — apparently modified Nike Air Max 97s — are decorated with a <strong>pentagram pendant,</strong> and purported to contain <strong>one drop of human blood</strong> in the midsoles in addition to a reference to <strong>Luke 10:18,</strong> a Bible verse about Satan&#8217;s fall from heaven.</p>
<p>Only <strong>666</strong> pairs, costing $1,018 each, were made, all of which were sold out within minutes of going on sale.</p>
<p>People initially thought Nike was a part of this. However, Nike strongly refuted such claims by filing a federal trademark infringement lawsuit against the company that released the controversial kicks.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_8566" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8566" class="wp-image-8566 size-full" title="Lessons To Learn from Lil Nas Xs Satan Shoes Saga" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Lessons-To-Learn-from-Lil-Nas-Xs-Satan-Shoes-Saga.jpg" alt="Lessons To Learn from Lil Nas Xs Nike Satan Shoes Saga" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Lessons-To-Learn-from-Lil-Nas-Xs-Satan-Shoes-Saga.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Lessons-To-Learn-from-Lil-Nas-Xs-Satan-Shoes-Saga-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Lessons-To-Learn-from-Lil-Nas-Xs-Satan-Shoes-Saga-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Lessons-To-Learn-from-Lil-Nas-Xs-Satan-Shoes-Saga-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8566" class="wp-caption-text">Lil Nas X holding the controversial Nike Satan Shoe</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The statement read:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>We do not have a relationship with Little Nas X or MSCHF. Nike did not design or release these shoes and we do not endorse them.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Nike&#8217;s mission to stop the rollout of MSCHF&#8217;s Lil Nas X-inspired &#8220;Satan&#8221; Air Max 97s was successful, and MSCHF was forced to buy back all the pairs for the original retail price of $1,018.</p>
<p>The judge&#8217;s ruling came as a result of Nike&#8217;s lawsuit (which was termed as &#8220;a somewhat hypocritical approach to copyright,&#8221; in a statement released by American postal service company, USPS).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>But as a business owner, you should be asking yourself this question 👇</p>
<h2>&#8220;What can I learn from Nike vs Lil Nas X&#8217;s Satan Shoe Saga?&#8221;</h2>
<p>Theft is a major concern for all businesses, as losing a property can directly translate to a loss of profit.</p>
<p>But for online businesses, the greatest worry is never theft of material goods, but that of <strong>intellectual property (or IP).</strong></p>
<p>This applies to all forms and sizes of businesses.</p>
<p>Businesses depend on their logos, trademarks, designs, and other property of the intellect to connect with their audience.</p>
<p>Your competitive advantage comes from and is built around your ideas, and if these ideas are not properly protected, they can be stolen, thereby potentially resulting in a huge financial loss.</p>
<p>In 2017, the <strong>Commission on the Theft of American Intellectual Property</strong> (or IP Commission) estimated that the cost of intellectual property theft to the US economy alone could be as high as $600 billion annually <strong><a class="extlink" href="http://www.ipcommission.org/report/IP_Commission_Report_Update_2017.pdf" data-schema-attribute="" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">[PDF | 352KB]</a>, </strong> and small businesses are at the greatest risk.</p>
<p>So what can you do to safeguard your brand from issues like the above?</p>
<h3>1. Trademark your brand</h3>
<p>A trademark officially confirms ownership of your brand name.</p>
<p>Although technically, “trademark” is used for products and “service mark” is used for services, the term “trademark” is commonly used in both cases.</p>
<p>Owning a trademark can give you the <strong>legal right</strong> under federal and state law to prevent others from using your trademark to promote their services.</p>
<p><strong>Read Also:</strong> <a href="https://branditechture.agency/top-6-factors-to-consider-when-naming-a-brand/#6_Trademark_it" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="noopener"><strong>Brand Trademark FAQs</strong></a></p>
<h3>2. Be unique. Stand out</h3>
<p>Avoid any likelihood of confusion.</p>
<p>According to the United States Patent and Trademark Office (or USPTO), there is a &#8220;likelihood of confusion&#8221; if they determine that the applicant&#8217;s marks are similar in appearance, sound, meaning or pronunciation to another, or the goods or services provided by two companies are similar enough for consumers to mistakenly believe they&#8217;re from the same company.</p>
<p>In order to avoid the likelihood of confusion towards getting your IP certified, you must ensure the uniqueness of your IP so that it is not similar to yours. You can do this by performing a trademark search in the <a class="extlink" href="https://www.uspto.gov/trademarks-application-process/search-trademark-database" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="noopener">USPTO trademark database.</a></p>
<h3>3. Include an intellectual property clause in your terms &amp; conditions</h3>
<p>From a legal viewpoint, it&#8217;s important to protect yourself and your intellectual property by putting it into writing.</p>
<p>The best way to achieve this is through a comprehensive terms and conditions (T&amp;C) agreement posted in a prominent location on your website or mobile app.</p>
<p>A terms and conditions contract agreement is aimed at protecting your brand It gives you the opportunity to set your rules (within applicable law) of how your service or product may be used including, but not limited to, things like copyright conditions, age limits, and the governing law of the contract.</p>
<p>It is a fundamental policy for your brand, and one that will give you the legal backing to deal with abuses and unruly users.</p>
<h3>4. Stay vigilant</h3>
<p>It is extremely important to stay vigilant and monitor your adversaries for potential thievery. Though, constant monitoring of other sites and businesses is an arduous and time-consuming task. In <a href="https://branditechture.agency/" data-schema-attribute="">Branditechture</a>, we use a software called <a class="extlink" href="https://www.g2crowd.com/categories/intellectual-property-management" target="_blank" data-schema-attribute="" rel="nofollow noopener">G2 Assistant</a> to aid our battle against IP theft.</p>
<p>This software crawls (or hunts) the internet in search of your <strong>brand name mentions</strong> and reports back with any infringements.</p>
<p>It frees you up to focus on other business-related tasks.</p>
<p>Legal implications aside, if the theft of your intellectual property goes unnoticed, it can have a negative effect on your brand&#8217;s equity—and ultimately, your market share. It could take years to recover completely from those losses, if ever.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/lessons-to-learn-from-lil-nas-xs-satan-shoes-saga/">Lessons To Learn from Lil Nas X&#8217;s &#8220;Satan Shoes&#8221; Saga</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/lessons-to-learn-from-lil-nas-xs-satan-shoes-saga/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Your Startup Needs A Brand Champion</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/why-your-startup-needs-a-brand-champion/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/why-your-startup-needs-a-brand-champion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How Tos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=8480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Your brand promises something to consumers, and in my previous article, you learned how to align your brand with your brand strategy. How would consumers believe your brand promise if your own employees don’t even align with your brand strategy? You&#8217;ll need a brand champion to spearhead your brand building quest. Does your company or startup have [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/why-your-startup-needs-a-brand-champion/">Why Your Startup Needs A Brand Champion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your<span> </span>brand promises<span> </span>something to consumers, and in my previous article<a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-align-your-brand-with-your-brand-strategy/"></a>, you learned <a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-align-your-brand-with-your-brand-strategy/">how to align your brand with your brand strategy.</a> How would consumers believe your brand promise if your own employees don’t even align with your brand strategy? You&#8217;ll need a brand champion to spearhead your brand building quest.</p>
<p><span id="more-2251"></span>Does your company or startup have a person in a leadership position? Preferably at the executive level, who embodies the brand promise, champions the brand promise both internally and externally, and ensures that it is effectively protected against naysayers. Yes? No?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-8496" title="How To Align Your Brand With Your Brand Strategy" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/How-To-Align-Your-Brand-With-Your-Brand-Strategy-3.jpg" alt="How To Align Your Brand With Your Brand Strategy" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/How-To-Align-Your-Brand-With-Your-Brand-Strategy-3.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/How-To-Align-Your-Brand-With-Your-Brand-Strategy-3-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/How-To-Align-Your-Brand-With-Your-Brand-Strategy-3-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/How-To-Align-Your-Brand-With-Your-Brand-Strategy-3-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The brand champion</strong> has a huge list of critical responsibilities, but the most important of all is to help to <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-secrets-to-building-and-sustaining-brand-equity/">increase<span> </span>brand equity.</a></p>
<p>Brand champions don’t always drive immediate results, making their position easy to write off or to consider as a secondary responsibility within another position. But if you have the means, do not let that happen in your organization.</p>
<p>Here, we&#8217;ve got some of the core features a brand champion should possess:</p>
<h2>Motivate the brand</h2>
<p>The brand champion should be the most powerful, most vocal promoter of the brand. He needs to be able to drive the employees, consumers, and other external audiences to trust and have faith in the brand, too.</p>
<p>The brand champion should also ensure that the brand is always in <a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-align-your-brand-with-your-brand-strategy/"><strong>alignment with its brand strategy.</strong></a> He makes sure no stone is left unturned.</p>
<h2>Protect the brand</h2>
<p>The brand champion should also be able to act like the brand’s guard. He should effectively protect it against negative publicity and avoid brand-related scandals.</p>
<p>The brand champion should be able to carry out fundamental PR duties; when a problem of any kind arises, the brand champion should be able to recognize and address them. In addition, he should always strive to be the first to bring the attention of the executive directors or head before the problem worsens.</p>
<h2>Embody the brand</h2>
<p>A utopian scenario is that which all employees are living embodiments of the brand promise, but at the very least you can expect is that the brand champion to <strong>live and breathe</strong> the brand. He should be a walking example.</p>
<h2>Preach the brand</h2>
<p>Preaching the brand should not be left for the marketers alone. A brand champion must also act as a brand <strong>evangelist</strong>.</p>
<p>He has to be able to put himself in the position of the consumers. He needs to be in a constant loop with them in order to ensure that business decisions are in alignment with the brand promise and don&#8217;t negatively impact consumers’ perceptions of the brand.</p>
<h2>Contribute to the brand&#8217;s innovation</h2>
<p>The brand champion must be innovative. He should lead strategic and tactical planning in order to maintain and sustain the brand’s relevance. He also leverages public feedback as a tool for adjustments and growth.</p>
<h2>Act as the brand coach</h2>
<p>In the absence of education, no one will fully understand and believe in a brand. That&#8217;s why the brand champion needs to make sure that both the staff, customers and potential customers understand the brand.</p>
<p>He also ensures that business goals and initiatives are in alignment with the brand promise.</p>
<p>He makes effort to ensures that all team members within the organization are on the same level as it relates to building brand equity.</p>
<p>Remember, the brand champion leads the charge, but without the required support from other stakeholders, the brand champion will not succeed.</p>
<p>To sum it up, stakeholders must ensure that adequately supporting the brand champion remains a top priority to stand any chance of real results.</p>
<hr />
<p><em><b>Need Market Research?</b></em></p>
<p><em>Our market research service ensures that your brand gets the market data it requires to enable it (re)connect and achieve top-of-mind recognition among its target markets. Kickstart a new market research study; <a href="https://branditechture.agency/start-a-project/">click here</a> and select <strong>Market Research</strong>. </em><span><b></b></span></p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/why-your-startup-needs-a-brand-champion/">Why Your Startup Needs A Brand Champion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/why-your-startup-needs-a-brand-champion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
