<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Web Design &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/category/web-design/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 05:45:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Web Design &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Top 7 Essential Elements Every Small Website Needs</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/top-7-essential-elements-every-small-website-needs/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/top-7-essential-elements-every-small-website-needs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 05:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=13911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Just imagine a prospective client or customer landing on your website for their very first time. Your website has a few seconds to create an impression. In the world of websites, the first impression is often the last impression. That is to say that their first experiences affect how they view your website and your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/top-7-essential-elements-every-small-website-needs/">The Top 7 Essential Elements Every Small Website Needs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just imagine a prospective client or customer landing on your website for their very first time. Your website has a few seconds to create an impression. <b>In the world of websites, the first impression is often the last impression. </b>That is to say that their first experiences affect how they view your website and your business as a whole.</p>
<p>Some studies suggest that it takes about <b>0.5 seconds</b> for the average visitor to form an opinion about your website, which means that your viewer decides whether or not they like your website within the blink of an eye.</p>
<p>If you are lucky to get a customer to stick around your website for more than a few seconds, you would certainly need a great<a href="https://branditechture.agency/what-exactly-is-ui-ux-design-and-why-does-it-matter/#:~:text=of%20a%20product.-,What%20is%20UX%3F,-UX%2C%20User%20Experience"> user experience</a> to keep them around. To achieve this, your website needs to have some engaging and helpful content, a user-friendly design, and clear<a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-amazing-microcopy-tips-for-ux-designers/#:~:text=3.1.%20Read%20Also%3A-,Wait!%20What%20is%20Microcopy%3F,-Microcopy%20refers%20to"> microcopy.</a></p>
<p><b>Dig deep to figure out what your site visitors actually want.</b></p>
<p>If you are really serious about making your website a client magnet that brings in the right audience, then you must care about making it engaging enough to keep visitors around for an impactful amount of time. You&#8217;ll need to structure your website in such a way that it guides them through a path that ultimately solves their problems.</p>
<p>The potential customer is looking forward to a few things. Yes, they may need your products and services, but they also need to see some elements of proof, trust, and niche authority.</p>
<p>Does your website have verifiable customer reviews? Are the contents of your website engaging enough to keep them around? Are you able to convince them in very few sentences that your service or product is just what they need? Do you have a clear explanation on how you are going to help them?</p>
<p>Look, your website is your marketing tool with limitless capabilities.</p>
<p>You’ll need to make it SEO-friendly so that it will easily get found on search engine result-pages for the right search queries. Once a curious prospective customer finds your website, you’ll need to get them hooked up as fast as possible.</p>
<p>Elements of trust, authenticity, and authority are underrated tools which can be used to convert strangers into buying customers. Some customers don&#8217;t buy from you on the first visit, which is why you need elements such as a newsletter subscription form to collect email addresses in order to keep in touch with them.</p>
<h2>Three important things your website must get done</h2>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-13926" title="Black Lady Designing Website" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Black-Lady-Designing-Website.jpg" alt="Black Lady Designing Website" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Black-Lady-Designing-Website.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Black-Lady-Designing-Website-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Black-Lady-Designing-Website-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Black-Lady-Designing-Website-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<h3>1. Ensure you get found online.</h3>
<p>This is probably the most important focus point. Did you know that search engine traffic is the leading source of traffic for most websites on the World Wide Web?</p>
<p>A lot of entrepreneurs have been able to generate huge amount of revenue by getting their search engine optimization right, and guess what, you can do it too.</p>
<p>You should employ a search engine optimisation strategy to improve your website’s ranking on Google search results. Studies have shown that the higher you rank, the higher the chance is that the searcher will click on this result. This explains the direct connection between high rankings and increased traffic.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>2. You must pique their interest using words that engage.</h3>
<p>Instead of just talking about your brand alone, tell a narrative about it while bringing your prospects (who are your website visitors in this context) into the picture. Prospects should imagine themselves as characters in a story that begins and ends with their difficulties, pain, and frustrations. They&#8217;ve come to your website because they&#8217;re facing difficulties. You must grab these people&#8217;s attention and persuade them that you are the solution to their problems.</p>
<h3>3. You have to lead them on a journey&#8230;</h3>
<p>Create a webpage that will lead visitors through the buying process. Tell them what to do next and provide them clear instructions on how to proceed. This is accomplished through the use of design, <a href="https://branditechture.agency/web-writing-best-practices/">copy</a>, and site functionality.</p>
<p><strong>So, how do you go about doing this in Tarnation?</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m grateful you inquired. Every small business website requires a few &#8220;must-have&#8221; items. Without them, your website will be nothing more than a billboard in the digital desert, and no one will ever notice it.</p>
<h2>Here are the Top 7 essential elements every small website needs.</h2>
<h3>1. A captivating home page</h3>
<p>Everything I&#8217;ve said so far begins on your <a href="https://branditechture.agency/">homepage</a>. Someone who lands on your homepage is looking for reasons to believe you&#8217;re the answer to their prayers, and they&#8217;re looking for a few things to persuade them.</p>
<p>They want to have faith in you. (Make certain they don&#8217;t have any doubts!) They&#8217;re starving for knowledge. (Provide the proof they&#8217;re looking for!) They must be aware of their options. (Your homepage&#8217;s content and structure must instruct and guide!)</p>
<p>Write text that stands out from the crowd, attracts the right people, and keeps them coming back for more.</p>
<p>Create a core message that is compelling, magnetic, and persuasive, and that is your promise to your clients that you will solve their problems.</p>
<p>To make your website&#8217;s homepage the magnetic sales tool it needs to be, read the following post.</p>
<h3>2. Put all your focus on your ideal customer.</h3>
<p>In order to to create engaging homepage copy, you must <a href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/">write content</a> that will appeal to your target customer.</p>
<p>Why? People want to find solutions to their issues. They&#8217;ll spend their money elsewhere until your copy pledges to do so.</p>
<p>All of your messaging should be driven by your ideal customer&#8217;s goals and needs, and here&#8217;s what your persuasive words should portray to a hungry potential customer:</p>
<p>Show them why your company is the best fit for them in a clear, simple, and convincing manner.</p>
<p>By putting your buyer&#8217;s needs first, you can design a solid marketing strategy and a compelling website.</p>
<p>When it comes to establishing client personas, most companies barely skim the surface. But you must dig deeper to create text that shows your ideal consumer why your company is the best fit for them in a clear and convincing manner.</p>

<h3>3. Guide them with storytelling</h3>
<p>You may have heard the term &#8220;storytelling&#8221; in marketing but have no idea what it entails.</p>
<p>You can immediately see how story works in marketing if you look at successful movies. People admire and identify with heroes, yet all heroes require instruction.</p>
<p>You will be the one to guide your students as a teacher (your customers).</p>
<p>People are hardwired to enjoy stories, therefore include elements of storytelling in your copy. Just keep in mind that the story isn&#8217;t about you. It&#8217;s all about your client. You draw them into a story about the difficulties they confront.</p>
<p>If you were to provide your customers with instructions. You&#8217;ll need to be their tour guide. You must have a complete understanding of what they are going through. You must show them that are the only one who is qualified to assist them.</p>
<h3>4. Trust, proof, and authority are all elements that must be present.</h3>
<div id="attachment_13927" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13927" class="size-full wp-image-13927" title="Website UI Wireframe Planning in Progress" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Website-UI-Wireframe-Planning-in-Progress.jpg" alt="Website UI Wireframe Planning in Progress" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Website-UI-Wireframe-Planning-in-Progress.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Website-UI-Wireframe-Planning-in-Progress-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Website-UI-Wireframe-Planning-in-Progress-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Website-UI-Wireframe-Planning-in-Progress-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-13927" class="wp-caption-text">Website UI Wireframe Planning in Progress</p></div>
<p>Let&#8217;s assume a potential client is checking out your website, but they aren&#8217;t sure why they should trust you. What do you believe they&#8217;ll do, in your opinion? They&#8217;ll skip town directly into your competitor&#8217;s arms. That&#8217;s something you don&#8217;t want to happen.</p>
<p>You must establish confidence by ensuring them that they&#8217;ve found what they&#8217;re seeking for—authority and proof of your expertise—to catch their attention and keep them engaged.</p>
<p>You might achieve this by prominently displaying <strong>client logos</strong> or <strong>testimonials</strong> throughout your site.</p>
<p><strong>Case studies,</strong> <strong>blog posts,</strong> and <strong>videos</strong> all demonstrate your knowledge while also educating and proving your point.</p>
<p>The benefit of all of this proof you&#8217;re throwing up? These components will keep your content machine churning out the type of content your target consumers are looking for.</p>
<h3>5. SEO optimized content</h3>
<p>In a sea of noise, strong branding and appealing website content will help you stand out. However, in this wide digital realm, people must find you, thus SEO is required to complete the picture.</p>
<p>Your customer&#8217;s marketing journey begins with a Google search, as previously said. To be found online, you must create a search engine friendly website.</p>
<p>You can build a steady flow of material that people will want to read by writing content that answers your ideal customer&#8217;s questions.</p>
<p>Inform, educate, and engage your audience.</p>
<p>Prospects will find you if you optimize your site for search. There are also some SEO fundamentals to master&#8230;</p>
<p>Are you aiming for a national or worldwide audience when you rank? If that&#8217;s the case, send us an email to have a look at our comprehensive SEO plan.</p>
<p>Or are you a local company owner that wants to rank higher for local searches? Then let us help you improve your local ranking.</p>
<p>As a website owner, your customer journey often times begins with a Google search. So create copy that is <a href="https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/">tailored</a> to your ideal customer&#8217;s needs.</p>
<h3>6. Optimized Call to Action</h3>
<p>The term &#8220;Call to Action,&#8221; or CTA, is certainly familiar to you.</p>
<p>A CTA, such as a &#8220;Let&#8217;s talk today&#8221; button, is a combination of action-oriented text and graphics. It&#8217;s the thing that makes a site visitor want to do something (&#8220;Call us;&#8221; &#8220;Sign up for our newsletter;&#8221; &#8220;Buy now,&#8221; and so on.)</p>
<p>You want to make your website as user-friendly as possible by including CTAs that will assist them through their journey.</p>
<p>So they don&#8217;t have to battle to find out what to do next, provide them with clear next actions.</p>
<p>CTAs are a must-have aspect because of this. They provide visitors with a clear and simple path to follow.</p>
<p>What are the big, fat, magnificent advantages? They&#8217;ll make your customers happy, and they&#8217;ll help you convert more customers.</p>
<p>To direct site visitors, include a clear Call to Action. Don&#8217;t use passive language and be specific.</p>

<p>Some businesses, shockingly, fail to include contact information. That&#8217;s not good! You must make it as simple as possible for someone to contact you through your website.</p>
<p>Is there a question they&#8217;d like to ask? If that&#8217;s the case, make it crystal clear how to contact you. What about a local client who merely wants to know your location? Is your address prominently displayed? Have you added local information on your website, such as a map?</p>
<p>In your top navigation menu, provide a &#8220;Contact&#8221; button. Include all contact information in your site&#8217;s footer and contact page, as well as anywhere else you think it&#8217;s necessary.</p>
<p>Make it simple for them to contact you!</p>
<p>Make sure to include your contact information prominently on your website. Also, don&#8217;t overlook the importance of optimizing your footer, which shows on every page of your website.</p>
<h3>7. Don’t underestimate the technical stuff</h3>
<p>What about your website&#8217;s underlying technology? There&#8217;s a lot to think about, from choosing the correct website host to site security.</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t usually think of technology first because it&#8217;s frequently associated with mysterious behind-the-scenes wizardry.</p>
<p>However, solid technology is required for your website to function, and here&#8217;s a little secret: it&#8217;s not that difficult to comprehend and master.</p>
<h2>Three critical technical parts are listed below, and you must ensure that they are correctly implemented.</h2>
<h3>1. Ensure that your website is mobile-friendly</h3>
<p>Today, most searches these days begin on mobile devices such as smartphones and tablets, rather than laptops or desktop PCs.</p>
<p>According to a recent <a class="extlink" href="https://www.perficient.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Perficient</a> analysis, &#8220;mobile devices drove 61 percent of visits to U.S. websites in 2020, up from 57 percent in 2019.&#8221; In 2020, desktops accounted for 35.7 percent of all visits, while tablets accounted for the remaining 3.3 percent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Visitors to your site may notice a cluttered layout, missing design features, or delayed loading times if it is not mobile-friendly. Because first impressions matter, ensure sure your website is mobile-friendly.</p>
<p>The simplest approach to do so is to take out your smartphone and go to your website. &#8220;Thanks, Master of the Obvious,&#8221; you&#8217;re presumably thinking, &#8220;but have you done this?&#8221; If that&#8217;s the case, how does your site appear on a smartphone? Is it taking a long time to load? Are all of the components present?</p>
<h3>2. Always check the security status of your website</h3>
<p>SSL and HTTPS are terms you may have heard. HTTPS (Secure HyperText Transfer Protocol) is a secure variant of HTTP (the main protocol used on the world wide web).</p>
<p>An HTTPS site encrypts and secures the connection between your server and a visitor&#8217;s browser. As a result, your site and your customers&#8217; data are safe from hackers.</p>
<p>A website that uses HTTPS and has a little lock icon in the URL bar is secure.</p>
<p>Google highly advises all website owners to switch to HTTPS. Google Chrome has labeled sites without an HTTPS address as &#8220;not secure&#8221; since July 2018.</p>
<p>As I have stated, first impressions are crucial. What if someone visits your site and notices a &#8220;not secure&#8221; message? That&#8217;s not good!</p>
<p>Furthermore, Google has made HTTPS a ranking criterion, thus upgrading has some SEO benefits.</p>
<h3>3. Check Your Site speed With <a href="https://pagespeed.web.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Page Speed Insights</a></h3>
<div id="attachment_13925" style="width: 1434px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13925" class="size-full wp-image-13925" title="Google Page Speed Insights Landing Page" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Google-Page-Speed-Insights-Landing-Page-min.png" alt="Google Page Speed Insights Landing Page" width="1424" height="792" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Google-Page-Speed-Insights-Landing-Page-min.png 1424w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Google-Page-Speed-Insights-Landing-Page-min-300x167.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Google-Page-Speed-Insights-Landing-Page-min-1024x570.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Google-Page-Speed-Insights-Landing-Page-min-768x427.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Google-Page-Speed-Insights-Landing-Page-min-480x267.png 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Google-Page-Speed-Insights-Landing-Page-min-1320x734.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1424px) 100vw, 1424px" /><p id="caption-attachment-13925" class="wp-caption-text">Google Page Speed Insights Landing Page</p></div>
<p>Customers abandon slow-loading websites.</p>
<p>They stick around because of the fast sites.</p>
<p>And because Google loves a fast website, site speed is a ranking consideration.</p>
<p>The following are some of the main reasons why site speed optimization is so important.</p>
<p>Why? A visitor to your site will not have the patience to wait for slow-loading pages and will quickly move on to your competitors.</p>
<p>So now you know how important site performance is, but how do you ensure that your pages load quickly enough to keep visitors on your site?</p>
<p>To test your site speed, go to <a href="https://pagespeed.web.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google PageSpeed Insights</a>, and enter your website address. If you don&#8217;t see <strong>green</strong>, contact your web developer right away.</p>
<h2>Examine your website right now!</h2>
<p>Consider this scenario: Someone finds your website and visits it for the first time, but they only stay for approximately five seconds before moving on to your competitors.</p>
<p>Why? Because you haven&#8217;t conducted a website evaluation to determine what&#8217;s missing and then add what&#8217;s required.</p>
<p>THIS IS HOW THE COMPETITION GETS POTENTIAL CUSTOMERS. Do you really want it to happen?</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s build a <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lets-build-your-website/">compelling website</a> for your company.</h2>
<p>You only have a few seconds to capture and engage your audience&#8217;s attention. A poorly designed website, on the other hand, is the kiss of death for any small business. In this crowded internet world, your website is only one of many, and a prospect doesn&#8217;t have to spend much time getting to know you before moving on to your competitors.</p>
<p>People want a website that engages them, informs them, and makes it apparent what you have to offer. You also require a quick, user-friendly, mobile-optimized website that will attract the right customers and help your company flourish.</p>
<p>See a <a href="https://branditechture.agency/web-design-portfolio/">list of websites</a> we have created, and <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lets-build-your-website/">let&#8217;s build a website</a> for your company/business.</p>
<pre>Fortunately, If your website is slow, we can assist you. We offer website review service that will show you what you're not doing properly and give you suggestions on how to improve your site.</pre>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/top-7-essential-elements-every-small-website-needs/">The Top 7 Essential Elements Every Small Website Needs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/top-7-essential-elements-every-small-website-needs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web Designers in Lagos — A Shortlist of The Top 5</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/web-designer-lagos/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/web-designer-lagos/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=11334#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=11334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Your choice of Web Designer or Web Design Agency can either make or break your business, that is why it is very crucial for you to hire the best web designer in Lagos for your Lagos-based business. You may be tempted to ask &#8220;Why choose a Web designer in Lagos for my business website?&#8221;. The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/web-designer-lagos/">Web Designers in Lagos — A Shortlist of The Top 5</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your choice of <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lets-build-your-website/">Web Designer</a> or <a href="https://branditechture.agency/">Web Design Agency</a> can either <strong>make or break</strong> your business, that is why it is very crucial for you to hire the best web designer in Lagos for your Lagos-based business.</p>

<p>You may be tempted to ask &#8220;Why choose a Web designer in Lagos for my business website?&#8221;. The answer lies in two truths;</p>
<ol>
<li>Lagos has by far the most developed tech ecosystem in the whole of Nigeria and West Africa, and this includes Web Design. (Source: <a href="https://africa.businessinsider.com/local/markets/here-are-the-top-5-african-countries-with-the-most-developed-startup-ecosystems/23v1mx8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Business Insider</a>).</li>
<li>In Nigeria, Lagos state has the biggest skill pool in the field of web design, and it is home to a fearfully huge percentage of world-class web designers and web design agencies in the country.</li>
</ol>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-13106" title="Web Designers in Lagos" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Web-Designers-in-Lagos-2.jpg" alt="Web Designers in Lagos" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Web-Designers-in-Lagos-2.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Web-Designers-in-Lagos-2-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Web-Designers-in-Lagos-2-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Web-Designers-in-Lagos-2-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Now that you have an idea of how important Lagos State is in the Nigerian Web Design space, let&#8217;s have a look at the top 5 Web Designers and Web Design Agencies in the city of Lagos.</p>
<p>The following metrics would be used for ranking in this list;</p>
<ul>
<li>Years Since Establishment</li>
<li>Public Rating: User reviews that are publicly available on the world wide web.</li>
<li>Online Presence: How many online assets they have, including websites and social media pages.</li>
<li>Affordability: How affordable they are to small businesses and entrepreneurs.</li>
<li>Web Content: Amount of helpful resources and support articles they have published online</li>
</ul>
<p>Here is a shortlist of the top 5 Web Designers in Lagos;</p>

<h2>1.<a href="https://branditechture.agency/"> Branditechture Design Agency</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/"><strong>Branditechture</strong></a> is a full-service web design agency that specializes in working with small businesses thus producing the highest quality results on a modest budget. They give better quality than what you would typically get from an enterprise-level web design agency or web designer in Lagos.</p>
<div id="attachment_13101" style="width: 2570px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13101" class="size-full wp-image-13101" title="Yusuf Odukoya" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-scaled.jpg" alt="Yusuf Odukoya" width="2560" height="1962" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-300x230.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-1024x785.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-768x589.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-1536x1177.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-480x368.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Yusuf-Odukoya-1320x1012.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /><p id="caption-attachment-13101" class="wp-caption-text">Yusuf Odukoya of Branditechture</p></div>
<p>Branditechture&#8217;s biggest selling point is in <a href="https://support.branditechture.agency/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>client support </strong></a>and creating personal relationships with business owners and entrepreneurs. It is also noteworthy that Branditechture is <strong>the most affordable</strong> web design agency on this list.</p>
<p>Branditechture was founded by Yusuf Odukoya, a WordPress Developer and Brand Identity Designer. Yusuf holds a Bachelor of Science in Zoology from the prestigious University of Lagos.</p>
<p>Notable clients include Art Basel, Airtel Nigeria, SPAR, among others.</p>
<p><strong>Located:</strong> Lekki Peninsula, Lagos</p>
<p><strong>Established:</strong> February 2020</p>
<p><strong>Google Business Rating:</strong> 5 Stars from 8 Google Reviews</p>
<p><strong>Online Presence:</strong> LinkedIn, Google My Business, Twitter, Instagram, Pinterest, Behance, Facebook</p>
<p><strong>Affordability:</strong> Starting from <span>₦100</span>,000</p>
<p><strong>Web Content:</strong> <a class="extlink" href="https://branditechture.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Small Business Blog</a>, <a class="extlink" target="_blank" href="https://support.branditechture.agency/" rel="noopener">Branditechture Client Support Center</a>, <a href="https://branditechture.agency/blog">Branditechture Blog</a></p>
<h2>2. <a href="http://ckdigital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CK Digital</a></h2>
<p><b>CK Digital </b>is one of the leading web designers in Lagos. It was founded by Charles Dairo, who is also the current CEO. According to him, CK Digital started over 10 years ago as a side hustle after completing his Computer Science degree program. Some of their past and existing clients include Sifax Group, Vitafoam, and Baba Ijebu.</p>
<p><strong>Located:</strong> Lekki Phase I, Lagos</p>
<p><strong>Established:</strong> 2010</p>
<p><strong>Google Business Rating:</strong> 4.7 Stars from 134 Google Reviews</p>
<p><strong>Online Presence:</strong> LinkedIn, Google My Business, Twitter, Instagram, Facebook</p>
<p><strong>Affordability:</strong> Not Known</p>
<p><strong>Web Content:</strong> <a class="extlink" href="https://ckdigital.com/blog/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CK Digital Blog 1,</a> <a class="extlink" href="https://ckdigital.com/blog/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">CK Digital Blog 2</a></p>

<h2>3. <a href="https://anakle.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Anakle Limited</a></h2>
<p><b>Anakle Ltd. (or Anakle) </b>is a Google-certified digital marketing agency, but they also offer web design services as well. They&#8217;ve worked with the likes of Access Bank, PZ Cussons, First Bank, British Council, Unilever and more. They made number 3 on this list because of their vast experience and exposure. Anakle, Anakle Labs, and Anakle Films were all founded by Editi Effiong, who started learning web design as early as 18 years old, according to an interview with Pulse NG.</p>
<p><strong>Located:</strong> Lekki Phase I, Lagos</p>
<p><strong>Established:</strong> 2010</p>
<p><strong>Google Business Rating:</strong> 4.6 Stars from 98 Google Reviews</p>
<p><strong>Online Presence:</strong> LinkedIn, Google My Business, Twitter, Instagram, Facebook</p>
<p><strong>Affordability:</strong> Not Known</p>
<p><strong>Web Content:</strong> <a href="https://anakle.com/blog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anakle Blog</a></p>
<h2>4. <a href="https://cregital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cregital</a></h2>
<p><b>Cregital</b> is another Lagos-based web design agency <a class="extlink" href="https://stories.cregital.com/rufus-oyemade-cto-now-cofounder-at-cregital-2b79c5ba8a16" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">co-founded</a> by Evans Akanno, a web designer and Rufus Oyemade, a software engineer. Rufus is one of the brains behind Disha Pages, a landing page builder which is widely used by Nigerians. Their clients include Coronation Bank, Globacom, Sterling Bank, Zenith Bank, among others.</p>
<div id="attachment_13099" style="width: 1410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13099" class="size-full wp-image-13099" title="Rufus Oyemade and Evans Akanno" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Rufus-Oyemade-and-Evans-Akanno.jpeg" alt="Rufus Oyemade and Evans Akanno" width="1400" height="1075" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Rufus-Oyemade-and-Evans-Akanno.jpeg 1400w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Rufus-Oyemade-and-Evans-Akanno-300x230.jpeg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Rufus-Oyemade-and-Evans-Akanno-1024x786.jpeg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Rufus-Oyemade-and-Evans-Akanno-768x590.jpeg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Rufus-Oyemade-and-Evans-Akanno-480x369.jpeg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Rufus-Oyemade-and-Evans-Akanno-1320x1014.jpeg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /><p id="caption-attachment-13099" class="wp-caption-text">Rufus Oyemade and Evans Akanno (via Medium)</p></div>
<p><strong>Located:</strong> Surulere, Lagos</p>
<p><strong>Established:</strong> April <span>2015</span></p>
<p><strong>Google Business Rating:</strong> 4.8 Stars from 79 Google Reviews <span class="hqzQac" data-ved="2ahUKEwiL__mtiNLzAhXpAGMBHfF5AKkQiCt6BAhsEAU"><span jscontroller="qjk5yc" jsaction="rcuQ6b:npT2md"></span></span></p>
<p><strong>Online Presence:</strong> LinkedIn, Google My Business, Twitter, Instagram, Facebook, Pinterest, Behance</p>
<p><strong>Affordability:</strong> Not Known</p>
<p><strong>Web Content:</strong> <a class="extlink" href="https://stories.cregital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Cregital Stories</a></p>
<h2>5. <a class="extlink" href="https://ellaecreative.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Ellae Creative</a></h2>
<p><b>Ellae Creative </b>was originally a branding agency focused on creating brand identities, but its portfolio now features several web designs. Its Founder, Noella Ekezie, is a graduate of Parsons School of Design, New York, and Havard Business School, Boston.</p>
<p>Clients include Google, USAID, and Wakanow among others.</p>
<p><strong>Located:</strong> Lekki Phase I, Lagos</p>
<p><strong>Established:</strong> 2010</p>
<p><strong>Google Business Rating:</strong> 4.2 Stars from 27 Google Reviews</p>
<p><strong>Online Presence:</strong> LinkedIn, Google My Business, Instagram, Facebook, Behance</p>
<p><strong>Affordability:</strong> Not Known</p>
<p><strong>Web Content: </strong><a class="extlink" href="https://ellaecreative.com/news-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ellae News</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/web-designer-lagos/">Web Designers in Lagos — A Shortlist of The Top 5</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/web-designer-lagos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Create A Successful Website Concept</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=13002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The world wide web is about first impressions and about keeping visitors on your website for as long as possible. Anyone who clicks away immediately because something does not suit them is lost as a customer. A good website concept helps to retain visitors and develop them into customers. No second chance for a good first [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/">How To Create A Successful Website Concept</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span>The world wide web is about first impressions and about keeping visitors on your website for as long as possible. </span><span>Anyone who clicks away immediately because something does not suit them is lost as a customer.</span> <span>A good website concept helps to retain visitors and develop them into customers.</span></p>
<h2><span>No second chance for a good first impression</span></h2>
<p><span>How does your website receive visitors? How quickly can they find their way around? How logically are the paths your web visitors take? Can they find what they are looking for? Are they encouraged to leave their contact details? Well, just a few details that are essential for a website concept &#8211; whether for a website relaunch or for a new website.</span></p>

<h2><span>The building blocks for a good website</span></h2>
<p><span>Many elements can be found on virtually every website and can therefore be viewed as the building blocks of websites.</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>A </span><strong><span>look</span></strong><span> or a </span><strong><span>design</span></strong><span>: is one of the elements that most quickly decide whether visitors stay or leave again. Should represent your company ideally and be as independent as possible.</span></li>
<li><a href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/"><strong><span>Content</span></strong></a><span>: Texts (including <strong>keywords</strong>), images, </span><span>videos</span><span> that meet the information needs of your visitors. Content not only conveys your company, your offers and products, but can also provide the visitor with further information. </span></li>
<li><strong><span>Contact options</span></strong><span>: The range goes from a simple contact page to customized call-to-actions. It is important that the establishment of contact appears natural and is made easy.</span></li>
<li><strong><span>Measures for visitor</span></strong><span> <strong>loyalty</strong>: Goodies that you give out in exchange for an e-mail address can bind visitors to your website. For example in the form of a newsletter or an e-book.</span></li>
<li><strong><span>Elements that distinguish you from your competitors</span></strong><span>: Whatever that may be, at least give it a lot of thought. Clever stand-alone positions can make a huge difference. Even if you are copied sooner or later, the market knows that you were the pioneer.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span>Your target group determines the choice of content</span></h2>
<p><span>What belongs on your website usually results automatically when you consider your <strong>target group</strong> <em><strong>(a.k.a Target Audience)</strong></em> and your offer. You design the website for this target group. Incidentally, this is much easier if you visualize a certain person in the target group as concretely as possible and then imagine in the future to design a website for precisely this person. (Depending on the target group, this can also be several people.)</span></p>
<p><span>Write down all that you think the target person would love to see on the website and give each item a <strong>priority</strong> as it corresponds to their importance. </span><span>The order affects which element is best placed where.</span> This practice is known as <strong>Information Hierarchy.</strong></p>
<p><span>But also keep in mind that you normally do not know which page of the website is used to access the website. The homepage is not always the first page they would visit, especially when your website is visited from search engine result pages. </span><span>The website conception must take this into account and must not ensure that all pages are of good quality.</span></p>

<h2><span>The sitemap and navigation</span></h2>
<p><span>A sitemap is a plan for how the various content on your website is organized. Regardless of which subpage the visitor enters from and what their interests are, he must be able to move safely through the website by using the navigation menu.</span></p>
<p><span>The navigation menu serves as a visible navigation tool through the page structure of a website.</span></p>
<p><span>The important links should be more obvious than the less important ones. That is why we have <strong>Menus </strong>and <strong>Submenus.</strong></span></p>
<p><span>At the same time, a good page structure must also encourage discovery and must always entice visitors to the next click. Website visitors are reluctant to be squeezed into a rigid framework, they want to move freely and discover interesting things over and over again.</span></p>
<h2><span>From overview to detail</span></h2>
<p><span>For the organization of your information, you should start from different information needs, which correspond to a level of depth on the website. (Depth refers to the number of clicks that are required to get to certain information n your website.)</span></p>
<p><span>Your </span><strong><span>start page</span></strong><span> or </span><strong><span>homepage</span></strong><span> only transports the central messages and serves as an interface to deeper information levels.</span></p>
<p><span>An example: The main benefit of your services or products is briefly presented on the homepage. From there you can get more detailed descriptions and additional details via links or CTA (or Call to action) buttons.</span></p>
<p><span>Another level, for example, can be very fundamentally concerned with the use of your services. This can be done, for example, through background articles that are summarized in the form of a blog. For a better overview, topics can be put together again in a clear manner.</span></p>
<p><span>These levels make it possible to address the various information needs of potential customers. Over time, these develop from very general interest to a need for knowledge about the details of your specific offers.</span></p>

<h2><span>Good web design follows function</span></h2>
<p><span>The job of web design is not just to be visually creative. Web design can also look good, but above all, it should be clear and unambiguous. Standards that everyone has gotten used to should only be given up if you have a concrete reason for doing so.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, a </span>logo is<span> always at the <strong>top left corner</strong>; that&#8217;s where visitors expect it. </span><span>If you link the logo on every page in such a way that clicking on the logo <strong>takes visitors to the home page</strong>, that is another standard that people expect.</span></p>
<p><span>If your company has a </span><strong><span>slogan</span></strong><span>, a </span><strong><span>motto</span></strong><span> or a </span><strong><span>claim</span></strong><span>, this message ideally belongs near the logo.</span></p>
<p><span>The </span><strong><span>menu</span></strong><span> is also best located at the top, simply because it is known from most websites and works well.</span></p>
<p><span>Please do not get creative when naming </span><strong><span>menu items</span></strong><span>, but think with the visitor&#8217;s head which names of the menu items they need in order to find their way around.</span></p>
<p><span>A </span><strong><span>multi-column layout</span></strong><span> can help structure content more clearly. However, it must then be clear which column transports the central content and which only has a supplementary function.</span></p>
<p><span>It is important that a good web design can flow freely with the content and does not restrict you too much. For example, if web design is not flexible in terms of the amount of text, then it is usually not a good web design.</span></p>
<p><span>You shouldn&#8217;t just use <strong>pictures</strong> “because that&#8217;s how you do it”. Instead, images should support and complement the statements on your website. In addition, images enable emotionalisation and, through skilful selection, can greatly contribute to the uniqueness of a company image.</span></p>
<h2><span>Pay more attention to legal requirements</span></h2>
<p><span>Legislators also have some requirements for your website. It is therefore mandatory that you have </span><strong><span>imprint</span></strong><span> and </span><strong><span>data protection information</span></strong><span> on the site.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_13006" style="width: 1038px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13006" class="wp-image-13006 size-full" title="Cookie Consent Prompt" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cookie-Consent-Prompt.png" alt="Cookie Consent Prompt" width="1028" height="159" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cookie-Consent-Prompt.png 1028w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cookie-Consent-Prompt-300x46.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cookie-Consent-Prompt-1024x158.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cookie-Consent-Prompt-768x119.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Cookie-Consent-Prompt-480x74.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1028px) 100vw, 1028px" /><p id="caption-attachment-13006" class="wp-caption-text">Cookie Consent Prompt</p></div>
<p><span>If you collect user data, either directly or through third-party technologies such as Mailchimp, Google Analytics, e.t.c., you are required by law to obtain the consent of your users via a popup or dismissable notice on your website. You would also need a Cookie Policy or/and Privacy Policy page(s) to explain how you use or process user data. </span></p>
<p><span>These pages should be visible and directly accessible via an easy-to-find link on the every page. This act is regulated by federal data protection laws such as the CCPC, GDPR etc. </span></p>
<p><span>What applies to your website depends on your region and that of the users of your website, but a GDPR compliance is sufficient in most cases. </span></p>
<p><span>If the subject of user data collection is too dry for you, you can consult with a contemporary lawyer or read about the fundamentals.</span></p>

<h2><span>Establishing contacts is mandatory</span></h2>
<p><span>Potential customers who visit your website once and never find their way back are of no use to you. You should therefore aim to retain these visitors so that you can send them information later. This is where <strong>blog</strong> <strong>comments </strong>and <strong>newsletters</strong> come in, but having a <strong>contact page </strong>can also do wonders since users would need to submit their emails to contact you.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Interaction elements</span></strong><span>, also known as </span><strong><span>call-to-action</span></strong><span>, are therefore so important for successful websites.</span></p>
<p><span>In addition, think about including your <strong>phone number</strong> and <strong>email address</strong> on every page, for example in the header or footer of the website. This allows your website visitors to quickly get in touch with you.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_13007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13007" class="wp-image-13007 size-full" title="Bunch of CTA buttons" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Bunch-of-CTA-buttons.jpg" alt="Bunch of CTA buttons" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Bunch-of-CTA-buttons.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Bunch-of-CTA-buttons-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Bunch-of-CTA-buttons-768x432.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Bunch-of-CTA-buttons-480x270.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-13007" class="wp-caption-text">Bunch of CTA buttons</p></div>
<p><span>A contextual call-to-action, which actively prompts the visitor to take any action at a strategically appropriate point in the content, works best. If there&#8217;s a small reward in return for that action, a call-to-action works even better.</span></p>
<p><span>For example, you can exchange an e-book for the e-mail address of your visitors and thus have the chance to prove your competence in the long term via a newsletter.</span></p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed reading. Please share.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/">How To Create A Successful Website Concept</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Fashion Nova was Built on Shopify</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natalia Bachmann]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=15832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Fashion Nova (www.fashionnova.com) is one of the world&#8217;s leading fast-fashion and lifestyle companies known for delivering the season&#8217;s hottest looks to millions of consumers across the world. It is a Los Angeles-based e-commerce firm that basically operates online with five retail outlets around Southern California which sell collections for women, men, curves, and kids. Fashion [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/">Why Fashion Nova was Built on Shopify</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fashion Nova (www.fashionnova.com) is one of the world&#8217;s leading fast-fashion and lifestyle companies known for delivering the season&#8217;s hottest looks to millions of consumers across the world. It is a Los Angeles-based e-commerce firm that basically operates online with five retail outlets around Southern California which sell collections for women, men, curves, and kids.</p>
<p>Fashion Nova was established in 2006 by <a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/style/luxury/article/3170404/who-fashion-nova-ceo-richard-saghian-new-owner-las-biggest" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Richard Saghian,</a> who is worth $1.4 billion (US Dollars) as of 2022. Richard began his career in the fashion retail industry by working at his father&#8217;s Los Angeles apparel boutique. Fashion Nova currently has over 600 employees.</p>
<p>In 2018, it was Google’s #1 most-searched Fashion brand with over 21 million followers on social media especially Instagram, including celebrity admirers and partners. In exchange for promoting the brand, models, celebrities, and others are paid or given free apparel.</p>
<h2>Is Fashion Nova Built Using Shopify?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-15840" title="Fashion Nova standing ipad mockup" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup.png" alt="Fashion Nova standing ipad mockup" width="2800" height="2100" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup.png 2800w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-300x225.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-1024x768.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-768x576.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-1536x1152.png 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-480x360.png 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Fashion-Nova-standing-ipad-mockup-1320x990.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2800px) 100vw, 2800px" /></p>
<p>Yes, we can 100% confirm that <a href="http://fashionnova.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Fashion Nova</a> is built and hosted on Shopify. For many successful e-commerce companies, Shopify is a top choice, and these are some important reasons why Fashion Nova was built using Shopify:</p>
<ol>
<li>The Shopify theme is adaptable and responsive with over 100 free and premium templates for all types of eCommerce enterprises. Its eCommerce framework allows you to easily add new features to your website and adjust the look to fit your preferences.</li>
<li>Shopify stores are simple to set up, and even a novice can get them up and running in a matter of days.</li>
<li>Fashion Nova is basically an online store and using the Shopify platform is quite affordable. Their monthly plans start at just $29 per month. They also provide a 14-day risk-free trial</li>
<li>Just like other eCommerce platforms, Shopify handles things like site hosting and other technicalities to remove obstacles to business ownership.</li>
<li>Even during the trial time, there is support for customers. Shopify provides 24/7 customer care via alternatives like live chat.</li>
<li>For Shopify, sustainability is a priority, and store owners like Fashion Nova love this idea. Shopify has social-impact programs in place, such as using renewable energy and minimizing carbon emissions.</li>
</ol>
<p>Currently, Fashion Nova has employed the use of a <a title="Shopify theme" href="https://branditechture.agency/recommends/shopify-theme/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Shopify theme</a>, known as&#8221;Shopify-Nova&#8221;. This theme is both mobile and SEO-friendly. Because of the abundance of user-generated content such as reviews on the site, it will appeal to people of all ages. The content will boost site engagement, which is crucial for the company.</p>

<h2>Fashion Nova&#8217;s Sales Strategy</h2>
<p>In the fashion industry, it&#8217;s no longer considered an option to want your business to have a social media presence; it&#8217;s now a necessity. Fashion Nova understands this and has been using the online platform to its advantage. To date, Fashion Nova has made sales of over 1 billion US Dollars by just being an online store. With Google search volumes that beat out Chanel and Dior in 2017, it has one of the most effective online marketing techniques among fashion brands today.</p>
<p>Although the online store boasts of lightning-fast delivery and a steady stream of new high-quality items, this isn&#8217;t the cause for its current success as the leading fashion store. Fashion Nova simply knows how to advertise their goods properly. Its social media marketing has reached millions, if not billions, of individuals using models, celebrities, and even customers. It is one of the largest online fashion stores with also one of the largest social media presences.</p>
<h3>The Secret of Fashion Nova’s Success Exposed</h3>
<div id="attachment_15837" style="width: 1820px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15837" class="size-full wp-image-15837" title="Richard Saghian and Cardi B" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-scaled.jpg" alt="Richard Saghian and Cardi B" width="1810" height="2560" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-scaled.jpg 1810w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-212x300.jpg 212w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-724x1024.jpg 724w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-768x1086.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-1086x1536.jpg 1086w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-1448x2048.jpg 1448w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-480x679.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Richard-Saghian-and-Cardi-B-1320x1867.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1810px) 100vw, 1810px" /><p id="caption-attachment-15837" class="wp-caption-text">CEO of Nova Fashion, Richard Saghian and Cardi B</p></div>
<p>Building a store on Shopify does not automatically guarantee success, and Richard Saghian, the founder of Fashion Nova, was one of the first to understand the importance of social media platforms in marketing his business when the company was founded in 2006. Their great social media strategy and usage of user-generated content made them really stand out.</p>
<p>Their huge success was due to their collaborative influencer approach. They had celebrities like Kylie Jenner, Cardi B, Nicki Minaj, and Khloe Kardashian post photos of themselves wearing the brand&#8217;s clothing on Instagram. A single post from any of these celebrities can bring in millions of dollars for the brand.</p>
<p>Fashion Nova also encourages its Instagram followers to share photos of themselves wearing their clothes for a chance to be featured on the homepage of their <a href="https://branditechture.agency/recommends/shopify-theme/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Shopify-based</a> website. This function has proven to be really beneficial to them.</p>
<p>Also, it is recommended that a brand makes at least three posts per day to be relevant on Instagram; however, Fashion Nova, whose objective is to reach as many people as possible, posts at least <strong>30 times per day</strong>. This is how they ensure that every Instagram user on the planet sees a post from them at least once a day in their news feed.</p>
<p>Fashion Nova has been mentioned in the lyrics of songs by prominent rappers like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/6ix9ine" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">6ixnine </a>and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/21_Savage" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">21 Savage</a>, this has also made them more popular and successful in the fashion world.</p>
<p>Finally, they have amassed a mind-boggling 21.2 million Instagram followers and can get over 64,000 plays on each video in less than 10 hours. That is a whole lot of numbers which directly lead to sales.</p>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>“Does Fashion Nova Use Shopify?”</strong> Adebisiadewusi, 2 March 2022, https://adebisiadewusi.com/does-fashion-nova-use-shopify/. Accessed 8 May 2022.</li>
<li><strong>“Fashion Nova.”</strong> <a href="http://Wikipedia,/ https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fashion_Nova" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Wikipedia, https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fashion_Nova</a>. Accessed 8 May 2022.</li>
<li><strong>Nataly, Juanita:</strong> <strong>“How Fashion Nova became a leading fashion brand through its social media presence.”</strong> LinkedIn, 29 October 2019, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-fashion-nova-became-leading-brand-through-its-carballeira." target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-fashion-nova-became-leading-brand-through-its-carballeira.</a> Accessed 9 May 2022.</li>
</ol>
<div id="gtx-trans" style="position: absolute; left: -34px; top: 1292.36px;">
<div class="gtx-trans-icon"></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/">Why Fashion Nova was Built on Shopify</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/why-fashion-nova-was-built-on-shopify/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Basic Services To Be Included In Any Website Design</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/10-basic-services-to-be-included-in-any-website-design/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/10-basic-services-to-be-included-in-any-website-design/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Website developer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=14029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Your website needs to be created or updated, however, you are unsure of what to look for in a web design firm. You begin your search online only to discover that many web design firms provide a variety of services. It&#8217;s not about creating a gorgeous website in today&#8217;s competitive market. Your website should cater [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/10-basic-services-to-be-included-in-any-website-design/">10 Basic Services To Be Included In Any Website Design</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your website needs to be created or updated, however, you are unsure of what to look for in a web design firm. You begin your search online only to discover that many web design firms provide a variety of services.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not about creating a gorgeous website in today&#8217;s competitive market. Your website should cater to your clients&#8217; requirements and challenges. If it only appears good but does nothing for your visitors, they will leave, irritated that you have spent their time. Not only that, but they&#8217;ll also remember to avoid your website in the future.</p>
<p><strong>A website that provides no value to visitors will never contribute to your customer acquisition process.</strong></p>
<p>So, what are the things to check out for when hiring a web design company?</p>
<h2>10 Basic Services To Be Included In Any Website Design</h2>
<p>Generally speaking, the following essential services should always be included by your website design company:</p>
<ol>
<li>Creating a specified amount of web pages at a predetermined fee.</li>
<li>Custom Graphic Design.</li>
<li>On-page SEO.</li>
<li>Basic logo optimization.</li>
<li>Premium royalty-free stock images.</li>
<li>XML Sitemaps and Robots.txt</li>
<li>Embedding or linking of videos (If applicable).</li>
<li>Integrations of contact forms.</li>
<li>Site verification on Google Search Console and Microsoft Bing Webmaster Tools.</li>
<li>Professional Email Hosting.</li>
</ol>
<h2>What Additional Services Should You Look For?</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, most web design agencies just want to hurriedly deploy your website and move on to the next client.</p>
<p>If done well, the above-listed services should be enough in many cases, but what you want is a website that acts as a sales magnet year-in, year-out, isn&#8217;t it? Then you have to go the extra mile!</p>
<p><strong>With the following additional services, your website would certainly become a lead magnet:</strong></p>
<h3> 1. Email Subscriptions</h3>
<p>An email subscription is a feature on a website that allows users to sign up for updates such as newsletters by entering their email addresses in a form. Your email marketing strategy&#8217;s basic starting point is the integration of an email subscription form.</p>
<div id="attachment_14032" style="width: 1166px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-14032" class="size-full wp-image-14032" title="Email newsletter subscription form" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Email-newsletter-subscription-form.png" alt="Email newsletter subscription form" width="1156" height="580" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Email-newsletter-subscription-form.png 1156w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Email-newsletter-subscription-form-300x151.png 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Email-newsletter-subscription-form-1024x514.png 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Email-newsletter-subscription-form-768x385.png 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Email-newsletter-subscription-form-480x241.png 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1156px) 100vw, 1156px" /><p id="caption-attachment-14032" class="wp-caption-text">Email newsletter subscription form</p></div>
<h3>2. Content Development</h3>
<p>Content Development refers to the process of obtaining, organizing, and editing information for a targeted audience.</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t want to end up with a website designer that launches your website with a bunch of Lorem Ipsum dummy texts because they lack the skill or motivation to develop <a href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/">relevant content</a> for your website.</p>

<h3>3. Content Distribution and Promotion</h3>
<p>You need to develop a strategy that facilitates the sharing of your website content on various platforms, like adding social media sharing buttons.</p>
<h3>4. Live Chat Integration and Call Back Requests</h3>
<p>Live chat allows you to provide quicker responses to customer queries, handle problems more quickly, and reassure your customers that you&#8217;ll be there for them when they need you. This is a straightforward yet highly effective method of increasing customer service and brand loyalty.</p>
<p>With a live chat integration, your site visitors wouldn&#8217;t have to leave your website to contact you. They would also receive your responses in real-time.</p>
<p>Let your Customers request a callback and choose a schedule that is comfortable for them. This is very useful if your company serves aged or busy customers who do not always have the opportunity to call immediately or have the time to chat. Here is an example: <a href="https://branditechture.agency/schedule-a-call/">https://branditechture.agency/schedule-a-call/</a></p>
<h3>5. Inbound marketing strategy</h3>
<p>Inbound marketing focuses on enticing customers by providing relevant and helpful information and offering value at each stage of the buying process. <a href="https://branditechture.agency/why-your-small-business-should-blog/">Blogs</a>, search engines, and social media are all channels for potential clients to find you.</p>

<h3>6. Analytics &amp; Insights</h3>
<p>There is no way to know how well your efforts and strategy are working without tracking and analytics. Therefore integrating a tracking tool like Google Analytics or Microsoft Clarity becomes imperative. With these tools, you can see the following user information:</p>
<ul>
<li>Geographic location &amp; Language</li>
<li>Age, Gender</li>
<li>Time of visit, pages visited, and time spent on each page of the webpages</li>
<li>Realtime stats of how many people are currently online on your website and what pages they are viewing</li>
<li>User journeys on your website from entry to exit</li>
<li>Search queries</li>
<li>Referring site details (such as the website a user came through to arrive at yours)</li>
<li>Type of web browser</li>
<li>Type of operating system (OS)</li>
<li>Specs of device used (e.g device type, screen size, resolution, e.t.c)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>🎉 BONUS:</strong> If you use WordPress, read <a class="extlink" href="https://support.branditechture.agency/docs/how-to-connect-your-website-to-google-analytics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this guide</a> on our client support website to learn how to integrate Google Analytics into your blog.</p>
<h2>Personal Traits to Look Out For In A Web Developer</h2>
<p>Whether you work directly with a freelance website developer or a full-service design agency, you&#8217;d still need to work with individuals. This is why it&#8217;s a great idea to look out for personal characteristics before fully committing yourself to work with such persons. Fundamentally, here are some important personal qualities to check out for in a website developer:</p>
<ol>
<li>Takes the time to understand your business and pain points.</li>
<li>Possesses the ability to examine your business and create <a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-use-brand-clarity-to-improve-your-marketing-message/">messaging</a> that resonates with your ideal customers.</li>
<li>Having the knowledge and experience to create and implement a marketing strategy that will work for you.</li>
<li>Caring about your success as much as you do.</li>
</ol>
<p>Your company deserves a technical partner who will go above and beyond to improve your brand, preserve or enhance your reputation, consider your goal and identity, and be <a href="https://branditechture.agency/why-your-startup-needs-a-brand-champion/">involved</a> in the long-term success of your company.</p>
<h2>Best Practices for Web Design Agencies</h2>
<p>A decent procedure for web design agencies to follow in order to achieve your expectations is as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>Consultation to learn about your specific requirements, ideas, and mission, as well as your website&#8217;s short and long-term goals.</li>
<li>Using tools like HubSpot and Google Analytics, analyze your website for critical insights from the data, and put together a cohesive lead generation strategy.</li>
<li>A unique website design with carefully developed messaging and user experience.</li>
<li>Follow-up and maintenance of the project&#8217;s site and assets, with detailed information on storage, privacy, and security provided throughout the process.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Don&#8217;t put your faith in a website designer just because they showed you a flashy portfolio. Instead, dig deeper and see what their agency has delivered in terms of results for their past clients.</p>
<p>In a sea of online websites, businesses need to recognize now, more than ever, that success requires a lot more than just establishing a website.</p>
<p>You will boost your business&#8217;s chances of success and future growth by partnering with an agency that knows that developing your website is just the beginning, and that what happens afterwards to bring qualified visitors to your website is where the main value lies.</p>
<hr />
<p>Need a compelling website for your business? <a href="https://branditechture.agency/lets-build-your-website/">Let&#8217;s build your website.</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/10-basic-services-to-be-included-in-any-website-design/">10 Basic Services To Be Included In Any Website Design</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/10-basic-services-to-be-included-in-any-website-design/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
