<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Chisom Nnachi &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/author/chisomnnachi90gmail-com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Chisom Nnachi &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Personal Brand or Corporate Brand; How To Choose.</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chisom Nnachi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=8197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coming to a final decision of how to professionally present oneself to the world can prove to be a confusing task. You certainly have multiple questions running through your mind and seeking clear answers; Should I have a personal brand? Do I need a personal brand? What’s the difference between a personal brand and a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/">Personal Brand or Corporate Brand; How To Choose.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coming to a final decision of how to professionally present oneself to the world can prove to be a confusing task. <span style="font-weight: 400;">You certainly have multiple questions running through your mind and seeking clear answers; Should I have a personal brand? Do I need a personal brand? What’s the difference between a personal brand and a corporate brand?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Until these questions are properly addressed, you will continue to find it difficult to define your public identity.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most individuals believe that a corporate brand works better than a personal brand and you must keep your identity off your business. This makes it hard to decide which one to choose.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the long argument of <strong>personal brand vs corporate brand</strong> boils down to which type of branding works well for your future marketing plans and structure.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This article is carefully curated to offer you a detailed guideline on setting up your brand and choosing between a personal brand or a corporate brand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Initially, branding processes entail all representations that build or portray a company. These days, the nature of digital marketing has introduced the use of personal identity for official representations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The definition of a brand has far evolved beyond the stables of a corporate organization to common positions like social media influencers and digital marketers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevertheless, there are certain factors to consider.</span></p>
<h2>Personal brand</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A personal brand is built around your identity and personality. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This also includes your lifestyle, interests, and endeavours. Personal brands are built around your name and persona. This means your business is branded with your name (or something very related e.g your nickname).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal branding attributes the brand to <strong>an individual,</strong> rather than a corporate enterprise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This gives individuals the opportunity of building authority around their niche market. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People that choose the path of personal branding present themselves as a go-to source for solutions and an expert in their career path. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This includes the coordinated effort of your skills, experience, and authenticity.</span></p>
<h2>Corporate brand</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate branding on the other hand builds an identity around your business enterprise. <strong>This presents your brand as a structured organization,</strong> with defined work ethics, dedicated customer-care services, and a catalogue of products and services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate branding portrays you as just a member of a larger corporate organization (which may also be your brand.)</span></p>
<p>With a <span style="font-weight: 400;">corporate </span>brand, public relations, brand communications, client onboarding processes are characteristically kept formal. Corporate brands are also known for things like Official Statements, Press Releases, Annual Reports e.tc.</p>
<p><strong>Read Also: <a href="https://branditechture.agency/10-common-branding-mistakes-you-must-avoid/" title="10 Common Branding Mistakes You Must Avoid" data-schema-attribute="" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10 Common Branding Mistakes You Must Avoid</a></strong></p>
<h2>Should I have a Personal Brand?</h2>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-9419" title="Personal Brand or Corporate Brand" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1024x683.jpg" alt="Personal Brand or Corporate Brand" width="940" height="627" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-480x320.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand-1320x880.jpg 1320w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Personal-Brand-or-Corporate-Brand.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiple factors determine if you should have a personal brand. These factors cut across what you wish to achieve with your identity and if it is necessary to put out yourself as an individual brand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the beginning of your decisions for personal branding lies in understanding personal branding and why it is important for your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are few reasons why you should have a personal brand.</span></p>
<h3>· Personal brands are adaptive</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal brands are developed to easily adapt to trends and updates. You can easily change your product line and service offerings without posing any threat to your brand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3>· Personal brands are entrepreneurial</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal brands are usually portrayed as a one-man business. This makes personal branding a nice option for career paths that require individual establishment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This includes but not limited to being an author, graphic designer, painter, coach, or public speaker. If you are considering setting your business in the one-man industry field, personal branding is a better option.</span></p>
<h2>Differences</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal branding offers the opportunity to market your services with your own personalized identity. However, depending on the context in which your personal brand name is found, it is still very possible for a prospective client to be unable to associate your name with your products or services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although business branding offers a clearer view of your business, it does not offer a flexible structure.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p><strong>Read Also:  <a href="https://branditechture.agency/8-ways-your-small-business-can-benefit-from-branding/">8 Ways Your Small Business Can Benefit From Branding</a> </strong></p>
<h2>How To Choose</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are three factors to consider when choosing between a personal brand and a business brand;</span></p>
<h4>· Type of business<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike business brands, personal brands are great options for freelancers.</span></p>
<h4>· Size of business</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You might have the option of setting up a large-scale business with different managerial arms. This makes it important to portray your business as an organization other than a personal representation of your lifestyle.</span></p>
<h4>· Business Interest</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your business line and area of specialization should help you determine whether to go for a personal brand or a business brand. Your business can pose the approach of a startup building it around yourself alone could limit your reach and expansion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This entails that before choosing between a business brand or a personal brand, you must be able to decide what your business stands for, and areas you wish to explore in the business economy.</span></p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you decide to go for a personal brand or a business brand, you must stick to authenticity and value.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Great brands are built on the level of services they offer, and how wide they spread the word about what do.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This means whatever type of branding you wish to explore, visibility, authenticity, and quality assurance should be your yardstick for growth.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/">Personal Brand or Corporate Brand; How To Choose.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/personal-or-corporate-branding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
