<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Content Writing &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/category/content-writing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 15:40:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Content Writing &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What is &#8220;Copy&#8221; in Content Marketing Terms?</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You may have come across the word &#8220;copy&#8221; in a different context before, but in content marketing, &#8220;copy&#8221; refers to the text that is used to communicate a message to an audience. The word, &#8220;Copy&#8221; can be used to refer to anything from blog posts and articles to sales pages and product descriptions. The goal [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/">What is &#8220;Copy&#8221; in Content Marketing Terms?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You may have come across the word &#8220;copy&#8221; in a different context before, but in <a href="https://branditechture.agency/20-content-generation-ideas-for-your-brands-marketing/">content marketing</a>, &#8220;copy&#8221; refers to the text that is used to communicate a message to an audience.</p>
<p>The word, &#8220;Copy&#8221; can be used to refer to anything from blog posts and articles to sales pages and product descriptions. The goal of copy in content marketing is to inform, educate, or persuade the reader to take a specific action, such as purchasing a product or signing up for a newsletter.</p>
<p>Copywriting is the act of creating this written content, and a person who specializes in this type of writing is called a copywriter.</p>
<h3>What is the Difference between copywriting and content writing?</h3>
<p>Copywriting and <a href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/">content writing</a> are similar in that they both involve creating written content, but they have some key differences.</p>
<p>Copywriting is focused on creating persuasive, sales-oriented text that is designed to get the reader to take a specific action, such as purchasing a product or signing up for a service. Content writing, on the other hand, is focused on creating informative and engaging text that provides value to the reader.</p>
<p>Content writing is often used to support the goals of a content marketing strategy by providing useful information to the reader and building trust and credibility for the brand.</p>
<h3>What are the types of copy we have in marketing?</h3>
<p>There are many different types of copy used in marketing. Some examples include:</p>
<ol>
<li>Sales copy: This type of copy is used to persuade the reader to make a purchase. It typically includes a highlight of the benefits of the product or service being sold, and a strong call-to-action <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-amazing-microcopy-tips-for-ux-designers/">microcopy</a> to nudge the reader to make a purchase.</li>
<li>Landing page copy: This type of copy is used on a website&#8217;s landing page, which is the first page a visitor sees when they arrive on the site. It is designed to grab the reader&#8217;s attention and convince them to take a specific action, such as filling out a form or making a purchase.</li>
<li>Email copy: This type of copy is used in email marketing campaigns. It is designed to engage the reader and encourage them to take a specific action, such as clicking a link or making a purchase.</li>
<li>Social media copy: This type of copy is used on social media platforms to engage followers and promote products or services. It is often concise and attention-grabbing, and may include hashtags and links to relevant content.</li>
<li>Blog post copy: This type of copy is used in blog posts and articles. It is designed to inform and educate the reader and may include links to other resources or calls-to-action.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are just a few examples of the many types of copy used in marketing. The specific type of copy that is used will depend on the goals of the marketing campaign and the target audience.</p>
<h3>What are the features of an effective copy?</h3>
<p>An effective copy should have several key features, including:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>A clear and compelling message:</strong> The copy should have a clear and concise message that is easy for the reader to understand. It should convey the value of the product or service being offered and convince the reader to take action.</li>
<li><strong>A strong call-to-action:</strong> The copy should include a strong call-to-action that tells the reader exactly what they should do next. This could be to make a purchase, sign up for a newsletter, or follow the business on social media.</li>
<li><strong>Relevance to the target audience:</strong> The copy should be relevant to the target audience and address their needs and concerns. By understanding the audience&#8217;s pain points and interests, businesses can create copy that resonates with them and motivates them to take action.</li>
<li><strong>Use of persuasive techniques:</strong> The copy should use persuasive techniques, such as testimonials, social proof, and scarcity, to convince the reader to take action. By leveraging these techniques, businesses can create copy that is more effective at persuading the reader.</li>
<li><strong>Proper grammar and spelling:</strong> The copy should be well-written, with proper grammar and spelling. This helps to ensure that the message is clear and easy to understand, and it helps to build trust and credibility with the reader.</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, an effective copy should be clear, concise, persuasive, and relevant to the target audience. By incorporating these features, businesses can create copy that is more effective at achieving their marketing goals.</p>
<h3>What are the benefits of effective copy?</h3>
<p>Effective copy has many benefits, both for the business and for the audience. Some of the key benefits of effective copy include:</p>
<p><strong>Increased sales:</strong> Effective copy is designed to persuade the reader to take a specific action, such as making a purchase. By creating compelling and persuasive copy, businesses can increase their sales and revenue.</p>
<p><strong>Improved customer engagement:</strong> Good copy is engaging and interesting, which can help to keep the reader&#8217;s attention and encourage them to take action. By providing valuable and interesting information, businesses can build trust and credibility with their audience.</p>
<p><strong>Increased website traffic:</strong> Effective copy can help to drive more traffic to a business&#8217;s website. This can be achieved through search engine optimization (SEO) techniques, such as using relevant keywords, or through social media marketing and email marketing campaigns.</p>
<p><strong>Better brand awareness:</strong> Effective copy can help to improve a business&#8217;s brand awareness. By creating consistent and compelling messaging, businesses can build their brand and <a href="https://branditechture.agency/how-to-build-a-unique-brand/">differentiate themselves from their competitors</a>.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Effective copy can be a powerful tool for your business. It can help you to increase sales, improve customer engagement, drive website traffic, and build brand awareness. Good copywriting practices will increase the overall value of your website.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading! If you have questions, kindly use the comment section below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/">What is &#8220;Copy&#8221; in Content Marketing Terms?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/what-is-copy-in-content-marketing-terms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Practices for Writing Website Content</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/web-writing-best-practices/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/web-writing-best-practices/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=13024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>People read differently online, but everyone wants the web copywriter (or content writer) to get to the point quickly and to have clear lines of thought that are easy to follow. The reader hates getting lost in a desert of texts. Readers love to be taken by the hand and guided through fluent text that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/web-writing-best-practices/">Best Practices for Writing Website Content</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span>People read differently online, but everyone wants the web copywriter (or content writer) to get to the point quickly and to have clear lines of thought that are easy to follow.</span></p>
<p><span>The reader hates getting lost in a<em><strong> desert of texts</strong></em>. Readers love to be taken by the hand and guided through fluent text that offers them a solution to a problem they are currently dealing with.</span></p>
<p><span>The copywriter&#8217;s first step is therefore to outline exactly what should be said and how the arguments build on/against each other.</span></p>
<p><span>If the content of your web text is of no value to the reader, any optimization of the presentation is pointless.</span></p>
<p><span>Value in this context means a tip, an impulse or simply the feeling that you have just consumed content that arouses your curiosity and makes you want to try a certain product or service.</span></p>

<h2><span>You must have a clear goal</span></h2>
<p><span>Before you write: think about what you want your text to achieve. And then you work towards that goal.</span></p>
<p><span>Put the arguments that build on each other in the form of an outline. In this way, you can immediately identify and iron out weak points.</span></p>
<p><span>The actual writing is a breeze later, you only need a few <strong>transitions</strong>. </span><span>Allocate 80% of your time to thinking and brainstorming, and 20% ​​of the time to writing, and you would immediately notice much better <a class="extlink" href="https://vwo.com/blog/conversion-marketing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>conversions</strong></a>.  </span></p>
<h2><span>Never write for yourself, write for the reader</span></h2>
<p><span>The most important trick for successful copywriting for websites is putting yourself in the reader&#8217;s shoes and formulating everything from their point of view.</span></p>
<p><span>So you should not be saying  <strong>&#8220;We are the specialists for bespoke design of modern living spaces&#8221;.</strong></span></p>
<p><span>It is better to say <strong>“let us transform your four walls into your personal dream home”.</strong></span></p>
<p><span>It&#8217;s not about you and how great you and your company are. It&#8217;s about connecting to your reader and how you can help them improve their lives.</span></p>

<h2><span>The entry into the web text: a strong headline</span></h2>
<p><span>The headline is the all-important element of a web text.</span></p>
<p><span>It decides whether to read or to go straight back to the list with the search results.</span></p>
<p><span>Good web copywriters, therefore, spend a long time writing a headline.</span></p>
<p><span>Unfortunately, the topic has been hyped a little too much recently. As a result, almost everyone feels like implementing the 10 or 99 tips for the best headlines.</span></p>
<p><span>So your best bet is to do headings that are a little different. So that you don&#8217;t get lost in the uniform mass of standard headings.</span></p>
<h2><span>The attractive appetizer: a compelling teaser</span></h2>
<p><span>The teaser is the short intro text at the beginning of an article.</span></p>
<p><span>A teaser briefly outlines what the reader can expect and what he or she will take away from the article.</span></p>
<p><span>Only if the reader recognizes a benefit for himself in the teaser will he continue reading the text.</span></p>
<h2><span>The temptation to continue reading: inspiring subheadings</span></h2>
<p><span>Subheadings give the eye an anchor and enable fast readers to skim through web texts better.</span></p>
<p><span>Text with subheadings is always more inviting than a wall of letters.</span></p>
<p><span>In addition, with cleverly chosen subheadings, it is not necessary to leave the entire text. This is how you grasp the basic content.</span></p>
<h2><span>Write easily consumable texts</span></h2>
<p><span>Avoid long, complicated sentences, unclear trains of thought, foreign words that should prove your education.</span></p>
<p><span>The work that you do in advance with the structure of the text, the reader does not have later.</span></p>
<p><span>If texts are too complicated to not invite to read, readers will drop out and leave your website.</span></p>
<p><span>Simple trick: It&#8217;s best to write the way you speak. That automatically makes texts better.</span></p>
<p><span>Because most of them speak very differently than they write. And are much more convincing.</span></p>
<p><span>So in the future, write the way you would talk to someone sitting across from you.</span></p>
<p><span>If this is difficult for you: speak your text, record it and type it up.</span></p>
<p><span>There are professional copywriters who, for this reason, do not write their texts with the keyboard, but rather dictate them into a speech recognition system.</span></p>
<p><span>And another tip that improves every text: Then read the text to yourself or, even better, to someone else. Then it is immediately noticeable whether your words are linguistically convincing or whether they are rather stiff writing.</span></p>

<h2><span>Simplification is the first step to success</span></h2>
<p><span>Anyone who expresses things in a complicated way has not done his job as a copywriter and passes it on to his readers. Not smart.</span></p>
<p><span>If you want to convince with copywriting, keep things simple. Even complicated things don&#8217;t have to be difficult to read. This is not only proven by the “broadcast with the mouse”.</span></p>
<h2><span>Forget what you learned about writing in school and university</span></h2>
<p><span>Most people learned how to write during their studies or at work so they often find it difficult to create boundaries between writing web copy and formal communication. </span><span>The result? An<em> endless desert</em> of long-winded, stiff, excessively formal texts, which is also full of technical terms and big grammar, but boring and meaningless to the reader.</span><span></span></p>
<p><span><strong>The academic writing that you learn at university is poison for successful websites.</strong> It is also best to forget many of the rules from school.</span></p>
<p><span>Don&#8217;t use only one line in a paragraph? Don&#8217;t start sentences with &#8220;and&#8221;? Never add a comma before &#8220;but&#8221;? &#8230;Meh meh meh.  Let me tell you this; Just do whatever makes your text more readable and your thoughts clearer.</span></p>
<h2><span>A lot of text is not good text</span></h2>
<p><span>Also at school and university, we are taught that you have to write a lot to get good grades.</span></p>
<p><span>An essay on half a page? Bad.</span></p>
<p><span>A thesis with only 25 pages? Even worse.</span></p>
<p><span>Forget all that.</span></p>
<p><span>Website copy is not about producing quantity. It&#8217;s about conveying content quickly and to the point.</span></p>
<p><span>Really good texts are therefore formulated briefly. So that you can&#8217;t leave out a word and the thought is still conveyed very clearly.</span></p>
<p><span>Make it a habit to radically shorten any webpage text before it is published. Most of the time it gets better.</span></p>
<h2><span>Foreign words and technical terms are not necessary to work as an expert</span></h2>
<p><span>Don&#8217;t use the language that you think should be used in your industry. Most of the time it&#8217;s just a lot of hot air.</span></p>
<p><span>Real experts do not need to use language to differentiate themselves or to have to rise above others. You are able to say something in perfectly normal terms &#8211; so that the target audience can understand it.</span></p>
<p><span>That is what makes them real experts.</span></p>
<h2><span>Talk to the readers</span></h2>
<p><span>Addressing readers personally works very well on websites.</span></p>
<p><span>This is because we all like to deal with our own lives and how we can make them more enjoyable.</span></p>
<p><span>Avoidance of getting too close with the reader is not a sign of professional website copy, and even large companies and corporate bodies have realized that.</span></p>
<p><span>The closer your texts are to the target group, the more likely you will be successful on the Internet.</span></p>
<h2><span>Make your texts do the attraction</span></h2>
<p><span>Many also learned about these brutal walls of text at the university. At that time there was a deduction for too many paragraphs or blank lines, which has an impact on life.</span></p>
<p><span>No one voluntarily struggles through such walls of text. Especially not on a screen.</span></p>
<p><span>Texts need space to be effective.</span></p>
<p><span>So make a </span><strong><span>lot of</span></strong><span> paragraphs. After five or six lines at the latest.</span></p>
<p><span>Use subheadings.</span></p>
<p><span>Use a font size large enough to be comfortable to read.</span></p>
<p><span>Make sure there is enough line spacing. Texts need this white space to invite reading.</span></p>
<p><span>Don&#8217;t make lines too long. Especially in the case of responsive websites that adapt to window sizes, it must be prevented that endless lines are created when the window is enlarged, which is no longer easy to read.</span></p>
<h2><span>Do not try to appear different from who you are</span></h2>
<p><span>Small, young companies like to try to make themselves older and bigger in their website texts in order to appear more professional.</span></p>
<p><span>Better leave that. </span></p>
<p><span>First, it won&#8217;t take so much time to find out that you are fake, which ultimately results in disappointment. Second, since you have raised the expectations of your prospective clients, you must, at all times give them something better than what they have tasted or experienced somewhere before.</span></p>
<p><span>So, be honest, write as you are, and not what you think a successful company has to be.</span></p>
<h2><span>Don&#8217;t accept time pressure</span></h2>
<p><span>A good website copy takes time.</span></p>
<p><span>You can&#8217;t always write everything in 30 minutes, no matter how small. So leave it behind for now. Sleep on it. And look again the next day. You will realize that you can write better that way.</span></p>
<h2><span>Give your web texts a real ending</span></h2>
<p><span>It is a shame when really good content just gushes out at the end.</span></p>
<p><span>It is better to give the reader a really strong, inspiring thought that summarizes what has been read before.</span></p>
<p><span>If you can&#8217;t think of anything like that, even a call-to-action or a call to ask questions is better than ending without an end.</span></p>
<p><span>Therefore, if you are not sure about how good the texts on your business website are, just send me a message via <strong>yusuf[at]branditechture.agency</strong> or reach me on the phone via <a href="tel:+2349034834608"><strong>+234 903 483 4608</strong></a>, and I will help you have a look. Doesn&#8217;t cost anything.</span></p>
<p>Please, share this article if you enjoyed reading my article.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/web-writing-best-practices/">Best Practices for Writing Website Content</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/web-writing-best-practices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Content for A Website? Read These Golden Tips!</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=13000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Do you have an upcoming website project and wish to know how to write compelling website content? You have come to the right place! Web design is much more than making a website look &#8220;flashy&#8221; or &#8220;catchy&#8221;, as some would call it. Ultimately, it is the texts and information on websites that determines whether visitors [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/">Writing Content for A Website? Read These Golden Tips!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Do you have an upcoming website project and wish to know how to write compelling website content? You have come to the right place!</div>
<div>
<hr />
</div>
<p>Web design is much more than making a website look &#8220;flashy&#8221; or &#8220;catchy&#8221;, as some would call it. Ultimately, it is the texts and information on websites that determines whether visitors become customers. Bad if nobody likes to read your texts and worse if no one could really comprehend the value proposition of your website.</p>
<p>So how do you write compelling content for a website?</p>
<p><b>First off, how does website writing compare with art?</b></p>
<p>Just as craftsmen need a blueprint from an architect, a website also needs structure.</p>
<p>If you are planning a new website or a relaunch for an existing website, then web design should not be the first consideration — It is important that a content strategy and conception are first gotten right.</p>
<p>People tend to put design first, but in reality, things are different; The layout and navigation of a website are more important than the content it is supposed to convey.</p>
<p>Any website built without respect to content and content structure would struggle to compete. If you are however lucky to work with a good web designer or design agency, then you will automatically be more successful than the rest.</p>
<p>Here is the simple, honest truth; <strong>First think about the goals and content of your website before thinking about the appearance.</strong></p>

<h2>“Help me make it pop!” Is not always the best idea</h2>
<p>If you want to build a website that can attract customers, it is important that you design it with the customer in mind.</p>
<p>Simply ordering &#8220;a beautiful website&#8221; from the web designer will not get you any further.</p>
<p>Because a pretty design and chic pictures look good, but beyond that, they do not bring any performance benefit if they do not contribute to an <a href="https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/">overall concept for the website</a>.</p>
<p>After all, you want to do marketing and not colourful pictures.</p>
<p>The communication concept, from which the concept for your online presence is derived, develops from your marketing concept. And the entire content of your website has to be subordinate to this.</p>
<p>Then everything comes up almost automatically. Even creating the website texts.</p>

<h2>Think first, then write</h2>
<p>At the beginning of the creation of a homepage, there is the question: What does the potential customer need and what can you offer them?</p>
<p>You should take your time for this step. After all, this is about the important basis for everything that follows.</p>
<p>All the necessary website content is derived from the conception of your online presence. In most cases, the structure of the website is also obvious. And the menu items and sub-items are also logically accessible.</p>
<p>In this phase, you or your copywriter for the website should already put together a rough table of contents for each planned subpage. This helps to assess the subsequent amounts of text and any call-to-action elements.</p>
<h2>Creating websites starts with the content</h2>
<p>It is important that in the conception phase of your website you do not initially speak to purely graphics-oriented web designers and also not to technicians.</p>
<p>Because graphics and technology are not the most important topics at the beginning.</p>
<p>In the beginning, sit down exclusively with highly conceptual web professionals and develop the basics of the content.</p>
<p>Good full-service <a href="https://branditechture.agency/">web design agencies</a> will make this possible. Or you can go straight to a specialist website copywriter.</p>

<h2>Don&#8217;t forget to do keyword research</h2>
<p>Keyword research is a crucial part of<a href="https://branditechture.agency/create-website-concept/"> web conception</a>. Unfortunately for some, it is often only done at the very end or forgotten.</p>
<p>There is no point determining keywords afterwards and using them to &#8220;optimize&#8221; a finished website. It is like dinning with a salt shaker. As a reference, it is often better to add salt your food during the cooking process than to do it after the food is cooked and served. Do you understand?</p>
<p>You have to determine your search terms in the conception phase so that they are available when you start writing the web texts.</p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t mean you end up writing for search engines like Google. You write specifically for the searches your prospects use to find answers to pressing problems on Google.</p>
<h2>Have texts written for the website or write it yourself?</h2>
<p>Once the concept is in place, there are two options for creating the content for your website: You can either write the content yourself or you can contract the task to a copywriter.</p>
<p>Having your website copy and <a href="https://branditechture.agency/7-amazing-microcopy-tips-for-ux-designers/">microcopy</a> written by a copywriter skilled in developing content for websites is an all-round carefree solution.</p>
<p>On the other hand, creating your own website texts yourself can be useful if a lot of your very special knowledge has to flow into the texts.</p>
<p>There is also a mixed method that I often use: I first let customers write texts and then revise them in order to optimize them for the Internet. This reduces the client&#8217;s copywriting costs whilst still resulting in the highest quality of the texts on their website.</p>
<p>Whatever you decide to do, only use highly relevant and purposeful texts on your website. In other words, make sure your texts contribute to your website&#8217;s goals.</p>

<h2>Don&#8217;t write yourself if you have no idea</h2>
<p>The best website copy comes from those who are really deep into a topic.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you are not so fit on a topic yourself, it is preferable to have the appropriate employees or other specialists <a href="https://branditechture.agency/start-a-project/">write to you.</a></p>
<p>Your job comes afterwards: Check whether the content is really written for the target group and have corrections carried out if necessary.</p>
<hr />
<p>Writing the content for a website can be an exciting task, but it could quickly become a chore if you aren&#8217;t built for it. So, If you would like us to help you write or rewrite your website&#8217;s content, click <strong><a href="https://branditechture.agency/start-a-project/">HERE</a> </strong>and select <strong>Website Content Development</strong> in the<em> Project Type</em> field.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/">Writing Content for A Website? Read These Golden Tips!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Big Data in Content Writing</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/the-importance-of-big-data-in-content-writing/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/the-importance-of-big-data-in-content-writing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 22:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=14827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that the majority of the data you consume today was created in the last two years? Within the next two years, roughly 1.7 megabytes of data will be generated for every human being on the planet every second. That&#8217;s fantastic news for content writers that use enormous volumes of data (known as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/the-importance-of-big-data-in-content-writing/">The Importance of Big Data in Content Writing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that the majority of the data you consume today was created in the last two years? Within the next two years, roughly 1.7 megabytes of data will be generated for every human being on the planet every second. That&#8217;s fantastic news for content writers that use enormous volumes of data (known as Big Data) to create engaging content.</p>
<p>When your site&#8217;s traffic grows as a result of relevant content, new advertising opportunities open up. Content writers, in turn, contribute to this vast source of information.</p>
<h2>What is Big Data?</h2>
<p>Big Data is a large collection of data that is rapidly growing in volume. It&#8217;s a data set that&#8217;s so large and complex that no traditional data management tools can effectively store or process it. Big data is similar to regular data, except that it is much larger and keeps growing at an exponential pace.</p>
<h2>How does Big Data impact content writing?</h2>
<p>When Big Data presents the numbers, it&#8217;s very easy for content writers to get tempted to employ means with which can make the algorithms increase their impressions and click-through rates rather than creating amazing content that humans love to read (which increases traffic quality and boosts CTR).</p>
<p>The ultimate goal of any content writing campaign is to provide relevant and appealing information while advertising a product or service. But is it that simple? Unfortunately, the answer is No.</p>
<p>Original content is increasingly getting difficult to come by in the majority of cases, but in spite of that, Big Data can still help generate unique topics for content writing, and here is how;</p>
<h3>1. Comparing Stats Can Give Rise to New Information</h3>
<p>Big data refers to information that can be analysed.</p>
<p>For example, the online dating service <em>OKCupid.com</em> analysed five years of data to examine the relationship between race and attraction, as well as men and women&#8217;s dating preferences and how they have changed over time. The information was useful for further study, and it was a decent attempt to understand users&#8217; preferences.</p>
<p>Everything checks out in terms of content: it presented new (arguably intriguing) information, opened up new conversations on race preference in dating, and still allowed them to market their service.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4ExBmXTMZM"><p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/">Writing Content for A Website? Read These Golden Tips!</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Writing Content for A Website? Read These Golden Tips!&#8221; &#8212; Branditechture" src="https://branditechture.agency/writing-content-for-a-website-read-these-golden-tips/embed/#?secret=4maL0mG4xI#?secret=4ExBmXTMZM" data-secret="4ExBmXTMZM" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<h3>2. You can use Big Data to figure out which audiences to target with your content.</h3>
<p>When you&#8217;ve found your voice as a content writer, you may use demographics like age, gender, ethnicity, employment status, education, income, geography, and interests to segment your target audience. With this knowledge, the content you create functions as a two-way street for both you and the consumer.</p>
<p>You will be able to better understand and respond to your customers&#8217; demands, while your target consumers will be introduced to your products or services and will be more inclined to respond to you than if your articles were sent to just anyone.</p>
<h3>3. Big Data Assists in the Development of User Personas</h3>
<p>User personas are archetypal users whose aims and traits mirror and represent that of a larger group of people. A persona is usually given as a virtual user profile, with data like habits, interests behavioural patterns, goals, talents, attitudes, and other background information</p>
<p>Content Writers typically create user persona templates that include a few fictional personal details to make the persona a realistic character.</p>
<p>Large amounts of data may benefit your <a class="extlink" href="https://support.branditechture.agency/docs/seo-checklist-how-we-perform-seo-on-your-website/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">site&#8217;s SEO</a>, but keep in mind that the material you provide isn&#8217;t for computers – it&#8217;s for humans.</p>
<p>You can utilise statistics to develop a profile of your target audience, and transforming data into a person can help you communicate more clearly with your audience.</p>
<h3>4. Big Data Analysis Leads to New Insights</h3>
<p>Writing content is difficult in and of itself, but it becomes even more difficult when you try to make it interactive for your viewers. Because data comes from three main sources on the internet (streaming, social media, and publically available sources), soliciting input or comment from your readers can help you gather additional data and perhaps spark new content ideas while staying true to your content marketing objectives.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Kv5IZyPtML"><p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/20-content-generation-ideas-for-your-brands-marketing/">20 Content-Generation Ideas for Your Brand&#8217;s Marketing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;20 Content-Generation Ideas for Your Brand&#8217;s Marketing&#8221; &#8212; Branditechture" src="https://branditechture.agency/20-content-generation-ideas-for-your-brands-marketing/embed/#?secret=oghLPswlIM#?secret=Kv5IZyPtML" data-secret="Kv5IZyPtML" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>For better or worse, Big Data analysis has altered the way we get information. However, we can be certain that this aids marketers in content creation.</p>
<p>We offer impactful content research and writing services. So, if you want to leverage content writing but are unsure how to make it work for your business, start <em><strong><a href="https://branditechture.agency/start-a-project/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HERE.</a></strong></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/the-importance-of-big-data-in-content-writing/">The Importance of Big Data in Content Writing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/the-importance-of-big-data-in-content-writing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
