<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Recruitment &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/category/recruitment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 05:45:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Recruitment &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What Comes Next After Getting Applicants For Your Job Offer?</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/what-comes-next-after-getting-applicants-for-your-job-offer/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/what-comes-next-after-getting-applicants-for-your-job-offer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yusuf Odukoya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 05:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recruitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[applicants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[candidates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruitment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=13908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Many recruiters believe that finding qualified candidates is the most difficult part of the recruitment process. While it may be challenging, it is merely the beginning of a critical business process. Even once candidates have been shortlisted, recruiters must maintain the same level of effort and drive throughout the recruitment process. Many experts consider recruitment to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-comes-next-after-getting-applicants-for-your-job-offer/">What Comes Next After Getting Applicants For Your Job Offer?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many recruiters believe that finding qualified candidates is the most difficult part of the recruitment process. While it may be challenging, it is merely the beginning of a critical business process. Even once candidates have been shortlisted, recruiters must maintain the same level of effort and drive throughout the recruitment process. Many experts consider recruitment to be a multi-stage process, with obtaining applicants being only the first step.</p>

<p><a href="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1915345.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-13916 size-full" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1915345.jpg" alt="Employment Application" width="1280" height="853" title="What Comes Next After Getting Applicants For Your Job Offer? 2" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1915345.jpg 1280w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1915345-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1915345-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1915345-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1915345-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /></a></p>
<div id="hs_cos_wrapper_post_body">
<h2></h2>
<h2>Why Is Recruitment Important?</h2>
<p>For firms to find suitable individuals, the recruitment process is critical. Employers must maximize their recruiting methods, especially in today&#8217;s applicant-driven market. Because so many companies are looking for skilled people, their recruiting processes must be optimized to appeal to potential employees.</p>
<p>To achieve so, they must ensure that their entire recruitment process, from beginning to end, runs well. It&#8217;s critical to optimize this process not only to get the finest applicants, but also to improve the candidate experience in general.</p>
<p>When people think about the recruitment process, they typically just contemplate recruiting individuals &#8211; that is, getting them to apply to your organization. In actuality, the recruitment process is significantly more involved, with actual recruitment being only the second of<strong> seven steps.</strong> As a result, you must understand and follow all seven processes to guarantee that you are executing a thorough and strong recruitment process.</p>
<ol>
<li aria-level="1">Define Your Ideal Candidate</li>
<li aria-level="1">Attract And Source Candidates</li>
<li aria-level="1">Shortlist Applicants into Candidates</li>
<li aria-level="1">Screen Shortlisted Candidates</li>
<li aria-level="1">Interview</li>
<li aria-level="1">Check for Refrences</li>
<li aria-level="1">Onboarding and Introduction</li>
</ol>
<h2>The Process So Far</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;ve already received applications for an open position, you&#8217;re ready to go on to the next stage of the hiring process: finding and attracting talent. The step before this was defining your ideal candidate, in which you, as an employer, determines who the &#8220;ideal&#8221; candidate would be. This stage will be important later in the screening process, but for now, it will help you understand what attributes to look for in a potential applicant.</p>
<p>After that, you&#8217;ll want to attract your current applicants, which is where the candidate experience starts. Communication between recruiters and applicants is the most important component of this process. Waiting for recruiters to react, or not receiving a response at all, may be highly frustrating for applicants, and might turn them off to your brand. For this reason, it&#8217;s critical that you contact with applications as soon as possible, whether you&#8217;re delivering your regrets or getting ready for the next stage.</p>

<p>Many recruiters employ the use of recruitment automation solutions to streamline this process, ensuring that applicants have a positive experience right from the start. Such technologies are useful for speeding up responses and notifying applicants of any choices or scheduling changes. It&#8217;s time to move on to the next stage of the hiring process once you&#8217;ve started receiving applications.</p>
<h2>The Next Steps</h2>
<p>Let&#8217;s have a look at the remaining steps in the hiring process.</p>
<h3>Shortlist Applicants into Candidates</h3>
<p>Shortlisting  applicants into candidates is the third phase in the recruitment process. While it may appear that applicants and candidates are the same, there is a distinction to be made. Anyone who applies for a job at your organization qualifies as an applicant. Candidates, on the other hand, are potential employees with high hiring potential who are likely to advance to the interview stage.</p>
<p>How many applications progress from one phase to the next determines the number of applicants turned to candidates. Employees can use this information to improve the recruitment process by determining if there is an issue early on. There may be a problem if too many applicants drop out of the process before the screening and interview stages. It can also help you track the number of people that click on your job posting against how many people apply.</p>
<h3>Screen Shortlisted Candidates</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s time to start screening your candidates now that you have a clear list of applicants. This is a crucial step since it determines which prospects will advance to the interview stage of the hiring process. It is critical to be diversified in your selections and to set expectations when screening prospects.</p>
<p>It may be helpful to return to the ideal candidate you identified in step one and compare your real applicants to the profile you created during this phase &#8211; but keep in mind that no prospect will precisely fit your &#8220;ideal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Instead, make a list of must-have traits like experience and education, as well as nice-to-have qualities like personality. Using an automated pre-screening technology can assist speed up the process and ensure that candidates receive a quick answer, which is especially important if they are moving on to the next level: <strong>the interview stage.</strong></p>
<h3>Interview</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s time to start scheduling and conducting interviews after candidates have been reviewed. Scheduling for convenience and efficiency is an important part of this procedure. Most of the applicants you&#8217;ll be interviewing are likely to have additional interviews lined up. As a result, it&#8217;s vital to organize interviews as soon as possible and at times that are suitable for your prospects.</p>
<p>Calendar apps can assist recruiters in resolving schedule difficulties, particularly when multiple interviews are required. This can make it easier for both sides to match availability and speed up the scheduling process, ensuring that all candidates are accommodated. Providing slots during lunchtime or during regular working hours can also benefit folks who are already employed.</p>
<h3>Reference Check</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s a good idea to do a reference check when a candidate has finished the interview process and is a strong contender for the position. This technique can help you choose amongst numerous qualified individuals while also verifying their skills and experience.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s critical to be patient at this stage and not discard any possible applicants until they&#8217;ve accepted an offer with all criteria met and a start date set. If you don&#8217;t, you risk losing a candidate or having them fail pre-employment testing.</p>
<p>If that&#8217;s the case, you&#8217;ve missed out on some excellent backup candidates by preemptively rejecting others, as it&#8217;s extremely difficult to bring a candidate back once they&#8217;ve been dismissed. Keep in touch with possible candidates during the reference check process to let them know they&#8217;re still being considered until a new hiring is finalized.</p>
<h3>Onboarding &amp; Introduction</h3>
<p>Onboarding is the final step in the hiring process. When a candidate accepts an offer and becomes a new hire, you can begin onboarding them into their new role at your organization. This stage will be different for each company, but it is essential for a seamless transition.</p>
<p>A good onboarding program should include training and mentoring, as well as enough information and resources for new employees. This is critical in making new workers feel welcome at your organization, and it contributes considerably to long-term team member retention and job satisfaction.</p>
<h2>The importance of effective recruitment in the growth of a company cannot be overstated.</h2>
<p>The recruitment process is frequently seen as a mundane and time-consuming task when, in truth, it is a critical corporate function. Recruiting and retaining fresh talent is critical to your company&#8217;s future growth and success. In terms of future hiring attempts, the candidate experience in your recruitment process can make or break your firm. As a result, it&#8217;s critical that your hiring process be both speedy and well-planned.</p>
<p>You can ensure that candidates get a positive impression of your organization from the first interaction by carefully following the seven steps of the recruitment process. As a result, candidates will be eager to work for your company, whether they get the position right away or decide to apply again later. Your firm can easily obtain competitive talent with the correct recruitment tools and an organized recruitment process.</p>
<p style="font-size: 20px; font-weight: bold; text-align: center;"><span style="color: #003366;">Looking to hire a web developer and graphic designer in your organization?</span><br />
<span style="color: #003366;">Let&#8217;s help you take care of the recruitment process!</span></p>
<p><!--HubSpot Call-to-Action Code --><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-7901bc2e-727a-4df6-ad64-c36cd21ef6f6"><span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-7901bc2e-727a-4df6-ad64-c36cd21ef6f6" id="hs-cta-7901bc2e-727a-4df6-ad64-c36cd21ef6f6"></span></span></p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/what-comes-next-after-getting-applicants-for-your-job-offer/">What Comes Next After Getting Applicants For Your Job Offer?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/what-comes-next-after-getting-applicants-for-your-job-offer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
