<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Emmanuel &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<atom:link href="https://branditechture.agency/author/eashemiriogwa/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<description>Web × Design; Branditechture is an hybrid creative design agency.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 06:23:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-Favicon-2-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Emmanuel &#8211; Branditechture</title>
	<link>https://branditechture.agency/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Best Low-Maintenance Mercedes Benz Cars for Tech Guys</title>
		<link>https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/</link>
					<comments>https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emmanuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 05:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://branditechture.agency/?p=17679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s face it; Mercedes-Benz is never cheap to own. Still, there are options for young tech guys who want the 3-point star ride without spending a fortune on periodical maintenance. What determines the maintenance cost of a Benz car goes beyond mechanical or electrical fixes from time to time. You also want to put a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">Best Low-Maintenance Mercedes Benz Cars for Tech Guys</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s face it; Mercedes-Benz is never cheap to own. Still, there are options for young tech guys who want the 3-point star ride without spending a fortune on periodical maintenance.</p>
<p>What determines the maintenance cost of a Benz car goes beyond mechanical or electrical fixes from time to time. You also want to put a great deal of thought into the Model age, service history, and location where you will use the Benz.</p>
<p>As a young techie looking for the best low-maintenance Benz cars to buy, you want to steer clear from models like the Metris and Sprinter since their average yearly maintenance is around $2,500. That&#8217;s pretty high.</p>
<p>With my exposure to Mercedes Benz models over the years and a little more digging into a pool of data from giant auto review sites, I&#8217;ve put together a list of the seven classy Benz cars that are great for tech guys and economy-friendly to maintain in the long run.</p>
<p>This will help you in your buying decision to save your budget and your vehicle from major repair costs.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get right into it.</p>
<h2>List of Best Benz Cars with Low-Maintenance Costs for Techies</h2>
<p>As you probably know, the sticker price is one of many things you will pay to own a Benz car.</p>
<p>During my extensive discussion with various technicians who see cars getting fixed day in and day out, I discovered that many Benz owners spend more money maintaining Brakes, Oil changes, Spark plugs, Transmission service, Coolant service, Tires, and Smog checks.</p>
<p>Given the status of the German vehicle, these services could set you back thousands of dollars annually compared to regular Chinese cars.</p>
<p>Fortunately, you stand a chance to spend less on maintenance while enjoying Merc if you drive any of these models:</p>
<h3>1. 2010 Mercedes-Benz C350</h3>
<div id="attachment_17682" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17682" class="wp-image-17682 size-full" title="2010 Mercedes Benz C350" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350.jpg" alt="2010 Mercedes Benz C350" width="1200" height="675" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350.jpg 1200w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-768x432.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2010-Mercedes-Benz-C350-480x270.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17682" class="wp-caption-text">2010 Mercedes Benz C350. 📸: <em>CNET Roadshow</em></p></div>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/reliability/mercedes-benz/c350" rel="noopener">Repairpal&#8217;s reliability rating</a> of the 2010 Mercedes-Benz C350 estimates average annual maintenance costs to be $720, influenced by the age, mileage, and location the vehicle is often used.</p>
<p>This Mercedes-Benz C-Class is one of the best options you can think of if you need a Benz car with the luxurious look of a classy techie but low maintenance cost. However, the model seems to be a better fit for handling than for comfort (many C-class do, too)</p>
<p>I won&#8217;t recommend the C350 if you ply curvy roads most of the time, but the vehicle has a fair chance of hitting 200,000 miles or more if you play your cards well in the area of maintenance routines.</p>
<p>The average buying price of the 3.5-liter V6 equipped vehicle starts from around $39,500 and is known for its high-quality parts like other Benz models.</p>
<p>The 2010 Mercedes-Benz C350 releases 268 Horsepower and 258 lb-ft of torque. It will stay in good condition for a very long time if you follow the affordable-to-achieve German manufacturer&#8217;s maintenance guidelines.</p>
<h3>2. 2012 Mercedes-Benz E350</h3>
<div id="attachment_17689" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17689" class="wp-image-17689 size-full" title="2012 Mercedes Benz E350 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1.jpg" alt="2012 Mercedes Benz E350 " width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2012-Mercedes-Benz-E350-1-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17689" class="wp-caption-text">2012 Mercedes Benz E350. 📸: <em>The Car Connection</em></p></div>
<p>Generally, you can expect a Mercedes-Benz E-Class to gulp about $11,224 for maintenance and repairs during its first ten years of service. While this beats the industry average for luxury cars, the 2012 Mercedes-Benz E350 offers more.</p>
<p>According to the leading provider of auto repair and maintenance information, Repairpal, <a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/cars/mercedes-benz/e350/2012#:~:text=The%20annual%20maintenance%20cost%20of,%2C%20mileage%2C%20location%20and%20shop." rel="noopener">the average upkeep cost of the Mercedes-Benz E350</a> annually is around $788. It is a reasonable maintenance cost for a full-size luxury sedan.</p>
<p>With an impressive 3.5-liter V6 engine that produces 302 horsepower, E350 is an excellent catch for the average &#8216;tech bro&#8217; willing to buy a German car on a budget. However, you have to keep in mind that the vehicle requires factory-recommended maintenance if it&#8217;s going to be on the road for as long as possible.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, on average, you can expect the Mercedes-Benz E350 to last, hitting 15,000 miles in 15 years.</p>
<h3>3. 2014 Mercedes-Benz CLA250</h3>
<div id="attachment_17688" style="width: 2570px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17688" class="wp-image-17688 size-full" title="2014 Mercedes Benz CLA250 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1.jpg" alt="2014 Mercedes Benz CLA250 1" width="2560" height="1492" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1.jpg 2560w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-300x175.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-1024x597.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-768x448.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-1536x895.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-480x280.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-CLA250-1-1320x769.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17688" class="wp-caption-text">2014 Mercedes Benz CLA250 📸: <a href="https://branditechture.agency/the-forgotten-website-where-you-can-get-over-70-million-free-images/"><em>Wikimedia Commons</em></a></p></div>
<p>Next on our list of low-maintenance Benz to buy is the CLA250.</p>
<p>This model is doing a better job challenging its contender, Audi A3 and Lexus CT 200h, in the compact luxury car market landscape. It is also cracking the top among a few others as it is the best affordable luxury car for upkeep.</p>
<p>It would cost you, at most, $736 to keep the 2014 CLA250 healthy throughout the year, as various reviews on RepairPal point out that the CLA250 is a top reliable car. <a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/mercedes-benz/cla250#:~:text=The%20annual%20maintenance%20cost%20of,%2C%20mileage%2C%20location%20and%20shop." rel="noopener">The four-star RepairPal reliability rating</a> the model has garnered from users is enough conviction.</p>
<h3>4. 2014 Mercedes-Benz GLK350</h3>
<div id="attachment_17687" style="width: 1290px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17687" class="size-full wp-image-17687" title="2014 Mercedes Benz GLK350" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1.jpg" alt="2014 Mercedes Benz GLK350 " width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1.jpg 1280w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2014-Mercedes-Benz-GLK350-1-480x270.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17687" class="wp-caption-text">2014 Mercedes Benz GLK350. 📸: <em>Sherwood Park Toyota</em> via YouTube</p></div>
<p>It is only possible to list low-maintenance luxury cars by mentioning this 2014 Mercedes-Benz GLK350.</p>
<p>Well, you can say that is subjective. Still, it is more convincing when you consider the fantastic reliability of the GLK as it secures the 7th position on the list of the top <a target="_blank" href="https://repairpal.com/reliability/compact-suv" rel="noopener">luxury compact SUVs on RepairPal.</a></p>
<p>The crossover combines the comfort of a sedan and the spacious cabin of an SUV to offer a decent driving experience. Fixing the 2014 GLK350 annually will cost you between $776 and $948, depending on vehicle usage.</p>
<p>Another exciting part of having this Benz model is that you are likely to experience fewer problems with the vehicle compared to when driving other luxury compact SUVs.</p>
<h3>5. 2020 Mercedes-Benz SL450</h3>
<div id="attachment_17686" style="width: 1610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17686" class="size-full wp-image-17686" title="5. 2020 Mercedes Benz SL450 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1.jpg" alt="2020 Mercedes Benz SL450" width="1600" height="1067" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1.jpg 1600w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-480x320.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/5.-2020-Mercedes-Benz-SL450-1-1320x880.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17686" class="wp-caption-text">2020 Mercedes Benz SL450 📸: <em>Edmunds</em></p></div>
<p>The 2020 Mercedes-Benz SL450 is a luxurious two-seat retractable-hardtop vehicle that offers more comfort and reliability than most Benz lineups.</p>
<p>The vehicle is not a hundred percent pass on many grounds, but it is the closest thing to perfection regarding low upkeep cost. With as low as $908, you will keep the SL450 running perfectly throughout the year in excellent condition.</p>
<p>This is a reasonable maintenance cost compared to the thousands of dollars that most other Benz cars gulp annually.</p>
<p>The 2020 Mercedes-Benz SL450 has a potent 3.0-liter twin-turbo V6 that dismisses 362 horsepower. It is one of the Benz makes that has a surprisingly low maintenance cost.</p>
<h3>6. 2020 Mercedes C200</h3>
<div id="attachment_17685" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17685" class="size-full wp-image-17685" title="2020 Mercedes C200" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1.jpg" alt="2020 Mercedes C200 " width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2020-Mercedes-C200-1-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17685" class="wp-caption-text">2020 Mercedes C200 📸: The Car Connection</p></div>
<p>The 2020 Mercedes C200 is my all-time favorite as long as the discussion of Mercedes Benz is in play. The vehicle is not only considered a decently reliable Mercedes model but also costs low when it comes to maintenance.</p>
<p>The C200 price isn&#8217;t encouraging for techies on a budget, especially when you place it alongside your typical Japanese car brand. But incredible things come at a price, Yeah?</p>
<p>And, what&#8217;s the point when the Benz model is cheaper to maintain than most of its German Luxury alternatives?</p>
<p>Upkeep routines like a simple oil change for the 2020 Mercedes C200 will cost around $150, including parts and labor, while full service for a C-class costs around $500.</p>
<h3>7. 2017 Mercedes-Benz GLS550</h3>
<div id="attachment_17684" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17684" class="size-full wp-image-17684" title="2017 Mercedes Benz GLS550 1" src="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1.jpg" alt="2017 Mercedes Benz GLS550 1" width="1920" height="1367" srcset="https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1.jpg 1920w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-300x214.jpg 300w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-1024x729.jpg 1024w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-768x547.jpg 768w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-1536x1094.jpg 1536w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-480x342.jpg 480w, https://branditechture.agency/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/2017-Mercedes-Benz-GLS550-1-1320x940.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p id="caption-attachment-17684" class="wp-caption-text">2017 Mercedes Benz GLS550 📸: <em>Select Luxury Cars</em></p></div>
<p>The 2017 Mercedes-Benz GLS550 has a young family demographic appeal as a full-size SUV. So, you will find many young guys buying this Benz model, which makes it a good fit for an average tech guy with a wife and children.</p>
<p>But still, another significant reason to consider the GLS550 is the low maintenance fee which puts it ahead of its alternatives like the Cadillac Escalade and even Audi&#8217;s Q7.</p>
<p>It will only cost you around $908 annually to maintain the 2017 Mercedes-Benz GLS550, allowing you to enjoy this luxury car&#8217;s benefits for a long time. It is equipped with a blistering turbo V8 and requires fewer visits to the repair shop for fixes if appropriately used.</p>
<h2>Reasons Why These Benz Cars are Cheaper to Maintain than Others</h2>
<p>These Benz models have been reviewed to be the best in low maintenance areas based on data from consumer surveys, up-close repair shop interviews, car history reports from RepairPal, and my exposure to a series of Mercedes lineups.</p>
<p>If you pay close attention, you will notice that all these Benz cars have something in common that makes them cost less for upkeep in the long run.</p>
<p>Similar features include simple technology, accessible replacement parts, and ample room under the hood of these cars that reduce the labor cost during repairs.</p>
<p>These Benz models appear to have a less complicated technology that makes it easier and quicker to observe repairs or maintenance routines.</p>
<p>Little wonder why many of the low-maintenance Benz cars are of older models since newer lineups are more complicated. In addition, these cars have common, standardized replacement parts, making their repairs cheaper.</p>
<p>Maintenance routines like regular oil changes, proper damage repair, and other essential tasks are required to guarantee the reliability of any Benz car. But observing this routine can be expensive for the typical Benz, but the few models reviewed earlier are going against the odds.</p>
<h2>Bottom Line</h2>
<p>Mercedes-Benz has a glorified reputation for making desirable premium cars. While most of their vehicles are expensive, we have walked through some of the best low-maintenance Mercedes-Benz models every Tech guy can buy.</p>
<p>If it were up to me, I recommend you choose the 2020 Mercedes C200. Not only is the C200 a decently reliable Mercedes model, but it is also a reasonably affordable car to maintain compared to many other Mercedes models on a broader comparative analysis.</p>
<p>The C200, indeed, is not a cheap buy like the regular American vehicle but is still cheaper to maintain than most of its German Luxury alternatives &#8211; a simple oil change will cost around $150 on average, with full service starting from as low as $500.</p>
<p>This is on the low side of spending compared to what Benz S-class owners spend for an oil change ($300 on average) and full service (around $1,400).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/">Best Low-Maintenance Mercedes Benz Cars for Tech Guys</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://branditechture.agency/">Branditechture</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://branditechture.agency/low-maintenance-mercedes-benz-cars-for-tech-guys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
